Fujiwarano Sai, a Go player from the Heian period
has passed through time and returned to
the world in the mind of Shindou Hikaru...
in order to obtain the Hand of God.
君が今僕を支えて
Kimi ga ima boku wo sasaete
Now you are,
holding me up strong!
僕が今君を支える
boku ga ima kimi wo sasaeru
Now I am,
holding you up as well!
だから迷いながらも共に生きていこうよ
Dakara Mayoi nagara mo tomo ni ikite ikou yo
So let us now, while wandering live together
未来へと
Mirai e to...
towards the future
Elite-Fansubs presents
Hikaru no Go
仲間と戯れ　それなりで居ても
Nakama to tawamaure sorenaride itemo
Even when I'm capricing with my friends,
もの足りなさを感じてしまう
mono tari na sa wo kanjite shimau
I feel an emptiness in my heart.
冷めた目で見られて
Sameta me de mirarete
Looked at with cold eyes,
乾いた時代の風に吹かれている
Kawaita jidai no kaze ni fukareteiru
I'm blown by the wind of a dry age
不安な 心と勇気が
Fuan na, kokoro to yuuki ga
Feelings of doubt and courage
背中合わせになっている
senaka awase ni natteiru
are back to back
だけど今なら夢をこの手で叶えてみせるよ
dakedo ima nara yume wo, kono te de kanaete miseru yo
but I'll make these dreams come true now with my own hands.
傷ついて壊れそうな日も
Kizutsuite koware sou na hi mo
The days where I'm hurt and about to break,
涙して困らせる日も
Namidashite komaraseru hi mo
the days where I cry and trouble you
あるけれど僕達はそれを
aru keredo bokura wa sore wo
They all exist, but we will
超えていくんだ誰より
koete ikunda dare yori...
get over it heading higher
上を目指して
ue wo mezashite!
than anyone else!
Is Touya going to quit the Go club after today?
Sai...
you play...
Is that okay?
You said you wanted to.
You play...
Tsutsui-san's just as motivated too.
First and second boards really should be like that.
The Fourteenth Match
The Third Match
Note: Read from right to left
Are you okay?
I'm fine, let's do it Tsutsui-san.
Let's Nigiri.
2...4...6...
I'm black.
I'm white, Shindou-kun's black.
Good luck
Good luck.
Finally...
Finally, I can play against you...
Good luck.
Hikaru, let's go.
Upper right corner, Komoku.
That was fast!
He must have already decided where to go.
That's probably the case.
He must have gone over many
matches against me in his mind.
15-4 Hiraki
5-7 Moku-Hazushi
[note: Moku-Hazushi is the third most popular opening
move. It moves one spot outwards from the komoku. It is the
most aggressive of the three most popular opening moves,
but it doesn't secure very much of the corner for you.]
They're the eyes from before.
The eyes he had when he challenged Sai.
I came all this way pulled by your eyes...
You're my far away objective.
Sai?
Thinking? Here? I'd go to 11-8 without hesitation.
What are you thinking about, Sai?
Dammit, I don't get it.
What's wrong with 11-8?
Have I improved a little?
You really don't need to improve anymore.
You've changed as well.
You hold your stone correctly now.
Hold my stone?
Of course I hold it correctly now.
I played Tsutsui-san everyday, and I played Mitani too.
I've gotten a lot stronger, really.
Touya...
I...
How much closer am I too you now?
You've realized already right?
That I'm not just a weak freshman.
Thinking?
Moron. You underestimated me, right?
I'm not just any Jr. High kid.
Yeah, you are better than me,
but by confusing you through overly
aggressive moves and unexpected moves,
and dragging you into my pace,
I might stand a chance.
What is it?
What is he thinking about?
Go ahead and think about it.
In order to make this match
befitting of the first board.
You're to aggressive. You should relent a little.
Talking in the middle of a match?
So you're still underestimating me.
Watch this, I'll make this match
befitting of the first board.
This guy's really cautious.
Last year, I was able to use
my opponent's mistake to win,
but this second board plays solidly.
He's really strong.
I want to play!
Touya, just like you're chasing after Sai,
I'm chasing you.
I'll catch you some day.
13-4
I'll play at 11-8, and then...
Hikaru? 13-...
I want to try it.
Sai, sorry,
I can't see it unless I play myself.
I want to know,
the gap between him and I.
11-8!?
I'm going to play.
Hikaru...
This is...
it surprised me for a second but... this is...
or is there something else?
It's interesting.
11-8 is interesting.
It's too bad that Hikaru doesn't have
the strength to follow up on that idea,
but, I can feel his will to keep
playing with each move he makes.
Hikaru...
I will simply watch over you for now...
Stop messing around!
T-Touya...
Touya!
I'm not messing around!
Yes! We're very serious!
Touya's too busy chasing after me,
and he can't see Hikaru's strength.
He can't hear Hikaru approaching him step by step.
Touya...
play to the end. Either that or resign.
I told you, you'd know once you played him.
Damn it!
Is he an idiot?
Getting so fired up over Shindou.
You over estimate him too much.
I know exactly how strong he is.
Tsutsui-san can't do it either.
I'm our only hope.
What is it!?
He's fighting me over a stone like this!?
I'm fighting back but...
is there that much meaning behind this stone?
He's... why is he this stubborn!?
A stone like this... I should just give it to him.
You pulled back.
As I see it, you play a game based
on strength, from your self training.
In that case, you can't pull back.
Even if there's no real meaning
behind this stone, you can't pull back.
With people like you, once you
pull back, you've lost emotionally.
You'll only fall apart from now on.
So your plan is to make me worry by saying that.
Go ahead and play!
I resign...
Touya!
Thanks for the game.
Thanks for the game...
I thought...
I thought I saw the Hand of God in you...
I resign.
Thanks for the game.
To be honest, I didn't think you were this strong.
It was fun.
It's not...
over yet!
Oh?
You intend to play to the end?
I resign...
Thanks for the game.
Kaiou against Haze, Kaiou wins with a score of 3-0
夢に見ていたシアワセなら
Yume ni miteita shiawase nara
I thought that someone would bring me,
誰かが運んでくれると思ってた
Dareka ga hakonde kureru to omotteta
the happiness that I dreamed of.
急ぎ足の街で
Isogi ashi no machi de
In a quick paced city,
言い訳ばかり
iiwake bakari...
all I'm doing is listing off excuses,
みんなも同じとうそ ぶいてた
Minna mo onaji to usobuiteta
and lying to myself, that everyone was doing the same.
本当にキミはいま　満足してるの？
hontou ni kimi wa ima manzokushiteru no?
Are you really satisfied right now?
心の真ん中 見抜かれたようで
kokoro no mannaka minukaretayoude
It feels as if you've straight through my heart.
あなたと出会えなかったら
Anata to deaenakattara
If i had not met you,
偽った笑顔のまま
Itsuwatta egao no mama!
I would still only have a false smile!
うわべの態度や言葉を
Uwabe no taido ya kotoba wo
My words and disagreements
繰り返したね
kurikaeshita ne
would only have been superficial.
あなたの瞳の力で
anata no hitomi no chikara de
With the power of your gaze,
私は変わってゆこう
watashi wa kawatte yukou
I am starting to change!
昨日の揺らいだ気持ちを
Kinou no yuraida kimochi wo
In order to cast off
脱ぎ捨てるために...
nugisuteru tame ni
the swaying feelings of yesterday.
Umezawa Yukari's
Go Go Igo!
Go! Go! Igo!
Let's try Nigiri, which is used to
decide black and white, today.
Nigiri today!
Teacher Yukari
Yuuki
Mai
With Mai-chan and Yuuki-kun, Mai-chan is older,
The older person does nigiri.
so Mai-chan, will you please
nigiri the white stones?
You grab the white stones.
Will you grab some stones and place
your hand over the board like this?
The stones that you've grabbed should be placed on
the board in a way that the opponent can't see them.
Now Yuuki-kun, if you think Mai-chan
holds an even number of stones,
The opponent guesses whether the
number of stones are even or odd.
If you think it's even, take out two
black stones, and say "Even first"
say "Even First" while taking two stones out.
If you think there's an odd number, say
"Odd First" while taking one stone out.
If you think it's odd, take out one
black stone, and say "Odd First"
Odd First!
Odd First!!
There's five so...
Oh it's odd!
Mai grabbed an odd number of stones.
That means that the game
begins with Yuuki-kun as black.
Yuuki was right, so Yuuki plays first with black.
To be continued...
So you can play people from all
over the world if you go here.
Hikaru! What are you trying to do?
I thought I'd let you play all the Go you want.
First I've gotta choose a name...
the name is..."Sai"!
This is F-Zhang(Loae666)'s 50th translation.
Congratulations!
All I want!? Really?
Okay, let's go!