Real Fansubbers presents
Hikaru no Go
Original Creator
Yumi Hotta
Takeshi Obata
Technical Director
Yukari Umezawa (Japanese Go Institute)
(Shueisha Weekly Shounen Jump Series)
mune no kodou atsuku yurugasu
胸の鼓動　熱くゆるがす
My heart walks, searching for something exciting
shigeki motomete aruku
刺激求めて　歩く
that will passionately sway the beating in my chest.
Planning
Keisuke Iwata
Takashi Harada
Yuuji Fugawa
My heart
jikan dakega sugiru mainichi jya
時間だけが過ぎる毎日じゃ
If I just wait for time to pass every day,
Animation Character Design
Kanami Sekiguchi
Miyuki Ueda
henka ha nai
変化はない
nothing's going to change.
Woo Wooo
tomaranai shinjitai susumitai
止まらない　信じたい　進みたい
I won't stop. I want to believe. I want to move forward.
jibun no chikara tamesu
自分の力試す
I will test my strength during my life.
My life
demo hayaaruki shitatte miotosudake
でも早歩きしたって見落とすだけ
But even if I walk faster,
I will definitely lose track of
sou kakujitsu ni
そう確実に
the important things.
Baby for you...
ashita ha ashita no kaze ga fuku
明日は明日の風が吹く
Tomorrow's wind will blow tomorrow,
Music Producer
Takashi Nagasawa
Music
Kei Wakakusa
soredemo
それでも　今この瞬間を強く生きたい
but I want to make the most out of this moment now.
Opening Song
Karaoke     llbx
LYRICS
Nana Katase
MUSIC
ARRANGE
Seikou Nagaoka
Nana Katase
ima kono shunkan wo tsuyoku ikitai
It's
It's fantasy.  even if I'm wandering,
fantasy
samayotta to shitemo
さまよったとしても
Program Manager
Tetsuya Watanabe
mitakotonai sekai demo
見たことない世界でも
even if I'm in a strange new world,
nani yori mo jibun wo shinji tachimukaou
何よりも　自分を信じ立ち向かおう
I'll stand up to it,
believing in myself more than anything else.
It's
It's destiny.  No matter where I am,
destiny
donna basho ni itemo
どんな場所にいても
tsutsumu sora ha hitotsu dakara
つつむ空は一つだから
I'm surrounded by the same sky,
Director
Tetsuya Endou
nee motto tsubasa hirogete
ねぇ　もっと　翼ひろげて
so I'll be able to fly
habatakeruyone
羽ばたけるよね
with my wings spread out.
This move...
He made moves like this...
Here...
I couldn't find Sai anywhere I looked...
and he was here all along...
The only way I could see you again...
was by playing!
I'm going to play...
dozens of games, hundreds of games,
thousands of games from now on.
With Isumi-san, with Waya,
with Ochi, with everyone!
The Seventy-First Match
First Comeback Match
I'm going now.
Are you really going to your match?
Yeah.
Not just today?
I'll go from now on, I told you.
I'm leaving. Arrange it with the school, ok?
Japanese Go Institute
You're 3-dan if you win today?
Yeah.
Isn't your opponent today that guy who
hasn't gone to any of his matches?
Yup, I get an easy promotion through a forfeit.
Lucky you.
I wanted to get promoted through a win, though.
Good morning!
Shindou... he came!
Damn that Shindou. Why did he
have to start coming today?
Shindou-kun is here?
Hi, Tsujioka-kun.
I'm playing him for my next Ooteai match.
I'm so happy. I've wanted to play him.
You've wanted to play him?
Yes!
I heard a rumor that Touya-kun
thinks of him as a rival.
Touya-kun!? and Shindou!?
That can't be!
Hey, are you serious?
Touya-kun's in the Honinbou league!
Good morning.
Touya-kun...
Shindou...
Good luck.
I played him in the Wakajishisen last year.
He scared me with a few good moves,
but he was bad at Yose, and I
won by six and a half moku.
But Touya persistently asked me how he played.
I was annoyed back then because he kept asking about the guy who lost,
but I guess Touya really did think of him as a rival.
I'll play a thick game, and make it hard
for either of us to get territory.
I'll bring it into Yose, and defeat him there.
I'll show you exactly how bad you are at Yose.
Stand.
Bow.
Teacher!
What is it, Kaneko?
Chemistry Lab
Kaneko-san, are you sure?
Hikaru was absent today for a match?
Yup. And I hear that he's been absent the last few
days for Go-related things like study sessions.
Hikaru cheered up!
I'm so glad!
I'm glad for Shindou-senpai.
Yeah.
We're still on short days since
summer break just ended,
so our homeroom teacher, Mr. Suzuki,
was happy about Shindou cheering up
despite the fact that he's missing school.
He was thinking about quitting as a pro,
and now he's ditching school to play Go.
What a selfish guy.
You're just as selfish as he is.
What'd you say!?
You suddenly declared that you
were going to the tournament.
And before that you only came
to the club occasionally.
I'm sure Shindou went back to being a pro
because he didn't want to study for exams.
You make it sound as if you're studying
for exams or something.
Shut up!
But thanks to Mitani-kun we were able
to go to the tournament. It was fun.
You guys made it all the way to the finals...
though all of you lost to Kaiou.
You girls won your first 3-0, too.
Yeah! Yeah we did. Wasn't that great?
All of you 3rd year students
are leaving the Go club...
What am I supposed to do all by myself?
Koike-kun, a senpai of ours called Tsutsui-san
started this Go club all by himself.
By himself!?
Yup.
Tsutsui-san started it by himself, then Hikaru
joined in, and I tagged along with him.
Then Hikaru dragged Mitani-kun
in. That's how it started.
After that, Kaneko-san came temporarily.
And Natsume-kun and Kumiko-san joined.
That's how the Haze Jr. High Go club was formed.
It's fun having lots of people, but it's
also fun starting up by yourself.
It's your Go club from now on, Koike-kun.
M-Mine!?
You look happy.
My Go club...
Beat Kaiou someday.
That's impossible.
The Haze Jr. High Go club is changing...
Everyone's changing...
Even Hikaru, who was about to quit being
a pro, has started playing again.
Hikaru... I'm sure he's sitting in front of
a Go board with a stern face right now.
Oh man, I'm so bad.
I got lucky there.
No, I have to rest.
Here you go.
Thank you.
But it was close.
That game right now, it looked like one
of our games, you were doing well.
Really?
Oh yeah, Isumi-san.
You went to Shindou's place, right?
Yeah.
Really? You did?
How was Shindou?
I don't quite understand.
But... it seems like he's over it now.
We both got to play a good game.
I see...
That bastard, making us worry like that.
Huh? What?
I can't just surround territory right now.
I'll fight back!
Shindou Hikaru...
Kids these days...
Oh, Sakamaki-san.
What's wrong? Sighing like that.
Amano-san.
Amano-san!
Sorry.
Hello, this is Ogata.
Oh, Amano-san.
Hello. Do you have some time right now?
You were asking about Shindou Hikaru first
dan earlier weren't you, Master Ogata?
Yes... yes... oh...
Shindou came to his match...
Okay... okay... thank you for calling.
Yeah.
So he's back...
Yes... yes... what!? I'll check up on it right now.
Looks like the editor-in-chief isn't here.
Oh, Master Kuwabara!
Here, the manuscript you asked me for.
Oh, thank you for bringing it here.
I had some business in the area, so I brought it by.
Thank you.
What is it, Amano-san?
Oh, nothing. I was just thinking about something...
Master Kuwabara, you were talking about Shindou
Hikaru first dan the other day weren't you?
About how he will come back?
Yeah. I was right, wasn't I?
Yes. But why is everyone so
interested in Shindou-kun?
Master Kuwabara, Master Ogata, Master
Kurata, even Master Touya...
Why, you ask?
I think that's what we all want to know.
Don't be so impatient. I'm sure we'll
all eventually find out, Amano-san.
My sixth sense tells me so.
Sixth sense?
Okay!
I can win!
Why is someone this strong here? How can I win?
I resign.
Thank you for the game.
Touya-kun's done, too.
What!? He's leaving?
Without watching Shindou-kun's first comeback match?
He'd want to watch it if he was a rival...
Maybe that rumor's false...
Or...
Could it be...
Maybe he thinks a match against a lower-dan
player isn't worth watching...
Only I can measure Shindou's strength now.
I knew it the moment he appeared
in front of me that night.
Oh yes, I received the pairings for the first round
of the first preliminaries of the Meijin match.
Touya-kun's opponent for the first round was...
Honda Tadao 2-dan
Fujiki Mina First dan
Nishizaki Shou 3-dan
Katou Yuuta 2-dan
Touya Akira 3-dan
Shindou Hikaru First dan
I just need to wait.
Touya Akira 3-dan
Shindou Hikaru First dan
They've already prepared a match between us.
Ring
Hikaru Shindou
Tomoko Kawakami
Akira Touya
Sanae Kobayashi
Akari Fujisaki
Yumi Kakazu
Honinbou Kuwabara
Rokurou Naya
Ogata 10-dan
Keiji Fujiwara
Mitani Yuuki
Yuu Asakawa
My
Bell
noizu darake no mune de
ノイズだらけの胸で
I listen to my fate through the din in my heart.
noizu darake no mune deunmei wo kikiwakeru
ノイズだらけの胸で運命を聴きわける
Waya Yoshitaka
Reiko Takagi
Isumi Shinichiro
Suzumura Kenichi
Amano
Yoshito Ishinami
Hikaru's Mother
Yurika Hino
Sakamaki
Shouto Kashii
Masako Kaneko
Yukiji
Toshinori Honda
Takahiro Sakurai
Asumi Nase
Atsuko Enomoto
Natsume
Takuo Kawamura
Kumiko Tsuda
Akeno Watanabe
Hitoshi Koike
Tomo Shigematsu
Murakami 2-dan
Toshiaki Kuwahara
Tsujioka 2-dan
Mizuki Saitou
ノイズだらけの胸で運命を聴きわける
It occurs to me.
hirameku
閃く
hiramekuyume ha watashi no naka demezame o matteta
閃く夢は私の中で目覚めを待ってた
My dream was waiting for the time
to wake up within me.
mezame o matteta
閃く夢は私の中で目覚めを待ってた
Music
Is
My
Thing
I can be more like myself
jibun rashiku nareru
自分らしくなれる
Music
In
My
Heart
ときめきならして
Let the pounding of my heart be heard
tokimeki narashite
ときめきならして
Music
Is
My
Thing
karada wo ugokasu
体を動かす
I move my body
karada wo ugokasu
体を動かす
Music
In
My
Heart
Feel the light
hikari wo kanjite
光を感じて
Ending Song
Karaoke: llbx
LYRICS
TUNE
JAPANESE LYRICS
YUUKO EBINE
EDITING
TATSUHIKO
SONG
Music
Is
My
Thing
shiro to kuro de egaku
白と黒で描く
I draw with black and white
shiro to kuro de egaku
白と黒で描く
Music
In
My
Heart
owaranai haamoni
The unending Harmony
終わらないハーモニー
owaranai haamoni
Choices to make when starting the midgame.
It's Black's turn on this board.
Yuuki
Teacher Yukari
Mai
Where would you go, Mai-chan?
Here.
Why did you want to play there?
I wanted to increase Black's territory, and
get in the way of White's territory.
A move to try to increase
Black's territory, and get in the way of White.
That's one way of thinking.
Other than this...
You can play here to try to solidify
Black's territory here,
Attempt to solidify Black's territory.
or move here, and if White responds move forward
even more to make this area Black.
An attempt to expand Black's territory in the center.
These are all good moves.
When you have lots of different paths
to take, choose one suited to yourself.
Choose a path suited for you,
to fight in the mid-game!!
To be continued...
Is the new wave really coming?
Is Shindou-kun's strength real?
I won't let these young ones take the world just yet.
Touya... I want to play against you, as soon as possible.