胸の鼓動　熱くゆるがす
mune no kodou atsuku yurugasu
My heart walks, searching for something exciting
刺激求めて歩く My Heart
shigeki motomete aruku MY HEART
That will passionately sway the beating in my chest.
時間だけが過ぎる毎日じゃ
jikan dake ga sugiru mainichi jya
If I just wait for the time to pass everyday.
変化はない
henka ha nai
nothing's going to change.
Woo Wooo
止まらない　信じたい　進みたい
tomaranai shinjitai susumitai
I won't stop. I want to believe. I want to move forward.
自分の力試す My Life
jibun no chikara tamesu MY LIFE
I will test my strength during my life.
でも早歩きしたって見落とすだけ
demo hayaaruki shitatte miotosudake
But even if I walk faster.
I will definitely lose track of
そう確実に
sou kakujitsu ni
the important things.
Baby for you...
明日は明日の風が吹く
ashita ha ashita no kaze ga fuku
Tomorrow's wind will blow tomorrow.
それでも　今この瞬間を強く生きたい
soredemo
but I want to make the most out of this moment now.
ima kono shunkan wo tsuyoku ikitai
It's fantasy
さまよったとしても
samayotta to shitemo
Even if I'm wandering,
見たことない世界でも
mitakotonai sekai demo
even if I'm in a strange new world,
何よりも 自分を信じ立ち向かおう
nani yori mo jibun wo shinji tachimukaou
I'll stand up to it,
believing in myself more than anything else.
It's destiny
どんな場所にいても
donna basho ni itemo
No matter where I am,
つつむ空は一つだから
tsutsumu sora ha hitotsu dakara
I'm surrounded by the same sky.
ねぇ　もっと 翼広げて
nee motto tsubasa hirogete
so I'll be able to fly
羽ばたけるよね
habatakeruyone
with my wings spread out.
There's Touya-Kun...
There's Shindou-kun.
There's always Ochi-kun and Waya-kun,
and together they make the new wave.
I get so excited when I think about the future.
The Seventy-Fifth Match
That Same Old Smile
Touya...
You played me twice...
in a Go salon...
He... he is Sai.
I can tell because I know you
better than anyone else.
Only I can tell this...
But there's someone else inside you!
Touya...
No... never mind.
I'm not making any sense.
Touya found Sai...
Only I knew of Sai until now...
But Sai... Touya's found you!
He's found you!
No...
The game you play is what you are.
That won't change, and that's all I need.
Touya...
The game I play... is what I am.
That's right.
Sai is in the game I play.
Yeah, maybe...
I might tell you everything someday.
Shindou!
What do you mean?
W-What is it?
So there is something behind you!? Tell me!
Tell you? No way.
You said that the game I play is what
I am, and that's all you need.
Y-Yeah... I did...
Then don't ask.
But you just said you'd tell me everything!
Someday! Someday far in the future! You idiot!
I'm home!
Welcome back.
I'm exhausted.
The game ended quickly, but we
discussed it for a long time.
And...
No need to tell me who won.
I don't know anything about Go.
I'll just worry about your health.
Dad will be out of the bath soon.
Bath? I don't need to take a bath.
Then do you want something to eat?
That's alright. I'm tired, so I'll go to bed.
Huh? Shoes?
Oh, this is a dream.
I can sometimes tell when I'm dreaming.
I hope something...
good happens...
in this dream...
Sai...
Sai!
You came to me in my dream!
Sai! I played Touya today!
With Touya!
In the first round of the first preliminaries for the Meijin match.
It was a great game.
Well...
Even though I did lose.
But we're going to play hundreds and
thousands of games together now!
We even promised to play each other
at his Go salon every now and then!
It's a secret from Master Morishita though.
Oh yeah! Isumi-san passed the pro exams!
And Mitani went to a tournament...
So much has happened since you disappeared!
I have so much... to tell you...
Sai...
Why did you disappear?
You said you wanted to keep playing!
Why did you disappear!?
I don't understand!
How did you feel when you disappeared?
Were you sad?
Or were you smiling, just like you are now?
I hope you were smiling...
Sai, Touya said that there was
someone else inside me.
Man, I panicked.
But I was kind of happy that he found you.
Sai...
Sai!
Don't go!
Say something!
Don't disappear!
Sai!
Sai?
Sai...
Hikaru!
It's past seven already. What about school?
I'll go! I'm going!
Did you forget anything?
Nope!
I'm gonna stop by a Go salon on my
way home. I'll be home for dinner.
You'll die if you try to help them.
But if you play here, then wouldn't it
be better to not have played here?
Is that the young Master playing
there? Who is he playing?
Shindou Hikaru first-dan. A first year pro.
Oh, does Shindou-pro drop by here sometimes?
No, he just started coming recently.
Oh, so they're friends.
Err... kinda.
It's not looking good.
It's about to start.
We're getting out of here
Again!?
Again?
"Oh! I see."!? Why can't you even notice that!?
How can you say that when you didn't
even see this Sagari over here.
But you missed this Tsuke over here, too!
Besides, how many times do you think
you've said' Oh! I see." Already!?
Wow, they're arguing over such complicated ideas.
Not really...
You've said it four times! Not three!
You said the same thing about
my ideas SIX times already!
You've got to be kidding!
There's no way I've said it Six times already!
You said it!
No I didn't!
I'm leaving!
Here's your bag.
See? It's a fight between grade school kids.
That Shindou really needs to learn his place.
A mere first-dan pro shouldn't argue
against the young master.
After all, he is already in the Honinbou league.
I'm a mere third-dan, too.
No matter how good you are, you're
a first-dan when you start off.
We all have to climb up from there.
There's no correlation between your
ranking and your strength.
Don't look down upon Shindou
just because he's a first-dan.
Weren't they just fighting?
Yup.
I want to play higher-dan players already.
Who are you playing today?
Kawasaki 3-dan. It's the third round of the
first preliminaries for the Honinbou match.
Touya is already playing against higher-dan players.
I'm still just a first-dan.
It's not just in the Honinbou match.
I have to play through the first preliminaries between
lower-dan players in all the title matches.
I have to play through them!
Okay, time for lunch.
Shindou, are you going out?
Yeah.
I ordered a pork cutlet bowl earlier.
Time for my pork cutlet bowl.
You...
Why... why is he a first-dan?
Why is Shindou-kun still a first-dan?
Remember the guy who skipped all his
matches between Spring and Summer?
Yeah, I heard about him.
That's Shindou.
He lost a lot of matches by default back then.
So even if he keeps on winning, he won't get
enough points for a promotion for a while.
He'll be a first-dan for a while.
First-dan for awhile...? But he's so good.
He's the best first-dan player ever.
Shindou...
Normally you would connect in
response to Black's threat.
But he played a Tsuke because he thought
just responding wouldn't be good enough.
That move...
it was carried out perfectly.
Waya.
Shindou, what is that?
This?
I bought it downstairs.
You... bought that?
Yeah.
Okay. I'm gonna finish up my game now.
kimi ga ima boku wo sasaete
君が今僕を支えて
You're holding me up right now
kimi ga ima boku wo sasaete
君が今僕を支えて
You're holding me up right now
boku ga ima kimi wo sasaeru
僕が今君を支える
Just like I'm holding you up
boku ga ima kimi wo sasaeru
僕が今君を支える
Just like I'm holding you up
dakara mayoi nagaramo tomo ni ikiteikouyo
だから迷いながらも共に生きていこうよ
So let us clumsily live towards the future, together
dakara mayoi nagaramo tomo ni ikiteikouyo
だから迷いながらも共に生きていこうよ
mirai heto
未来へと
So let us clumsily live towards the future, together
Sai...
One day... I will play the divine move with you!
nakama to tawamure sorenari de itemo
仲間と戯れ　それなりで居ても
Even when I'm together with my friends
nakama to tawamure sorenari de itemo
仲間と戯れ　それなりで居ても
Even when I'm together with my friends
mono tarinasa wo kanjiteshimau
もの足りなさを感じてしまう
I feel an emptiness deep inside
mono tarinasa wo kanjiteshimau
もの足りなさを感じてしまう
I feel an emptiness deep inside
sameta me de mirarete
冷めた目で見られて
You stare at me with those cold eyes,
sameta me de mirarete
冷めた目で見られて
You stare at me with those cold eyes,
kawaita jidai no kaze ni fukareteiru
乾いた時代の風に吹かれている
as the wind of a dry age blows against me.
kawaita jidai no kaze ni fukareteiru
乾いた時代の風に吹かれている
as the wind of a dry age blows against me.
akiramekireru mono naraba
諦めきれるモノならば
If it was something I could give up on
akiramekireru mono naraba
諦めきれるモノならば
If it was something I could give up on
saisho kara kyoumi motanai
最初から興味持たない
I wouldn't have taken notice of it to begin with
saisho kara kyoumi motanai
最初から興味持たない
I wouldn't have taken notice of it to begin with
wasurerareru mono nara
忘れられるモノなら
If I could forget about it,
wasurerareru mono nara
忘れられるモノなら
If I could forget about it,
hitsuyousa mo kanjinaikara
必要さも感じないから
I wouldn't have thought it necessary to begin with
hitsuyousa mo kanjinaikara
必要さも感じないから
I wouldn't have thought it necessary to begin with
fuan na kokoro to yuuki ga
不安な心と勇気が背中合わせになっている
I always feel doubt with courage,
fuan na kokoro to yuuki ga
senaka awase ni natteiru
不安な心と勇気が背中合わせになっている
I always feel doubt with courage,
dakedo ima nara yume wo
だけど今なら夢を
but I feel that I can make my dream come true now.
dakedo ima nara yume wo
だけど今なら夢を
kono te de kanaete miseruyo
この手で叶えてみせるよ
but I feel that I can make my dream come true now.
kidutsuite kowaresouna hi mo
傷ついて壊れそうな日も
Though there are days when I get hurt and am about to break
kidutsuite kowaresouna hi mo
傷ついて壊れそうな日も
Though there are days when I get hurt and am about to break
namida shite komaraseru hi mo arukeredo
涙して困らせる日も あるけれど
and days where I worry you by crying
namida shite komaraseru hi mo arukeredo
涙して困らせる日も あるけれど
and days where I worry you by crying
bokura ha sore wo koete ikunda
僕達はそれを超えていくんだ
We're going to get over it
bokura ha sore wo koete ikunda
僕達はそれを超えていくんだ
We're going to get over it
dareyori ue wo mezashite
誰より上を目指して
heading higher than anyone else.
dareyori ue wo mezashite
誰より上を目指して
heading higher than anyone else.
tanoshii koto dake erande ikitemo
楽しいことだけ　選んで生きても
If I live life only for pleasure
tanoshii koto dake erande ikitemo
楽しいことだけ　選んで生きても
If I live life only for pleasure
sono saki niha nani mo mienakute
その先には何も見えなくて
I won't be able to see anything in my future
sono saki niha nani mo mienakute
その先には何も見えなくて
I won't be able to see anything in my future
dakara donna koto mo
だからどんな事も
so I won't run away from reality.
dakara donna koto mo
だからどんな事も
so I won't run away from reality.
genjitsu kara nigenaide uketomeruyo
現実から逃げないで受け止めるよ
No matter what happens, I'll face it.
Waya-kun congratulations on
your promotion to second dan!
genjitsu kara nigenaide uketomeruyo
現実から逃げないで受け止めるよ
No matter what happens, I'll face it.
daiji na mono ga arunaraba
大事なモノがあるならば
I promise I'll protect everything
daiji na mono ga arunaraba
大事なモノがあるならば
I promise I'll protect everything
mamori nuite miserukara
守り抜いてみせるから
that's important to me.
mamori nuite miserukara
守り抜いてみせるから
that's important to me.
nakushitakunai mono ni
失くしたくないモノに
I'll put everything I have into
nakushitakunai mono ni
失くしたくないモノに
I'll put everything I have into
jibun no subete wo kakeruyo
自分の全てを懸けるよ
protecting things I don't want to lose.
jibun no subete wo kakeruyo
自分の全てを懸けるよ
protecting things I don't want to lose.
kiyou jya nai kara toki ni kidutsuke
器用じゃないから時に傷つけ
We're not good with words, so I may hurt you,
kiyou jya nai kara toki ni kidutsuke
器用じゃないから時に傷つけ
We're not good with words, so I may hurt you,
kidutsuiteiku
傷ついていく
and you may hurt me.
kidutsuiteiku
傷ついていく
and you may hurt me.
dakedo ima nara sukoshi
だけど今なら少し
But I think I can walk with confidence now.
dakedo ima nara sukoshi
だけど今なら少し
jishin wo motte arukeruyo
自信をもって歩けるよ
But I think I can walk with confidence now.
kodoku dato kanjiru hidemo
孤独だと感じる日でも
There are days when I feel lonely,
kodoku dato kanjiru hidemo
孤独だと感じる日でも
There are days when I feel lonely,
mijime dato kanjiru hi sae arukeredo
惨めだと感じる日さえ あるけれど
and days when I feel miserable
mijime dato kanjiru hi sae arukeredo
惨めだと感じる日さえ あるけれど
and days when I feel miserable
bokura ha kitto hitori jyanai to omouyo...
僕達はきっと一人じゃないと思うよ
but I know I'm never alone...
bokura ha kitto hitori jyanai to omouyo...
僕達はきっと一人じゃないと思うよ
but I know I'm never alone...
kimi ga iru
君がいる
you're here.
kimi ga iru
君がいる
you're here.
Come to the Go club!
Com
Come
Come to the Go club!
naze hito ha doki ni ayamachi wo...
なぜ人は時に過ちを…
Why do people sometimes make mistakes...
naze hito ha doki ni ayamachi wo...
なぜ人は時に過ちを…
Why do people sometimes make mistakes...
koukai wo shitemo shikirezu...
後悔をしてもしきれず…
I can't regret those mistakes enough...
koukai wo shitemo shikirezu...
後悔をしてもしきれず…
I can't regret those mistakes enough...
naze hito ha itsumo soredemoto
なぜ人はいつも　それでもと
Why do people always try to get over it?
naze hito ha itsumo soredemoto
なぜ人はいつも　それでもと
koeteikou to suru?
超えていこうとする？
Why do people always try to get over it?
kimi ga ima boku wo sasaete
君が今僕を支えて
You're holding me up right now
kimi ga ima boku wo sasaete
君が今僕を支えて
You're holding me up right now
boku ga ima kimi wo sasaeru
僕が今君を支える
Just like I'm holding you up,
boku ga ima kimi wo sasaeru
僕が今君を支える
Just like I'm holding you up,
dakara mayoi nagaramo tomo ni ikiteikouyo
だから迷いながらも共に生きていこうよ
So let us clumsily live towards the future, together
dakara mayoi nagaramo tomo ni ikiteikouyo
だから迷いながらも共に生きていこうよ
mirai heto
未来へと
toki ni kidutsuite kowaresouna hi mo
時に傷ついて壊れそうな日も
So let us clumsily live towards the future, together
Sometimes there will be days when I'm hurt and about to break,
toki ni kidutsuite kowaresouna hi mo
時に傷ついて壊れそうな日も
Sometimes there will be days when I'm hurt and about to break,
namida shite komaraseru hi mo arukeredo
涙して困らせる日もあるけれど
and days when I cry and worry you.
namida shite komaraseru hi mo arukeredo
涙して困らせる日もあるけれど
and days when I cry and worry you.
bokura ha sore wo koete ikunda
僕達はそれを超えていくんだ
But we're going to get over that
bokura ha sore wo koete ikunda
僕達はそれを超えていくんだ
But we're going to get over that
dareyori ue wo mezashite
誰より上を目指して
heading higher than anyone else
dareyori ue wo mezashite
誰より上を目指して
heading higher than anyone else
The End
Yukari Umezawa's
Today is the last episode of Go Go Igo
after running for a year and a half.
Yuuki
Teacher Yukari
Mai
Thank you so much for watching the entire time.
During the last year and a half...
I've been very happy because I was able to
see a lot of people happy from playing Go.
What do you think, Mai-chan?
It was a lot of fun because I got to play
a lot of people, and learn a lot of things.
What about you, Yuuki-kun?
I'm going to become a pro, and play in the room
of deep contemplation with this board.
Do your best, okay?
The three of us will keep playing Go.
I hope that we'll be able to meet
all of you someday, somewhere.
Well then everyone.
Thank you so much
for your continued support!!
The End
Good bye!