kono me kimi no me ni
この瞳君の瞳に
On this eye, this eye on yours,
utsuru donna mono mo
映るどんなモノも
everything will appear.
mikiwamete miseru yo shinjitsu wo
見極めて見せるよ真実を
I will tell apart the truth.
Real-Fansubbers
Presents
Hikaru
Real-Fansubbers
Presents
no Go
Hikaru no Go
bokutachi wa kono jidai ni
僕達はこの時代に
We had so many dreams
dore dake no yume kakaete
どれだけの夢抱えて
in this time we live in.
namida shite mayoi nagara
涙して迷いながら
We stare at it and run towards it,
sore ni kakete miteru no
それに賭けてみてるの
even as we wander about crying.
boku wa sore demo hito ni hiketoranu you na
僕はそれでも人にひけとらぬような
Even then, I will find a deciding move.
kimete mitsuke yume wo te ni suru darou
決め手見つけ夢を手にするだろう
just as good as anyone else's, and
take ahold of my dreams.
kono me kimi no me ni
この瞳君の瞳に
On this eye, this eye of yours,
utsuru donna mono mo
映るどんなモノも
everything will appear.
mikiwamete miseru yo shinjitsu dake
見極めて見せるよ真実だけ
I'll tell apart, just the truth.
tatoe genjitsu ga
たとえ現実が
Even if the truth is
kitsuku umoresou demo
きつく埋もれそうでも
so harsh it's suffocating.
konna basho de owaru
こんな場所で終わる
I'm not going to end
boku janai
僕じゃない
in a place like this.
It's all because of my match against
Isumi-san yesterday!
I couldn't concentrate today!
Hikaru, Hikaru!
I want to become stronger.
I'm never going to play a match like yesterday,
or a match like today ever again!
Was it because you were scared of Shindou?
So you got scared of him, and
made a careless mistake.
Is that what happened?
Waya... Isumi-san...
lost again today...
against Fuku...
Honestly, I'm disappointed. You're
too worried about Shindou.
I kind of regret ever seeing you as a rival.
Though thanks to all this...
Ochi...
It's easier for me to pass undefea...
Shut up.
The Forty-First Match
Three Weeks Isn't Enough!
He's coming in this deep?
I'll be short on territory if he survives here.
I won't let you survive that easily.
Just you watch.
Ochi.
Though I respect your skill,
I never once thought that you were stronger than me.
So that's what you did.
Isumi-san is back to normal.
Fine!
Let's play!
Will that really do it?
Wow. He connected it.
Now white's stones are all connected!
I lost the fight on the right side!
Damn it!
Shindou Hikaru!
My name is...
I'm me.
It's not that I lost confidence.
My Go supports me!
I resign...
Thanks for the game.
How did this part go?
I saw it. It went like this.
Yup. Black lost the game there.
I need to clean up.
Oh, we'll take care of it.
Ochi. Thank you.
You helped me get back on my feet.
Isumi-san, you're back.
I feel as if I haven't seen you in days, Waya.
What do you mean by that? What about Shindou?
The pro exam isn't over yet.
Yeah.
It's just starting, for both you and I.
Yeah!
I don't know if Shindou is stronger than me or not.
But, I'm still getting stronger.
Shindou isn't the only one that's getting stronger.
I should believe in myself more.
Yes, this is it. I shouldn't have done
a Hane when white did a Tsuke.
It would have been better if I
had simply pulled back there.
White would have had a harder
time connecting then.
That's it... that's...
I won't lose next time!
Next time...
Ochi, find out for yourself how strong Shindou is.
Ochi: 14 wins 1 loss
Isumi: 12 wins 3 losses
Waya: 13 wins 2 losses
Shindou: 13 wins 2 losses
Honda: 12 wins 3 losses
Fukui: 8 wins 7 losses
Nase: 8 wins 7 losses
Twelve matches left, we're
in the final stretch Hikaru.
Yeah.
Shindou...
I'll be playing you in the last round Ochi.
I'll be much stronger than I am now.
Japanese Go Research Center
Sixteenth Match of the Pro Exam Finals
I resign...
Thanks for the game.
Great, I managed to win.
I was scared of losing today, because
of the shock of losing to Isumi-san.
But Waya and Shindou won too.
The same is true with Isumi-san and Honda-san.
What if I mess up and fail?
No way. That's impossible.
Shindou!
Iijima-san looked sad when he left.
Looks like you won, Ochi.
You're doing well too, staying at two losses.
You played Nase today right? Easy win?
Not at all.
Even if you're at an advantage, mistakes
happen if you try to rush the win.
Since it's the pro exam, it's hard to play normally.
Being too determined to win
can make you falter too.
Emotions are difficult.
Shindou has changed...
And it's not just his strength in the game.
No, I can't be worrying.
Seventeenth Match of the Pro Exam Finals
Oh! Shindou lost to Honda-san!
Okay! Now Shindou has three losses!
I knew he'd start falling.
I wonder if Honda-san has gone home yet.
Oh, Honda-san!
You beat Shindou!
Now you, Isumi-san and Shindou
are all tied at three losses.
I feel relieved that Shindou lost.
Everyone's making such a fuss that
Shindou has gotten stronger.
How was your game?
Honda-san?
I just barely won. No, I thought I had lost.
When we counted, I had half a moku left.
I played well for myself, and I gained a lead.
I made the shape for a win. and
I was determined not to budge.
But... Shindou kept pushing
at me and pushing at me.
I tried to hold on, and the game ended
just when I thought I had lost.
There was half a moku left...
But, I can't believe that I won...
10...
20...
Hikaru!
I dreamt that I was half a moku short.
Is your loss from yesterday troubling you?
I'm glad that you don't have a match today.
What are you worried about?
I can play, even if I have a match today.
His losses and his wins...
All of the games leave something behind
in Hikaru, and make Hikaru stronger.
He grows with every game.
Hikaru...
Grandpa! Please call Touya 2dan.
I'll do my best, in the three
weeks left of the pro exam.
Thank you for your determination.
Please feel free to dress casually in the future.
I'll be excusing myself now, I have
some work to take care of.
I'll have someone bring you some tea.
I doubt you can do anything in just three weeks.
But, grandpa told me to call you so...
Call me "teacher" for the next three weeks.
How can you listen to anyone
that you're disrespectful to?
You can call me "you" or "Touya" or anything
else, after the pro exams are over.
You just said that I can't do anything
in only three weeks.
You're right. You won't get better
just by learning from a pro.
But, I think I can help you in
your match against Shindou.
I will be taking advantage...
of your obsession towards Shindou, teacher.
I'll try to come every day.
But, I may not be able to come on some days
because of matches or my schedule.
On those days...
If I know about it in advance,
I'll have another pro come.
No, don't do that.
They'll get in the way.
Get in the way?
Instead, replay Shuusaku's games.
Shuusaku?
I think there are around 400 of Shuusaku's
games left on record.
Replay all of his games, as many times as you can.
What does that have to do with Shindou?
What is he thinking?
Well, let's begin.
We're not playing?
I want to show you this game first.
A Korean kenkyuusei, Hong Su-Young, is black.
Shindou Hikaru is white.
Shindou played a match against
a Korean kenkyuusei!?
A teacher from my junior high
just happened to be there.
That teacher, replayed this game for me.
This... this white is Shindou!?
That move that I thought was a mistake,
was actually preparing for the fight here!
I hear that some of his Insei
friends were there too.
It's Isumi-san...
Isumi-san saw this match.
That's why he was cautious against Shindou.
And in the end, white...
Shindou... wins by one and a half moku...
If this is really Shindou's strength right now...
Three weeks...
isn't enough!
That's not true.
That's what I'm here for.
Tsutaetai omoi ga ima
伝えたい想いが今
These feelings I want to tell you
Afurete iru yo
溢れているよ
are spilling out right now
Kotoba ni dekinakute tomadotte iru
言葉にできなくて 戸惑っている
but I'm hesitating, not knowing how to put it into words
Deai kara kazoekirenu kisetsu ga meguri
出会いから　数えきれぬ 季節が巡り
so many seasons passed by since we met
Katari akashita yoru ga natsukashii yo ne
語りあかした夜が なつかしいよね
I miss that time we stayed up all night talking
Yume e chikazuku tabi ni
夢へ近づくたびに
As I walk towards my dreams
Hakanasa wo shitta yo
儚さを知ったよ
I learn what vain all my effort are
Sorezore no tabidachi
それぞれの旅立ち
Let's start each of
Koko kara hajimeyou
ここから始めよう
our departure here
Ima made no bokura to wa chigau
今までの僕達とは違う
I'm not like I was before
Mou makenai arukidashite iku yo
もう負けない 歩き出していくよ
I won't give up anymore, I'll keep on walking,
Donna mirai e demo
どんな未来へでも
no matter what the future holds.
Tsuyoku nareru you ni
強くなれるように...
So that I can become stronger.
Teacher Yukari
Mai
Today, we're at Tokyo city Kodaira district's
Fifth Public Kodaira Junior High School.
Tokyo City Kodaira District's
Fifth Public Kodaira Junior High School
Kodaira Five's Go club is a brand new
club that started just this year.
Tokyo Kodaira Junior High School     Go club     Formed in 2002    9 Members       Formed by 7th graders who were inspired by Hikaru no Go.
At first, they played on home made Go boards.
But as you can see, they are...
very active now. Doing things like...
keeping records of their matches,
and solving problem sets.
So, I challenged a club member again.
But, I lost.
I was close to winning too.
At the end, teacher Yukari gave us some Tsumego
problems, and we solved them together.
Their club just started, but
everyone was really good.
I lost my game too.
Please keep up the good work.
Everyone in Kodaira Junior High School
Thank you very much
To be continued...
Okay!
The top five just won't fall.
I've finally lost my grip on the cliff.
Who is Shindou!?
That's what I want to find out.
I want to find out how strong Shindou
is. His mysterious strength.