Fujiwarano Sai, a Go player from the Heian period
has passed through time and returned to
the world in the mind of Shindou Hikaru,
in order to obtain the Hand of God.
君が今僕を支えて
Kimi ga ima boku wo sasaete
Now you are,
holding me up strong!
僕が今君を支える
boku ga ima kimi wo sasaeru
Now I am,
holding you up as well!
だから迷いながらも共に生きていこうよ
Dakara Mayoi nagara mo tomo ni ikite ikou yo
So let us now, while wandering live together
未来へと
Mirai e to...
towards the future
Elite-Fansubs presents
Hikaru no Go
仲間と戯れ　それなりで居ても
Nakama to tawamaure sorenaride itemo
Even when I'm capricing with my friends,
もの足りなさを感じてしまう
mono tari na sa wo kanjite shimau
I feel an emptiness in my heart.
冷めた目で見られて
Sameta me de mirarete
Looked at with cold eyes,
乾いた時代の風に吹かれている
Kawaita jidai no kaze ni fukareteiru
I'm blown by the wind of a dry age
不安な 心と勇気が
Fuan na, kokoro to yuuki ga
Feelings of doubt and courage
背中合わせになっている
senaka awase ni natteiru
are back to back
だけど今なら夢をこの手で叶えてみせるよ
dakedo ima nara yume wo, kono te de kanaete miseru yo
but I'll make these dreams come true now with my own hands.
傷ついて壊れそうな日も
Kizutsuite koware sou na hi mo
The days where I'm hurt and about to break,
涙して困らせる日も
Namidashite komaraseru hi mo
the days where I cry and trouble you
あるけれど僕達はそれを
aru keredo bokura wa sore wo
They all exist, but we will
超えていくんだ誰より
koete ikunda dare yori...
get over it heading higher
上を目指して
ue wo mezashite!
than anyone else!
This makes one win and one loss.
It's up to Tsutsui...
The Sixth Match
The Beautiful Match
We're holding a Junior High
Go Tournament here today.
Could you possibly take a look at it later?
O-Okay.
Well...
I heard you were applying for our school...
I have something to ask of you...
Okay...
If you make it into this school,
could you possibly join our Go club?
But, I...
I understand.
For someone aiming towards becoming a pro, such as yourself, it's probably not an appropriate place.
However, the existence of someone to admire...
...would bring energy to the club.
Principal...
I...
I'm not as strong as you think I am.
Don't be so modest.
Those aren't the words someone who's
about to become a pro should say.
No...
Really, I'm...
We've won.
Really?
White... with Komi... 60 and a half moku.
Black... 61 moku.
I lost?
He came back?!
But you were winning...
He overcame a 20 moku difference in the Yose...
[note: Yose is the equivalent of the end game in Go. It is where
the shape of the game has more or less been decided, and the
two players compete for the small amounts of still disputed
territory. Usually only 2 or 3 moku of difference can be overcome
during Yose. Overcoming 20 moku during the Yose is incredible.]
Wow, you really don't make a mistake in the Yose do you?
At Mokusan and Yose...
[note: Mokusan is the process of calculating how much
territory each player controls. Pros can calculate it to
the moku, however, most people should aim at being
able to judge who's winning and who's losing]
I guess it cancels out your stupidity
in the opening and midgame.
Come on captain, go report the result!
Haze Junior High has won with 2 wins and a loss.
Haze Junior High has advanced
to the second round...
Wow, Haze Junior High?
They've gone past the first
round for the first time here?
Wow, you both won, that's incredible!
You had to resign halfway through.
Please begin the second match now.
Oushou
I resign.
Why didn't you try to enter the
Upper Right Corner Ikeshita?!
If you place a stone at 3,3
then you still have a chance.
That's not possible, I'd kill him even if he came in.
And even if he came in, he'd still lose.
Mister, why don't you try doing the mokusan?
His resignation is correct.
Kaiou wins 3-0.
Oh!
It's been decided already?! That was fast.
They've made it to the final match
again without any problem.
No...
This guy's stronger than the last.
He'll lose by about 5 moku...
I thought they were stronger...
but they're not that strong.
Isn't this the guy that recreated
our game before the tournament?
Yeah, it seems the only strong
guy there is the captain.
This guy doesn't stand a chance now.
Lemme see...
Hmm...
Your play is interesting but... it's
so inexperienced and unskilled...
I told you so! I told you so!
Really...
I have so much trouble judging Hikaru's potential...
Sometimes he makes some
really insightful moves...
and then he makes a real stupid move...
Tsutsui!
This makes 1 win and 1 loss.
This match...
If we don't win, we don't get a
Go club for Haze Junior High.
Tsutsui didn't want to tell you because
he didn't want to stress you out.
But... he said all we needed to do was participate.
That's not all.
The guy's over at the Shougi club are
angry that I had to work for the Go club.
They said that if we don't win, then
they're not going to forgive Tsutsui.
But! It's just that Tsutsui-san's really
devoted to establishing the Go Club.
Then why don't you play seriously?!
Show them your real strength!
Hey do you think you could keep it quiet?
If you don't hurry up and move, you'll lose on time.
Sai...
Please play...
I can't do it.
I can't win...
Sai...
But you told me not to do anything...
H.. Ah... Hikaru!
I'm sorry, I'm sorry!
You're angry aren't you, Hikaru?
That you can't win on your own strength?
Don't worry, if we combine our strength we can still win.
Wipe your tears, make sure you don't
place the stone in the wrong spot.
Let's do it.
8-3 Tsuke!
[note: Tsuke is where you place a stone next to your
opponent's stone. But, the stone that you place can
only be in contact with one opponent stone at the
time it's played for it to be considered a tsuke.]
Sorry, I was in the bathroom.
That kid won.
R-Really?
Did we really win?!
He really is something.
Makes me look forward to the finals.
We might be able to win.
It's unbelievable, I can't believe we came this far.
Tsutsui, throw that book away.
You don't need a book!
Throw it away! Your game begins there!
And him...
Will he play terribly like he did the first round?
Or will he play the way he just did?
We're about to begin the final
match in the boy's division.
Will the students from Kaiou Junior High
and Haze Junior High please get ready?
Tsutsui! We're going!
Please start your game now.
Good luck.
Sorry for all the trouble Touya-kun.
It's no problem.
Also, my father gives you his best wishes.
When your father was a
student here, I was his teacher.
We were in a wooden building back
then, and it wasn't as nice as this.
There was a room that was
rumored to be haunted...
and he'd play Go with me every now and then...
Dad played a game against Shindou Hikaru?!
He hasn't told you anything about it?
I bumped into him just outside.
And what happened?!
They played a few moves, and he ran out of here.
See you later.
Thanks for coming.
With just that, he can't really say anything.
A child strong enough to make Akira-kun worry...
I guess I can't just sit around either.
Touya-kun...
Touya-kun!
Y-Yes?
Why don't we take a quick look at this?
Third Annual North District Winter Junior High Go Tournament Hall.
Seems like they're on the final match already.
He's the person in charge of our Go Club, Mr.Yun
Shindou!
Why is he at a place like this?!
5-10 Hane.
[note: Hane is the process of playing a stone diagonally
from one of your stones, to a position adjacent to an
opponent that's adjacent to the first stone.
XO
X
It's a very common move in Go, and it's
usually very strong when used properly]
9-3 Hiraki
[note: Hiraki is a move where you place a stone deep
into unclaimed territory from an area that you control.
What it does is claim the unclaimed territory as your own.]
17-14 Hiraki!
17-4 Tsuke!
Hikaru, listen to me.
Don't just play where I tell you to, like a
puppet, but try to feel the flow of the stones.
The flow of the stones?
18-5 Hane!
From now on, I'll play a game to show you Hikaru.
Just look at the flow of this game.
You should be able to do it already Hikaru.
That is your first step.
17-3 Nobi!
[note: Nobi is a move that extends a
stone you already have on the board]
16-5 Ate!
[note: Ate is the process of placing a stone
so that an opponent's stone is in Atari.]
[note: Atari is where a stone formation is
one move away from being captured]
Hikaru...
You have awakened!
I resign.
Thanks for the match.
The Kaiou Go Club...
I've heard of them...
I guess guys like Touya Akira
are a dime a dozen there...
I guess Tsutsui stands no chance against them then.
What about that kid?
Touya!
What's he looking intently at?!
No, I can't do it.
I've tried upto now, but I guess it's about time for me to resign...
Cutting there was supposed to be useless...
I guess the possibility arose due to Damezumari...
[note: Damezumari is the process where empty
breaths are taken through the regular course of
the game. When this occurs, formations that seemed
lively earlier in the game, could enter into danger.]
I can win!
I'll win by about 8 moku now!
I won't let him come back in the Yose!
I resign.
Kaga, I...
Shindou-kun...
This is the end, Hikaru.
We won...
This one did well playing until now...
This kifu was formed, because
of your strength as well.
[note: Kifu is a record of the order in which the stones are placed
in a Go match. In this instance, Sai is referring to the impression
this game made in the minds of the people involved in it.]
Feel proud.
You played well.
Mr. Yun...
Yes!
Touya!
It was a beautiful match...
I'm angry...
Why wasn't I playing you in that match?!
Shindou-kun...
I realize now that I won't reach the
Hand of God if I don't surpass you.
Therefore...
I won't run from you anymore.
Well, the final match between Kaiou
Junior High and Haze Junior High is a win
by Haze with a record of 2 wins to 1 loss.
Who would've thought that Kaiou would lose?!
Could you lend me that marker for a second?
Yes.
That kid... it's Hikaru!
But aren't you a 6th grader right now?!
They found out!
Just what is this about?
Aren't you a student of Haze?
I'm sorry! I asked him to come for us!
Winner of the third annual North District Winter
What about the Go club?
Junior High Go tournament
is Kaiou Junior High School.
We'll try again next year.
What about you Kaga?
I wanna go back to the Shougi
Club as soon as possible.
We give you this to show your
excellence in the tournament.
Oh yeah...
And we wish you luck in your later matches
against other schools from the city of Tokyo.
All that stuff I said about not winning
the tournament. It was all a lie.
Thank you very much.
Hikaru....
That last match... did you feel something from it?
Yeah
Sai, maybe you really are an incredible guy.
That serious look Touya has, stares straight at Sai.
That guy'll probably chase after Sai with all his strength.
Touya might catch up to him...
and I'm far far behind them...
But from there, I'll take my first step!
Haze
Junior
High
どこにあるのかな
Dokoni aru no kana?
Where is it?
ボクだけの宝物
bokudakeno takaramono
The treasure that belongs to me
今　大きな冒険へ
ima ookina bouken e
Now with a great adventure...
やわらかな日差し
yawarakana hizashi
the gentle sunlight
旅立ちの予感
tabitachi no yokan
a feeling of departure
空も花も　ホラ 笑っている
sora mo hana mo hora waratte iru
The sky and the flower are both laughing!
この先には何が待つのだろう
kono saki ni wa nani ga matsu no darou?
I wonder what waits ahead for me.
深呼吸
shinkokyuu
take a deep breath...
夢の扉にそっと手をかけて　行こう
yume no tobira ni soutto te wo kakete... ikou!
place your hand gently on the door to your dreams... let's go!
風に吹かれながら
kaze ni fukare nagara
Because I was blown by the wind!
心揺らしながら
kokoro yurashi nagara
Because my heart was touched!
真っ白な地図を片手に持ちながら
masshiro na chizu wo katate ni mochinagara
holding my belongings in one hand
風に吹かれながら
kaze ni fukare nagara
Because I was blown by the wind!
明日を描きながら
asu wo kaki nagara
Because I can't cause strife!
遠くまで　何処まで
tooku made, doko made?
far away
たどり着けるまで
tadori tsukeru made
until I reach that place...
絶対負けないよ　絶対泣かないよ
zettai makenaiyo zettai nakanaiyo
I won't lose! I won't lose!
この夢を叶えるその日までは
kono yume wo kanaeru sono hi made wa
Until the day that I make this dream come true!
あの空は笑っていた
ano sora wa waratteita
That sky is fleeting!
あの花はも笑っていた
ano hana mo waratteita
That flower is fleeting!
ボクもいつか笑うから
boku mo itsuka warau kara
Some day I will laugh with you!
どんな壁も越えるから
donna kabe mo koeru kara
I will surpass any obstacle!
もう　何も何も　コワクナイ
mou nani mo... nani mo kowakunai
I'm not afraid of anything any more!
Umezawa Yukari's
Go Go Igo!
Go! Go! Igo!
Oh no, a Ko's formed.
...ko?
What's happened Teacher?
Yuuki
Teacher Yukari
Mai
There's an important rule
that we need to deal with.
Mai-chan took back when
Yuuki-kun captured her stone right?
Studying "Ko"
If you keep taking the stone, then the game will go on forever.
If you both keep capturing each
other, then the game will never end.
That's why there's an important
rule called "Ko" in Igo.
When white takes black's stone, black can't
take back the white stone immediately.
Black has to place it somewhere else first,
and then you can take the stone back.
You have to move somewhere else once first.
White can capture again after
moving somewhere else first.
After that you can capture the stone.
This is the rule called "Ko"
Let's continue from where Yuuki-kun captured.
To be continued...
Join the Igo Club! Contact 3-2 Tsutsui.
In order to catch up to you.
I've risen since our last match.
Join the Igo Club! Contact 3-2 Tsutsui.
I'm waiting for you.
I'm not playing with you.
I'm gonna work hard with Tsutsui-san in the Go Club.
You can't possibly fear me...
Why?!
Why won't you play against me?!