Fujiwarano Sai, a Go player from the Heian period
has passed through time and returned to
the world in the mind of Shindou Hikaru...
in order to obtain the Hand of God.
君が今僕を支えて
Kimi ga ima boku wo sasaete
Now you are,
holding me up strong!
僕が今君を支える
boku ga ima kimi wo sasaeru
Now I am,
holding you up as well!
だから迷いながらも共に生きていこうよ
Dakara Mayoi nagara mo tomo ni ikite ikou yo
So let us now, while wandering live together
未来へと
Mirai e to...
towards the future
Elite-Fansubs presents
Hikaru no Go
仲間と戯れ　それなりで居ても
Nakama to tawamaure sorenaride itemo
Even when I'm capricing with my friends,
もの足りなさを感じてしまう
mono tari na sa wo kanjite shimau
I feel an emptiness in my heart.
冷めた目で見られて
Sameta me de mirarete
Looked at with cold eyes,
乾いた時代の風に吹かれている
Kawaita jidai no kaze ni fukareteiru
I'm blown by the wind of a dry age
不安な 心と勇気が
Fuan na, kokoro to yuuki ga
Feelings of doubt and courage
背中合わせになっている
senaka awase ni natteiru
are back to back
だけど今なら夢をこの手で叶えてみせるよ
dakedo ima nara yume wo, kono te de kanaete miseru yo
but I'll make these dreams come true now with my own hands.
傷ついて壊れそうな日も
Kizutsuite koware sou na hi mo
The days where I'm hurt and about to break,
涙して困らせる日も
Namidashite komaraseru hi mo
the days where I cry and trouble you
あるけれど僕達はそれを
aru keredo bokura wa sore wo
They all exist, but we will
超えていくんだ誰より
koete ikunda dare yori...
get over it heading higher
上を目指して
ue wo mezashite!
than anyone else!
A gap of 12 and a half moku with komi.
I win.
Hey boy, take out 10,000 yen.
The Twelfth Match
You Are The Third Board
I came to the chem lab just like you asked me to.
Now gimme 10,000 yen.
Not until you agree to join the Go Club.
You will join right?
Yeah I'll join the club,
I can't go back to that Go Salon anyways.
Gimme my 20 yen back!
Sure.
Let's play!
10,000 yen?
With no betting.
We are just the Go club after all.
Can I take white?
I don't care.
No cheating, okay Mitani?
Maybe.
Mitani!
Tsutsui-san!
Mitani said he'll join the Go club,
and that he won't cheat anymore.
What?
Are you still angry about how I tricked
you into making two consecutive moves?
That's your own fault for being
stupid enough to fall for it.
I heard from Shindou-kun.
You were cheating at Seichi?
That's not all.
I moved stones, or hid stones in my
pocket, and used them at Seichi.
I don't lose.
They're just words! He just says stuff like this.
It's the way he is.
Hikaru!
Oh, Mitani-kun.
What is it?
I made cookies today during Home Ed.
Here's some for you, Tsutsui-san.
Can I have some? I'm hungry.
Sure, if you stop cheating.
Did you tell everyone?
But it's true isn't it?
I only told Tsutsui-san and Akari!
You won't right?
I won't, I won't.
Here Hikaru.
Thank you!
Great, now we can go to the tournament.
Tournament?
I'm not going to that.
W-what!?
I dragged you here for the tournament!
None of my business.
You're on our team!
It's been decided.
No.
No "no"s!
Tsutsui-san...
say something!
There's no need to force him
to go when he doesn't want to.
But...
It'll be impossible to find someone else now.
We don't have any time left before the tournament.
Whats going to happen to
our goal of beating Kaiou!?
It's not like we can beat them even if he joins.
Kaiou's really strong.
It's just a Jr. High club, right?
You don't stand a chance against Kaiou!
But Tsutsui-san, you won against
Kaiou at the last tournament.
But only because he made a mistake!
What?
I don't stand a chance against a guy like that?
Want me to beat them for ya?
Mitani...
You're going to go to the tournament!
I'll beat them before your very eyes.
You don't know how strong they are.
How funny.
I told you.
I don't lose.
Come on,
let's start.
That can't be!
Does he intend to cheat against Kaiou?
Kaiou would realize!
If that happens...
what will happen to the Haze Jr. High Go Club?
This is terrible.
I resign.
Thanks for the game.
Mind if I don't discuss the game?
I should make it clear.
The tournament is coming up.
Mr. Yun should be announcing
the team members soon.
I'd better display the difference
in strength between Touya and I,
so no one complains when he announces.
Hey...
Touya!
Yes?
Let's play a game.
It's our first game, do you mind if we make it even?
Sure.
Sempai
Are the first, second, and third boards
for tournaments decided by strength?
There are teams where it's not, but usually is.
Concentrate on your own games.
Okay.
Shindou... almost...
I'll almost...
catch you!
Touya, the tournament registration
form has arrived from Haze Jr. High.
Take a look at it.
Shindou is the third board!?
Sometimes, they don't decide the boards
by strength for strategic purposes.
The Fourth Summer North District Jr. High Go Tournament Registration Form
To the Tournament Officials
This Jr. High School wishes to register for the Fourth Summer North
District Jr. High Go Tournament. In participating, we promise to follow
the rules of the tournament, and not engage in any dishonest conduct.
In the case that we do engage in dishonest conduct, we will
not object to any sort of consequences that you may give.
Jr.High: Haze Public Jr. High School
The participants are as follows
Name   Year
First Mitani Yuuki First
Second Tsutsui Tomihiko Third
Third Shindou Hikaru First Year
Alternate ____________
That Mitani is probably the weakest in the group.
By throwing away the first board,
they probably plan on
definitely taking the other two.
Since, Tsutsui is in his third year, and
the president, he's the second board,
leaving Hikaru at third probably.
Teacher, please make me our third board!
Teacher!
Let me think about it.
I do think that you are the only
person who can play Shindou.
Thank you!
I resign.
Thank you for the game.
I didn't stand a chance.
Not at all!
You were far better than I thought.
You were just to good,
you saw far deeper than I did.
Perhaps I tried to control the center too much.
It probably won't work because of all the
discontinuities in your stone formations.
[note: Stone formations are usually stronger when they
are connected to each other. In this case, Akira was able
to cut Kishimoto's formations apart, weakening them.]
I connected here in my desperation,
and I was constantly on the defensive after that.
You wouldn't let me do anything.
It was correct of me to give
up on trying to become pro.
Everyone, listen up for a second.
Most of the registration forms from the other
schools have arrived for this tournament.
Sorry I'm late, but I'll announce our team for it.
First the boys.
First Board:
First year, Touya.
Second Board:
Third year, Kishimoto.
Third Board:
Third year, Kuno.
Now the girls...
Teacher!
Weren't you going to make me third board!?
Japanese Go Institution Center
Good morning Mr. Kuwabara
Oh! I haven't seen you in awhile.
Perfect, let me talk to you for a bit then.
The Gosei match next month, I'm
going to be challenging you for it.
[note: Gosei is one of the 8 major titles]
I wish you luck.
I'm aware of it.
You crushed Ogata-kun with your strength.
At your age too, I'm astonished.
Come now, you're hardly young yourself.
How many titles do you have now? 4,5?
I'd like the one you have for my fifth.
But really, the young people disappoint me.
Even if they manage to get a
title, they lose it right away.
No really astounding new comers lately either.
Are the Inseis getting weaker?
How is your son doing?
He's not an insei right?
He plays me regularly, and he
plays any pro that visits us.
He's not lagging behind in his study of the game.
He's not taking the pro exams?
No
He's in the Go club of his Jr. High right now.
When I heard that you joined the Go
club at Kaiou, I didn't say anything.
The principal told me that your
presence would encourage the club,
so I let you do as you wish...
But, why are you going to the tournament?
It's unbefitting for you to
go to a Jr. High tournament.
I don't care about the people around me right now.
If Shindou Hikaru is going to a club tournament,
then I'm going to follow him there.
Father, it may sound arrogant...
but my goal is you, Father.
I've progressed towards
that goal steadily until now.
I thought I just had to walk straight towards you.
I thought that walking straight would
place me closer to the hand of god.
But I was wrong...
I couldn't do anything...
against Shindou Hikaru.
He's different from Father, or Ogata-san.
His presence is a weight upon me.
Right now, he is the only thing on my mind.
He's facing the obstacle despite his fear...
that's the only way a person can grow.
It was something you didn't have before.
Chasing while shivering, challenging while fearing,
only through that can you approach the hand of god.
Teacher!
Were you not going to make me third board!?
You said yourself that only I
stand a chance against him.
I...
I... joined to fight...
Touya!
This is a Jr. High club activity.
I believe that the strongest
person should play first board.
Teacher!?
That's not all!
The Go club of Kaiou is a model for other schools.
I did say that you're the only one who stands
a chance against Shindou Hikaru of Haze.
But...
This is a place of education.
I will not bend my will as an educator.
You are the first board.
But...
Just once...
Just this one tournament is all...
Once this tournament is over, I'll quit the club!
Teacher! I...!
Teacher!
Touya...
Hey! Mitani!
Great, I thought you might
not come, out of fear of Kaiou.
You've gotta be kidding.
Nothing good can come of
that black formation running.
If that runs, the other group
of black will get captured.
Shut up!
Tsutsui-san...
Mitani, why'd you cheat if you're that strong?
Oh, there they are.
Akari! You didn't have to come.
You wouldn't understand even if you watched.
I would!
Tsutsui-san's been teaching me lately.
I know how to capture stones and count territories.
What!? But I made lunches for all of you!
You're wonderful!
Hey, Mitani-kun...
Fujisaki-san, I'll show you to the
room where you can drop that off.
Thanks...
Mitani... let's play!
No thanks.
Will it really be alright like this?
Oh? It's Shindou of Haze!
Huh?
Shindou?
Haze?
He won against Kaiou at the last tournament.
He was only a 6th grader, but
he participated as a Jr. High,
and everyone watching was astounded by his play.
This is a problem...
Don't worry about that.
Just try your best.
Yup!
My best! My best!
First, I'll beat the third board of the first round...
Is it really that simple Hikaru?
He'll be trying his best too...
Come on, my target is Kaiou.
I can't afford to lose my first round.
Then, if I do my best up against Kaiou...
maybe...
Kaiou's third board will try his best too, Hikaru...
Oh man! I can't wait for the match against Kaiou.
I wonder who Kaiou's third board is...
It's me.
Kaiou's third board is me...
Shindou!
Touya...
Why are you...
Do you remember saying that you won't play me?
And that you were going to
the Go club tournament?
I finally arrived.
Touya...
you came all this way...
chasing... Sai?
どこにあるのかな
Dokoni aru no kana?
Where is it?
ボクだけの宝物
bokudakeno takaramono
The treasure that belongs to me
今　大きな冒険へ
ima ookina bouken e
Now with a great adventure...
やわらかな日差し
yawarakana hizashi
the gentle sunlight
旅立ちの予感
tabitachi no yokan
a feeling of departure
空も花も　ホラ 笑っている
sora mo hana mo hora waratte iru
The sky and the flower are both laughing!
この先には何が待つのだろう
kono saki ni wa nani ga matsu no darou?
I wonder what waits ahead for me.
深呼吸
shinkokyuu
take a deep breath...
夢の扉にそっと手をかけて　行こう
yume no tobira ni soutto te wo kakete... ikou!
place your hand gently on the door to your dreams... let's go!
風に吹かれながら
kaze ni fukare nagara
Because I was blown by the wind!
心揺らしながら
kokoro yurashi nagara
Because my heart was touched!
真っ白な地図を片手に持ちながら
masshiro na chizu wo katate ni mochinagara
holding my belongings in one hand
風に吹かれながら
kaze ni fukare nagara
Because I was blown by the wind!
明日を描きながら
asu wo kaki nagara
Because I can't cause strife!
遠くまで　何処まで
tooku made, doko made?
far away
たどり着けるまで
tadori tsukeru made
until I reach that place...
絶対負けないよ　絶対泣かないよ
zettai makenaiyo zettai nakanaiyo
I won't lose! I won't lose!
この夢を叶えるその日までは
kono yume wo kanaeru sono hi made wa
Until the day that I make this dream come true!
あの空は笑っていた
ano sora wa waratteita
That sky is fleeting!
あの花はも笑っていた
ano hana mo waratteita
That flower is fleeting!
ボクもいつか笑うから
boku mo itsuka warau kara
Some day I will laugh with you!
どんな壁も越えるから
donna kabe mo koeru kara
I will surpass any obstacle!
もう　何も何も　コワクナイ
mou nani mo... nani mo kowakunai
I'm not afraid of anything any more!
Umezawa Yukari's
Go Go Igo!
Go! Go! Igo!
Let's try another problem.
Teacher Yukari
If black moves, it can capture
a few of white's stones.
Where can black go to capture white's stones?
Think about it.
Everyone try it!
Yuuki
Mai
Even if they capture one of your
stones, you can capture a lot more.
Hint: Even if they capture one of your stones, you can capture a lot more.
White'll do this.
And then this.
Think about it again. But,
it is one of the three spots.
What!?
Yup.
I take...
One stone was taken but...
and if I connect...
That's right! Pick up the stones you captured.
You did it Yuuki-kun!
Happy new years!
Have a nice 2002!
So you're from Kaiou.
I heard you guys are good,
But you lost to Haze Junior earlier?
Mitani is...
He is our first board!
Don't underestimate him.
You can't laugh until it's over!