kono me kimi no me ni
この瞳君の瞳に
On this eye, this eye on yours,
utsuru donna mono mo
映るどんなモノも
everything will appear.
mikiwamete miseru yo shinjitsu wo
見極めて見せるよ 真実を
I will tell apart the truth.
------- -------- -- -- --- - --- --- ---- ---- ---
Real-Fansubbers
Presents
----- ----- ---- --- -- --
----- ---- ---- --- - - --
Hikaru
Hikaru no Go
bokutachi wa kono jidai ni
僕達はこの時代に
How many dreams did we carry with us,
dore dake no yume kakaete
どれだけの夢抱えて
through this day and age?
namida shite mayoi nagara
涙して迷いながら
We gave them all a try, even as we cried
sore ni kakete miteru no
それに賭けてみてるの
wandering around so very lost.
boku wa sore demo hito ni hiketoranu you na
僕は それでも 人にひけとらぬような
Even then, I will find a deciding move,
kimete mitsuke yume wo te ni suru darou
決め手見つけ夢を手にするだろう
just as good as anyone else's, and take hold of my dreams.
kono me kimi no me ni
この瞳君の瞳に
On this eye, this eye of yours,
utsuru donna mono mo
映るどんなモノも
everything will appear.
mikiwamete miseru yo shinjitsu dake
見極めて見せるよ 真実だけ
I'll tell apart, just the truth.
tatoe genjitsu ga
たとえ現実が
Even if the truth is
kitsuku umoresou demo
きつく埋もれそうでも
so harsh it's suffocating.
konna basho de owaru
こんな場所で終わる
I'm not going to end
boku janai
僕じゃない
in a place like this.
This atmosphere...
It feels familiar.
Yes! This atmosphere...
This feeling of pressure...
I've felt it before.
This is...
It's the old Shindou...
that I see in Sai!
I... finally understand.
God has...
given me a thousand years...
just to show Hikaru this match.
The Fifty-Seventh Match
Let Me Play Sai!
Hikaru...
Father...
Sai...
It's Sai...
Ah! The wind feels great!
Say,
Sai.
You told me before...
that only the people playing the
game can see some things.
Well, being where I was during
that game it felt as if...
I could see what you were thinking,
and I could see what Master Touya was thinking.
I felt as if I was in the very
middle of that match today.
Master Touya must be really
disappointed, losing to Sai!
If I lose this match, I will retire.
Did he really mean that!?
Ah, that was close.
AISHINDOU
HOSPITAL
Well...
I came here first thing in the morning, but...
He can't really be serious, can he?
I mean, it's crazy!
Someone with five titles can't just retire... right?
Y-yes...
What? Were you thinking about something else?
Ahh! Why am I always the one that has to worry?
Let's go, Sai.
Touya Kouyou-sama
Akira-san?
G-Good morning.
I'm sorry, who were you again?
Touya's mom!
U-umm... I...
He's Shindou-kun, he just became a pro this year.
Remember? We played once.
Ah, yes! I remember seeing you on Weekly Go.
You're the same age as Akira-san, right?
Akiko... I'm sorry, but could you
leave the room for a minute?
Okay, okay.
Umm...
Master, you resigned yesterday, but...
you won't retire... right?
You said that you'd retire if you
lost to Sai on impulse, right?
Right?
I just wanted to make sure...
Are you...
Sai?
No! No! It's not me! Why do you think I'm Sai!?
He reminded me of you during the game...
of the feeling I got when we played
in the Room of Deep Contemplation.
Sorry.
I won't pursue it.
I don't care who Sai is.
Shindou-kun...
Let me...
Let me play Sai again!
I don't care if it's on the net.
I won't ask him to tell me who he is anymore.
Again?
Oh yeah...
We could do that if he plans to
continue to play on the net.
Yeah.
Master Touya would probably keep
it secret from anyone else.
I can probably let Sai play from time to time.
He would probably like that a lot.
It's too late.
I probably don't...
have enough time for that.
I can feel it...
Inside me...
The sands of time that were frozen within me...
are mercilessly and without doubt...
starting to flow once more.
Master...
Then... if I let you play him again, will you
take back what you said about retiring?
I won't take back what I said.
I intend to retire after the upcoming
fifth game of the Jyudan match.
But I just asked you not to do
anything crazy like that!
Retiring is not a great concern for me.
In fact, it might be for the better.
I'll be freed from the constraints and
responsibilities that come from being a pro.
I won't have to accept any boring interviews.
It's not that I won't be able to play Go.
I have this existence.
The happiness of existing...
I can play an all absorbing game
of Go outside of the title matches.
The match I played yesterday proves it!
I can play a game at that high of a level
with someone I've never met before!
Let me play Sai again, Shindou-kun!
I have no idea who Sai is.
But...
There is someone connected to Sai nearby.
Is it Shindou...
or is it one of the other people that visited him?
Anyway, the person who heard that
the Meijin plays go on the Internet,
and arranged the match...
Who is it?
Master Touya should know.
This voice...
Is it Shindou!?
I can't hear what they're saying.
That may be okay for you, Master,
but not for me! I can't have
that. It'll all be my fault.
You want to play Sai again don't you, Master?
Sai feels the same way! So please
give up on that idea!
Hikaru!
Oga...
Sai...
you said!?
So you do know who Sai is!
No! No! No! I don't know him! I have no idea!
Ogata-kun!
Liar!
You just said...
Bye!
Wait!
Shindou!
Did you arrange the match between
Sai and the Master!?
No! It wasn't me!
If you know who Sai is...
Let me play him, too!
Mr. Ogata...
M-Mr. Ogata...
You know Sai, don't you!?
If you know him then let me play him, too!
I-I don't know him! I don't know him!
I just... happened to be watching the game...
between Sai and Master Touya on the Internet...
Shindou!
Touya...
Ogata-san!
Ogata-san...
What happened?
Shindou was visiting the Master in his room.
He ran away when I went in.
I heard some of what they were talking about.
Chances are, Shindou and Sai know each other.
He was denying it, but...
all we have to do is ask the Master.
They know each other...
No!
Shindou and Sai are...
Master.
Ogata-kun.
Akira...
It was Shindou, wasn't it, who arranged
your match against Sai.
No.
Master!
He has nothing to do with it.
Sai challenged me to a game on the Internet
first thing in the morning yesterday.
That's all.
Seems like you both watched the match yesterday.
It was a game deserving of my name, wasn't it?
Well?
But... Sai went above me.
Akira-kun, ask him!
Don't you want to find out who Sai is as well?
If Father says that he doesn't know who Sai is...
there's no point in asking him about it any further.
Ogata-san thinks that Sai and
Shindou are different people.
I don't have an answer for it yet.
But the one thing I know for certain is...
that Shindou holds the answer to all of these mysteries.
There's nothing I can do if both
Shindou and the Master deny it.
So this is it...
Oh! Akira-san.
Ogata-san, too?
Hello.
Did Shindou-kun leave?
Shindou-kun was just here.
Phew, that was close.
Seems like Mr. Ogata heard me talking about Sai.
And then Touya came in, too, to top it off.
I wonder if he still thinks that I'm Sai.
Well, I'm sure Master Touya
won't tell them anything.
But I think I can let you play the Meijin again, Sai.
Sai?
What's wrong Sai, you look sad.
I said that I can let you play him again some time.
Don't worry about it!
I'm sure that Master Touya won't
tell anyone about me.
I can let you play from time to time.
From time to time?
How distant that sounds to me right now.
Hey! I just let you play yesterday!
Tsk. You're always asking for more. Let's go home.
Ahh! Dammit.
Well, I don't think we'll be
able to play him for a bit,
because there will be a commotion over his retiring...
Don't be impatient, we've got plenty of time.
There is...
no time...
Hikaru may have it but...
I don't...
Japanese Go Institute
Waya, is this it?
The game that Kouyou played on the Internet?
Yes! I was watching this game from start to end.
It's an awesome match! It really is.
Is Black Master Touya?
Yes.
But really... I can't see him using computers.
I thought that computers weren't for either of us...
Hello.
Hey, Shindou-kun.
Hey, Shindou.
It's Sai!
Sai came back to the Internet!
We're going over a game he played
against Touya Meijin right now.
You saw it too, Waya?
I saw it too.
What!? You saw it too?
So the opponent, playing White, is Sai?
Yes. I told you about him before, Master.
I told you there was someone
really strong on the Internet.
This is him!
And then Sai... White went here.
What an astounding move.
And then, it went like this...
and Black resigned here.
Game over.
Resigned!? Here!?
It's a half moku match...
White's winning? Isn't there
anything Black can do?
What if he doesn't respond here?
No, that's definitely Sente.
White can't lose any more territory...
I'm starting to get a headache.
Well, the thing is...
What?
Black would've gained territory if he had played
in the corner instead of connecting here.
I see...
Oh!
You're right.
See? Black is ahead by a bit this way.
He'll need to move there once all
the outside liberties are gone.
He can't move back there at this point either...
But you always miss stuff like this, Shindou!
Waya, stop making light of it!
This move decided the match.
Shindou-kun, have you calculated it out?
Oh! You noticed it because you usually
don't calculate stuff out!
What did you say!?
Everyone is starting to notice
the strength Hikaru has...
I can see it...
The brilliant future that is...
shinning about Hikaru... the future that I lack.
tsurai omoide toka ikutsu atta no kana?
つらい想い出とかいくつあったのかな？
How many sad memories did we have?
donna tanoshii hi wo
どんな楽しい日を
What kind of happy days are we going to
kore kara wa taisetsu ni shite iku no kana?
これからは大切にしていくのかな？
hold onto preciously from now on?
chikaku no kouen de atsumatta ne itsumo
近くの公園で集まったねいつも
We always gathered at the nearby park
yonaka made ookina koe dashite waratteta ne
夜中まで大きな声出して笑ってたね
and laughed out loud into the middle of the night,
zutto... zutto...
ずっとずっと
always... always...
onaji toki wo ima ikiteru kiseki ga
同じ時代を今生きてる奇跡が
Because I'm really happy for the miracle
sugoku ureshii kara ne
すごくうれしいからね
of being here when you are
tsugi au hi mo kitto nee
次あう日もきっとねぇ
Let's laugh together again
issho ni waratte iyou yo
一緒に笑っていようよ
the next time we meet
kondo wa donna yume wo
今度はどんな夢を
what kind of dreams
issho ni katariau no kana?
一緒に語りあうのかな？
are we going to talk about then?
Teacher Yukari
Mai
Hey, Mai-chan, do you remember what Komi is?
Teacher Yukari
Mai
Yup!
Well Komi just changed from five and a half moku
"Komi",                           the Handicap given to Black,
is changing from 5.5 moku to 6.5 moku!
to six and a half moku.
Why?
It's because Black's win rate has been
Black's win percentage from the last five years was 51.86%!
significantly higher in the last five years.
Komi recently became seven and a half moku in China.
In China, Komi is 7.5 moku.         It's 6.5 moku in Korea!
Since komi became six and a half moku in Korea,
Japan has decided to follow in their footsteps
and change komi to six and a half moku.
Note from translator: As stupid as this joke is, I have no choice but to explain it. 'Gomoku
Gohan' is a type of food dish, and it sounds like 'Gomoku han' which is 5.5 moku.
I thought it was because people mistook it for Gomoku Gohan.
I thought it was because people would
mistake it for Gomoku Gohan~!
That's not quite it...
Overseas matches have become more prevalent recently
and the players have changed their view of the rule.
Komi didn't even exist in Shuusaku's time,
This is the first major rule change in
the last 50 years, and it was made to keep up with the times.
what a big difference that is from six and a half moku.
The rules of Go change with the time.
To be continued...
Okay! I'll see exactly how far I can go
playing against Kurata-san!
Huh?
They're both white...
Oh well, let's play like this.
It's one color Go.
One color Go?
It's just starting to get interesting.