胸の鼓動　熱くゆるがす
mune no kodou atsuku yurugasu
My heart walks, searching for something exciting
刺激求めて歩く My Heart
shigeki motomete aruku MY HEART
That will passionately sway the beating in my chest.
時間だけが過ぎる毎日じゃ
jikan dake ga sugiru mainichi jya
If I just wait for the time to pass everyday.
変化はない
henka ha nai
nothing's going to change.
Woo Wooo
止まらない　信じたい　進みたい
tomaranai shinjitai susumitai
I won't stop. I want to believe. I want to move forward.
自分の力試す My Life
jibun no chikara tamesu MY LIFE
I will test my strength during my life.
でも早歩きしたって見落とすだけ
demo hayaaruki shitatte miotosudake
But even if I walk faster.
I will definitely lose track of
そう確実に
sou kakujitsu ni
the important things.
Baby for you...
明日は明日の風が吹く
ashita ha ashita no kaze ga fuku
Tomorrow's wind will blow tomorrow.
それでも　今この瞬間を強く生きたい
soredemo
but I want to make the most out of this moment now.
ima kono shunkan wo tsuyoku ikitai
It's fantasy
さまよったとしても
samayotta to shitemo
Even if I'm wandering,
見たことない世界でも
mitakotonai sekai demo
even if I'm in a strange new world,
何よりも 自分を信じ立ち向かおう
nani yori mo jibun wo shinji tachimukaou
I'll stand up to it,
believing in myself more than anything else.
It's destiny
どんな場所にいても
donna basho ni itemo
No matter where I am,
つつむ空は一つだから
tsutsumu sora ha hitotsu dakara
I'm surrounded by the same sky.
ねぇ　もっと 翼広げて
nee motto tsubasa hirogete
so I'll be able to fly
羽ばたけるよね
habatakeruyone
with my wings spread out.
Waya, have you heard? Murota 9-dan, the head
of the pros committee, gave Shindou a call.
And?
He asked if Shindou was sick or needed to file
for leave, but he didn't get a clear answer.
That idiot!
I wonder if he's going to quit being a pro.
I have no idea.
And to think people thought he could become Touya's rival.
Genius is meaningless if you don't play.
If I were to want to play...
If I were to play Go again...
Sai would be gone forever...
That...
I... I'm afraid of that.
The Sixty-Ninth Match
The Determined Visitor
I haven't been in Japan for two months.
The pro exams are approaching.
Kadowaki, the former holder of three
student titles. Will be taking them.
It's finally starting next week.
I wonder how everyone's doing...
The results from the match last week...
Ochi beat Mashiba!
Waya didn't have a match...
And Shindou...?
Forfeit!?
Isumi-san!
You haven't changed at all.
You would look like you had just come back from
training if you had a beard or something.
I was surprised when you called.
How was China?
Huh? What is it?
Le Ping! You grew up so quickly!
So that's what you were doing.
Yeah. It's good that Le Ping started following me around and studying, but...
he was always glaring at me.
What a brat.
He's just a kid, but he's really good.
But I did end up becoming good friends with him.
All thanks to the Waya medicine.
Waya medicine?
I gave him some medicine when
he got a stomach ache.
Remember? The kind you always
take when you have one.
I figured since he looks just like you, the
medicine would work on him, too.
That makes no sense!
Anyway, it worked like a charm,
and we became good friends.
And?
What about your match against that Zhao Shi?
What happened?
I lost... Zhao got Yang Hai-san's MD player.
But I won the next time we played!
We played a few times after that, too.
And I renewed my visa over there.
Anyway, I played all that I could
during the last two months,
surrounded by the top players of China,
and the future top players of China.
It was really tough.
But I won against a few people, and above
all I've gained confidence in myself.
Good.
Oh Yeah, what was it you wanted to ask
me about that you mentioned on the phone?
This.
I picked one up to read all this
time, and Shindou had a forfeit!
I was wondering what's wrong.
Is he sick?
I wanted to see him again before
the pro exams, so...
Waya?
That's not the only match Shindou
has a forfeit on, Isumi-san.
It's been like that since May.
Don't trip now.
I don't understand.
It seems like he doesn't want to play Go anymore.
Sai...
Oh, Isumi-kun!
Hello, long time no see.
I heard from Mr. Narusawa, you were studying
in China? When did you get back?
Just the other day.
Would you mind telling me what the young
players there were like sometime?
Sure.
I'll contact you later then, thank you.
U-Umm... Amono-san.
Have you heard anything about Shindou?
Shindou Hikaru first dan?
Yes.
I don't understand why he hasn't gone
to any of the matches, and...
I don't know. Ogata Jyudan asked
me about it earlier, too.
Master Ogata?
Master Ogata!
You played Shindou?
Yeah, towards the end of Golden Week.
One night during the Go seminar
run by the Go institute.
To the best of my knowledge, he hasn't gone to
any matches or the Wakajishisen since then.
Was anything out of the ordinary
when he played you?
Out of the ordinary?
I was really drunk.
Thank you for the ride.
Don't worry about it.
Let me know if you learn anything about Shindou.
Okay.
So he hasn't come here either.
I'd beat him to a pulp if he did. Yelling,
"What the hell are you thinking!?"
I'm sure there's a reason.
What?
Well, I don't know exactly what, but Kawai-san
remember what you said about visiting Shuusaku?
Shuusaku? As in Honinbou Shuusaku?
I think it was towards the end of Golden
Week. I bumped into him during work.
Oh, did you know that I'm a taxi driver?
And what happened?
Well, it looked like he was going on a trip
so I asked him where he was going.
He said Innoshima, so I went with him.
Since it was where Shuusaku was
born, I was interested, too.
And the kid ran around everywhere.
The Shuusaku memorial at Ishikiri Shrine, Housenji
Temple, Itosaki Hachibanguu, Jikanji Temple...
Even to Honmyouji Temple in Sugamo
when we got back to Tokyo.
Man, I was busy.
And how was Shindou during the trip?
Did he act out of the ordinary?
Let's see... now that I think about
it, he seemed really panicky...
As if he was in a hurry...
It seemed like he was searching for something.
Searching for something?
Shindou.
Why aren't you playing, Shindou?
Shindou
I'm going to make you tell me.
I'm sorry for coming without calling.
He should be home from school soon.
Oh I'll bring you some tea.
Oh, don't worry about it.
There's a lot of dust on it.
He really hasn't been playing... Shindou...
I'm home.
Shindou?
It's... Isumi-san...
Hikaru, why were you in such a hurry?
It wasn't Sai...
I felt that someone was in my
room, so I was hopeful, but...
it wasn't... Sai...
He just got here. I'll bring you some tea, too.
I don't want any.
Thank you very much.
Make yourself at home.
It's been awhile, Shindou.
Isumi-san, you were in China?
Yeah, I was studying there the last two months,
and I just got back a few days ago.
But more imporantly, what's wrong with you?
Waya told me you haven't been going to
any of the matches or study sessions.
Shindou!
Oh man...
Should I run away somewhere?
But I can't leave Isumi-san here,
I haven't seen him in so long.
You said that Touya was your rival.
Did you lose your will to play because you thought
you would never catch up to Touya?
Touya has nothing to do with this.
What do you mean, I don't stand a chance?
You didn't know? He's playing
at an incredible level already.
An incredible level?
Players rising in rank... Touya...
he's 3-dan already!?
And look at the section above that about
this week's matches, under today's date.
Hagiwara 9-dan, Touya 3-dan... Honinbou
match, third preliminaries, final match.
Final match of the third preliminaries!?
Master Kuwabara!
Your match is already over, Master?
Not at all. My opponent, Mano, is taking his
time thinking, so I came for a smoke.
How is Touya's successor doing?
They're fighting everywhere. It's
a difficult game for both of them.
But it would be incredible if Touya-kun were to win.
Third dan at the age of fifteen!
Someone who's been a pro for two years
entering the Honinbou league...
Kurata-kun lost to you, Master,
in this year's Honinbou match.
But when Touya-kun joins in for the competition to
become the Honinbou challenger for next year,
the new wave will finally be here.
But I wonder what's wrong with Shindou-kun.
To think he had the attention of Master Kuwabara,
Master Ogata, and even Master Touya Kouyou.
Don't worry, hardship and
doubt are both necessary.
Amono-san, I'm not worried at all.
So long as that successor of Touya's, who dragged
that brat into the world of the pros,
is struggling hard to reach the top, there's no need to worry.
He will return...
before the opponent that he needs to face.
You speak as if Shindou-kun is
Touya-Kun's destined rival.
You're overestimating him.
I'm not overestimating him.
Touya Akira himself thinks so.
Touya...
He's already gotten this far...
If he wins today,
he'll join a league of eight top pros to compete
for the right to challenge Master Kuwabara.
How strong has he gotten?
It seems like you still love the game,
why don't you play it then?
I... I'm... not interested in this stuff. Besides, what
business of it is yours if I quit playing Go?
Quit playing Go!? Are you serious!?
Shindou.
Let's play a game.
Wait, Isumi-san! I don't want
to play! Leave me alone!
Don't worry about me!
I'm not saying this out of concern for you.
Play me... play me for my sake.
That's what I'm here for today.
I...sumi-san...
Shindou, do you remember? The match between
us during the pro exams last year...
Oh no, I went to Atari from the wrong side!
I... that match last year.
When I resigned for violating the Hagashi rule.
During that long period when I considered my violation.
When I thought about whether I could
pretend that I didn't violate the rule.
It's a bitter memory for me.
Shindou.
That was the last match I played against you.
I want to play a clean game against
you before the pro exams this year.
Shindou! Please!
Let me start again from there!
Isumi-san...
Please! Shindou!
But... I...
If I play Go again... Sai won't...
Ring
My
Bell
noizu darake no mune de
ノイズだらけの胸で
I listen to my fate through the din in my heart.
noizu darake no mune deunmei wo kikiwakeru
ノイズだらけの胸で運命を聴きわける
It occurs to me.
hirameku
閃く
hiramekuyume ha watashi no naka demezame o matteta
閃く夢は私の中で目覚めを待ってた
My dream was waiting for the time
to wake up within me.
mezame o matteta
閃く夢は私の中で目覚めを待ってた
Music
Is
My
Thing
I can be more like myself
jibun rashiku nareru
自分らしくなれる
Music
In
My
Heart
ときめきならして
Let the pounding of my heart be heard
tokimeki narashite
ときめきならして
Music
Is
My
Thing
karada wo ugokasu
体を動かす
I move my body
karada wo ugokasu
体を動かす
Music
In
My
Heart
Feel the light
hikari wo kanjite
光を感じて
Music
Is
My
Thing
shiro to kuro de egaku
白と黒で描く
I draw with black and white
shiro to kuro de egaku
白と黒で描く
Music
In
My
Heart
owaranai haamoni
The unending Harmony
終わらないハーモニー
owaranai haamoni