Fujiwarano Sai, a Go player from the Heian period
has passed through time and returned to
the world in the mind of Shindou Hikaru...
in order to obtain the Hand of God.
君が今僕を支えて
Kimi ga ima boku wo sasaete
Now you are,
holding me up strong!
僕が今君を支える
boku ga ima kimi wo sasaeru
Now I am,
holding you up as well!
だから迷いながらも共に生きていこうよ
Dakara Mayoi nagara mo tomo ni ikite ikou yo
So let us now, while wandering live together
未来へと
Mirai e to...
towards the future
Elite-Fansubs presents
Hikaru no Go
仲間と戯れ　それなりで居ても
Nakama to tawamaure sorenaride itemo
Even when I'm capricing with my friends,
もの足りなさを感じてしまう
mono tari na sa wo kanjite shimau
I feel an emptiness in my heart.
冷めた目で見られて
Sameta me de mirarete
Looked at with cold eyes,
乾いた時代の風に吹かれている
Kawaita jidai no kaze ni fukareteiru
I'm blown by the wind of a dry age
不安な 心と勇気が
Fuan na, kokoro to yuuki ga
Feelings of doubt and courage
背中合わせになっている
senaka awase ni natteiru
are back to back
だけど今なら夢をこの手で叶えてみせるよ
dakedo ima nara yume wo, kono te de kanaete miseru yo
but I'll make these dreams come true now with my own hands.
傷ついて壊れそうな日も
Kizutsuite koware sou na hi mo
The days where I'm hurt and about to break,
涙して困らせる日も
Namidashite komaraseru hi mo
the days where I cry and trouble you
あるけれど僕達はそれを
aru keredo bokura wa sore wo
They all exist, but we will
超えていくんだ誰より
koete ikunda dare yori...
get over it heading higher
上を目指して
ue wo mezashite!
than anyone else!
Registration Form
Name
Hey, all I want? Really?
The name is...
S...
a...
i...
Sai!
Okay let's do it!
The Sixteenth Match
Who is Sai!?
The current temperature is 36.5 degrees...
Experience
the internet here!
State-of-the-art
systems available.
What's wrong?
He suddenly sent me a message in English!
Where?
Let's see... Anata wa tsuyosugiru!
Puro desuka? He said.
Wow that's incredible!
This guy was too weak that's all.
Do you want to reply?
No! No!
Then bring your cursor over here and
click on it. Look at the monitor, not me.
Y-Yeah!
When you don't want to reply, just do that.
Thanks!
Dou itashimashite
It means "You're Welcome".
Foreigners are so much trouble.
How peculiar, why can we play Go with
so many people with a box like this?
Don't ask me!
But...
come on out!
Hey...
Well then...
Let's play a Japanese next.
Be quiet already!
Nick
Given his nick and the way he speaks, I
just thought he might be a child that's all.
Hey jerkoff! Don't quit the game just because
I killed a big cluster of stones! Moron!
That guy! Okay, let's play him!
Yay! Another game!
I get to play more, right? Yay! Yay!
You look happy, Sai.
Well, of course!
I'm so happy!
I'll let you play for awhile, it's
only summer break anyways.
It's Japanese. He might be a child.
A child!?
here...
Hikaru! Please don't click the wrong spot this time!
Last game, half way through, you...
Like I said, I'm not used to computers!
What the...
Who is this!?
How is he Sai?
He's strong... Stronger than anyone else
1-10.
Coming from Sai that's gotta mean a lot...
Resignation.
but look, he just resigned.
He's strong, so he can accurately
and quickly judge the situation.
Knowing my strength, he probably
decided that he couldn't do any more.
The weaker an opponent is,
the lesser his ability to judge,
and they continue a game that they've already lost.
Just like the way Hikaru used to be.
Shut up!
Mitani's sister!
What is it this time?
Can you send "I'm strong,
aren't I?" to the other guy?
Sure, but learn to do it yourself already okay?
There you go.
Arigatou!
The internet's so much fun.
Sai> I'm strong, aren't I?
Zelda> Who are you! I'm an "Insei"!
Who are you... I'm an "Insei"...
Insei?
Hikaru-kun, can you find a place to
stop soon? My shift's almost over.
Oh, I'm done. Thanks much.
So Zelda's an Insei...
He's aimed for the pros...
Japanese Institute of Go
It's time for lunch, so please halt your game.
What's wrong Waya-kun?
What are you thinking about?
Did you make a mistake in the first half?
No, I didn't! Quiet you!
Why am I so agitated? I'm in the
middle of the pro examinations.
Wow! Look at those wrinkles on his forehead.
You're such a moron.
It is a chance that comes along only once a year...
Oh yeah, it concerns me too.
Look, there's one guy that's all calm.
Touya... Akira...?
Yes?
That's...
I knew that Touya Meijin's son
was taking the exam here but...
Not many people know how he looks...
That's it!
You didn't know?
I knew that he was Touya-kun.
Why?
Because he's my opponent
today. I don't stand a chance.
A guy aimed at becoming pro
shouldn't give up so quickly!
B-But!
Are the two of you Insei?
Yup. It's my first exam this year. It's
the third for you Waya-kun, right?
Don't "right?" me!
Oh, I'm totally going to lose today.
A loss on the first match.
But your game isn't over! Just
make a come back against this guy!
Waya-kun you're too irritated.
Did something happen?
When I was playing Go over the internet yesterday,
someone really strong came and beat me.
Given his strength, he's definitely a pro.
And that guy said to me "I'm strong,
aren't I?" How can I not be irritated?
Would a pro really say that?
I'm not talking to you!
Waya-kun, you're being too loud!
Damn, I'm gonna get three wins
and pass out of the try outs.
Don't think about Sai.
Hmm... so this is Sai.
What's your opinion on him as
the American rep from last year?
Subarashii! I'd love to play him once.
But, Sai gets so many challenges
these days, it's hard to get a game.
Well, well, then watching like
this is all we can do, I guess.
Shanghai...
The number of observers are increasing every
day. People are starting to take notice of Sai.
Master, is this person a pro?
Probably not, a pro wouldn't play
amateurs constantly like this.
So he's not a pro...
If he's not a pro... who is he!?
He may be the God of Go.
The only time I played Sai,
he ignored my messages.
No matter who I ask, they were all ignored.
And no one has any information on Sai.
The International Amateur Go Tournament
is coming up... if I go to Japan...
If I go to Japan...
I might find out something about Sai.
Resign
I first saw Sai in the beginning of July.
I've seen him constantly since then...
But it's the middle of the day!
Doesn't this guy have a job!?
if you go everyday you'll...
I'm strong aren't I?
July... August... Summer Vacation!?
Could it be!?
A child!?
Japanese Institute of Go
Recently, the international skill
level of Go has been rising steadily.
And this year, we once again have
more than 50 nations competing!
This is clear proof of how much all of
you enjoy go, and dedicate yourself to it.
I like to believe that one of our goals for the
future, is to continuously explore new possibilities.
Well then, Four days from today,
there'll be 8 matches, at two a day.
Please enjoy them all you can.
Sai... the mysterious player on the internet.
When I first played him last month,
I thought he was incredibly strong.
Since then I've watched his games over and over...
He has... within the past month... changed...
Master, please figure out who Sai is for us!
He's so cool! The ultimate
player who lurks on the nets.
I wish greatly to know about Sai, but there's no rush.
I have to do my best in the tournament first.
The most important goal is to
bring the trophy back to China.
I have to win, no matter what.
I'll worry about Sai after that.
Well then, please Nigiri!
Well then, please begin!
Mr. Morishita, thank you for coming
as head judge for the next four days.
It must be hard running this tournament.
It's not a problem once it begins like this, but
it's very difficult until all the players arrive here.
Every nation has some problem with it.
But I love this tournament the most.
It shows how Go is spreading internationally.
It's worth the effort.
Waya!
Teacher.
Is he your student?
Yes, I called him to come help today.
What kind of a face is that!?
The reason I had you come was to play the
foreign players who have finished their games.
Even you might have a hard time against the
strongest of the International Amateurs, but
the weaker ones still have much to learn.
They came all this way, we should
teach them as much as possible.
He passed the tryouts for this year's Pro
examinations with 3 wins and a loss.
That one loss was against Touya Meijin's son.
Oh! Touya Akira-kun! I heard he
was taking the exam this year.
Hey, don't you dare lose at the real thing.
Teacher!
There's...
There's someone really strong...
Like I said. Touya Jr.
Not that! On the internet!
Internet? Then it's a pro isn't it?
He's not a pro! He's there even during pro matches!
Then he's an amateur. There
are strong amateurs too.
Shimada-san, who's representing
Japan today plays Pros evenly!
He's stronger than that!
How much stronger?
He's stronger than you teacher... I can't say that...
Ah, I don't care anymore.
But really, Amateurs are
getting stronger these days...
Teacher, anyways, can you...
I'll listen to you some other
time. We have work to do today.
Excuse me.
Yes?
I'm Waya, an Insei.
Is there a computer with internet
access that I could borrow?
Sure. Use that laptop over there.
Thank you very much.
Idle Players: 56
Refresh
Observe
He's not there...
Thank you very much for your help.
Oh you can leave it like that.
Okay.
I resign.
Thank you for the game.
Sai...
International Amateur... Japanese representative.
Sai is Japanese... could he be?
No, he's not Sai.
Sai is stronger than that.
But if he's that strong, there may
be other people looking for him.
Maybe there are people on this very
stage who have played Sai, like me.
Sai...
T-This person... he just...
Waya...
Come here for a sec.
O-okay.
He's almost a pro.
B-But I don't have time for this!
What are you talking about?
Just do it. Give him six stones.
He's strong... but it's not him...
He's not Sai...
Sai...
Where are you... Sai?
夢に見ていたシアワセなら
Yume ni miteita shiawase nara
I thought that someone would bring me,
誰かが運んでくれると思ってた
Dareka ga hakonde kureru to omotteta
the happiness that I dreamed of.
急ぎ足の街で
Isogi ashi no machi de
In a quick paced city,
言い訳ばかり
iiwake bakari...
all I'm doing is listing off excuses,
みんなも同じとうそ ぶいてた
Minna mo onaji to usobuiteta
and lying to myself, that everyone was doing the same.
本当にキミはいま　満足してるの？
hontou ni kimi wa ima manzokushiteru no?
Are you really satisfied right now?
心の真ん中 見抜かれたようで
kokoro no mannaka minukaretayoude
It feels as if you've straight through my heart.
あなたと出会えなかったら
Anata to deaenakattara
If i had not met you,
偽った笑顔のまま
Itsuwatta egao no mama!
I would still only have a false smile!
うわべの態度や言葉を
Uwabe no taido ya kotoba wo
My words and disagreements
繰り返したね
kurikaeshita ne
would only have been superficial.
あなたの瞳の力で
anata no hitomi no chikara de
With the power of your gaze,
私は変わってゆこう
watashi wa kawatte yukou
I am starting to change!
昨日の揺らいだ気持ちを
Kinou no yuraida kimochi wo
In order to cast off
脱ぎ捨てるために...
nugisuteru tame ni
the swaying feelings of yesterday.
Umezawa Yukari's
Go Go Igo!
Go! Go! Igo!
Teacher Yukari
Today, we'll talk about how to make it
impossible to get your stones captured.
How to make it impossible
to get your stones captured.
Yuuki
Mai
Out of these three formations. One of the black
formations can't get captured no matter what.
Which shape would prevent black
from getting captured no matter what?
Which one is it?
This.
With this, if white plays here,
they all get taken right?
White plays here.
All of it gets taken.
With this, even if you play
here, and black takes back...
Even if you take back.
It gets captured.
It still gets taken.
Then what about this?
Can you move here?
No you can't.
With this shape...
Can you go here?
You can't.
Even if you're surrounded, you can't get captured.
Okay. That's right.
These shapes are called "eyes"
"eyes"
and if you make two "eyes" you
can't get captured no matter what.
If you make two "eyes" you can't
get captured no matter what.
To be continued...
Seems like there's someone really good on the net.
I thought he was kinda like Shuusaku...
Is he a god...?
He gets stronger every time he plays.
Or a demon?
Maybe Sai's a child?
Sai challenged me to a game!