Fujiwarano Sai, a go player from the Heian period...
has passed through time and returned to
the world in the mind of Shindou Hikaru,
in order to obtain the Hand of God.
Kimi ga ima boku wo sasaete
君が今僕を支えて
Now you are,
holding me up strong!
boku ga ima kimi wo sasaeru
僕が今君を支える
Now I am,
holding you up as well!
Dakara Mayoi nagara mo tomo ni ikite ikou yo
だから迷いながらも共に生きていこうよ
So let us now, while wandering live together
Mirai e to...
未来へと
towards the future
Elite-Fansubs presents
Hikaru no Go
Nakama to tawamaure sorenaride itemo
仲間と戯れ　それなりで居ても
Even when I'm capricing with my friends,
mono tari na sa wo kanjite shimau
もの足りなさを感じてしまう
I feel an emptiness in my heart.
Sameta me de mirarete
冷めた目で見られて
Looked at with cold eyes,
Kawaita jidai no kaze ni fukareteiru
乾いた時代の風に吹かれている
I'm blown by the wind of a dry age
Fuan na, kokoro to yuuki ga
不安な 心と勇気が
Feelings of doubt and courage
senaka awase ni natteiru
背中合わせになっている
are back to back
dakedo ima nara yume wo, kono te de kanaete miseru yo
だけど今なら夢をこの手で叶えてみせるよ
but I'll make these dreams come true now with my own hands.
Kizutsuite koware sou na hi mo
傷ついて壊れそうな日も
The days where I'm hurt and about to break,
Namidashite komaraseru hi mo
涙して困らせる日も
the days where I cry and trouble you
aru keredo bokura wa sore wo
あるけれど僕達はそれを
They all exist, but we will
koete ikunda dare yori...
超えていくんだ誰より
get over it heading higher
ue wo mezashite!
上を目指して
than anyone else!
Did you pass?
Waya, you know him?
Oh, I heard him say "To surpass
Touya Akira" in the hall.
Really! I'm his, and he's my rival!
There's too much of a gap!
I'll catch up eventually!
[note: Yuugen translates roughly into
Spiritual Wonder or Spiritual Mystery]
The Twenty-Third Match
The Room of Yuugen
[note: When you lose you get a black
mark. That is what Waya is referring to]
Oh it's all black!
Touya Akira's rival experiences
six straight losses in a second class.
What is it!? What are you trying to say?
Oh! I see! He's your rival at Shougi!
Don't mind him Hikaru, you're getting stronger.
And what's your rank!?
Me?
Let's see...
Waya... Waya...
6th... in first class...
Waya you're good.
Compared to the bottom of second class I am.
And still lost to Touya twice.
Though I lost to him, I'm a lot
closer to Touya than you are!
Though he probably doesn't even know I exist.
What are you talking about?
Ah! Dammit!
I'm pissed at myself for letting
Touya beat me at the Pro exams.
I can't lose to him in spirit and skill.
I played against Touya-kun too!
I lost!
O-Oh...
Touya doesn't matter.
It's all a matter of making yourself the top.
Who was that?
Ochi, he's in the sixth grade.
He came three months before you.
Of course he started at the
very bottom of second class.
Now?
He's third in first class!
Third... in first class?
He probably thinks he'll pass the pro exams today.
I want to pass them too this year, no matter what!
If I pass this year, I won't
have to go to High School.
You don't like studying Waya?
I hate it!
Ahh! The pain of having to listen to a
teacher for hours and hours everyday.
Same with me.
I'll be in the ninth grade by
the pro exam in the summer.
If I pass it, I'll start as a pro
the same time I graduate!
I'd like to finally pass this year too...
Isumi-san.
I'll turn 18 this year, it's the
last year I can remain an Insei.
But, even if you're not an Insei,
you can take the pro exam until you're 30.
I know all that. It's a matter of feelings.
Last year, and the year before that, I failed the
pro exams despite being ranked one in the Inseis.
If I fail this year too...
I'd feel too sorry for myself to continue.
How many people can pass the pro exams?
Three.
What!?
Just three!?
There's a long way ahead on the path
you're walking, six straight losses.
Long way... ahead...
I didn't think that would work.
I mean, this flow here, that's
not good enough for black.
Then, do you want us going after the 2 moku here?
Yeah yeah, extend yourself here.
Can you really win the battle?
Probably?
Probably!?
What do you think about it Akira-kun?
Akira-kun?
O-Oh!
What is it? Is your mind filled with becoming pro?
No...
I'd like to say "finally". Akira-kun
is finally a pro starting in April.
What I don't understand is why you were fooling
around in the Go club when you joined Jr. High.
Right Ogata-san?
But he had more spirit back then.
Go isn't all about skill.
In between the small difference in
skill, your emotions, your spirit affects
the outcome of the game greatly.
Right now you're...
not even worth pounding.
I don't feel different...
Akira-kun's a scary enough existence for me.
That's because you're losing one out
of every three matches, Ashiwara.
Touya-Meijin probably knows
since he plays him every day.
Well, once the matches begin in
April, the results will show it.
But Ashiwara-kun, how long do you plan on drifting
in between the first and second preliminaries?
Umm... yeah!
Are you free this Sunday?
There's something I'd like to show you.
Something to show me?
Shindou...
You won!?
Yup! My first victory!
Just one win?
I'm just about to start my winning streak now.
Touya...
Touya!
What's with him?
Hey!
Touya!
What's with him?
Did he have some business with the teacher?
No... he came to see if I was here.
What are you talking about?
He completely ignored you.
He's not your rival at all.
He said he'll never appear before me again...
He's waiting for me...
For me to rise to his level!
You didn't know did you?
That he became Insei.
Was he what you wanted to show me?
So what if he is Insei?
What does that have to do with me?
He probably did it in pursuit of Touya Akira.
Oh! Touya-kun you're here?
Hello!
Perfect! Do you mind if I interview you for a bit?
About becoming pro, and about your father?
It's fine with me.
Will you come to the publishing
department upstairs later?
I understand.
Thanks a lot.
Hello, Ogata-sensei.
Well then I'll...
Okay, I'm going home.
I just thought he would motivate you.
Hmph! That's funny. To chase
after me with his skills?
Then, I'll move forward far beyond
him, so that he'll never reach me.
I won't let him come near me!
He's motivated you plenty.
What an interesting existence he is.
So he'll get pummeled here for awhile as Insei....
hurry up and come to the world of the pros...
no...
will he be able to come at all?
What's going on?
Imanishi-kun! Wait!
What is with his attitude? Just over losing?
You were Imanishi's opponent just now right?
Yeah.
Did he make a stupid mistake somewhere?
Yup. A total miscalculation.
Maybe he's irritated because the High
School entrance exams are coming up.
Oh, Arigatou.
He said his grades at school were dropping.
Of course, if I had time, I'd be studying Go.
and if it pays off and we become pro,
it's all fine, but he's still second class.
And he lost to someone like Shindou because
of a stupid mistake, no wonder he's irritated.
Why you...
Hey, Touya doesn't study for school either right?
But he's in Kaiou Jr. High, he must be really smart.
Yeah! Doesn't that irritate you?
It doesn't really irritate me but...
It's irritating! He passed the
pro exams in one shot too!
He'll be appearing in the new first dan series soon.
New first dan series?
You really don't know anything do you?
The new first dan series are matches
between people who just passed the
pro exams, and the top pros.
It's to encourage new pros.
Encouragement huh?
You start as a pro in April, but we
have a match like this before then.
Last Tuesday, there was a match between
Kuwabara-sensei and Mashiba-san!
Mashiba-san?
He was an Insei.
Hmm... so he passed the pro exams.
When Isumi-san and Waya failed.
You be quiet.
How did the match go?
He resigned helplessly before Kuwabara-sensei.
Oh...
Touya should have it soon too.
He keeps on moving forward doesn't he?
It's not just Touya.
Everyone who passed the pro
exams keeps moving forward.
We Insei, don't move forward at
all unless we pass the pro exams.
Who is it?
Down!
Hey who is it?
That was Zama-sensei! Ouza!
Ouza?
That's one of the titles.
You should know the titles at the very least.
Zama-sensei! Perfect timing.
What?
The day for your match against the
new first dan has been decided.
We'll send a notice for it.
Who's my opponent?
It's Touya Akira-san. The Meijin's son.
Oh Touya... him?
I've heard about him.
He's supposedly really strong according to
the players studying under Touya-Meijin.
Of course they won't say anything bad.
The new first dan series...
How have they been going? A
sweep by us experienced pros?
No there are losses as well.
Hmm... so they're letting the
new players feel some glory.
It is a festival of sorts.
Then maybe I'll let him win by half a moku too.
I'm sure everyone will like it.
"Touya Akira makes a great start as
pro," your headlines will read better.
Well the publishers may appreciate it but...
Oh yes, Kuwabara-sensei played
it a few days ago didn't he?
Yes. His opponent was Mashiba-kun,
and he used to be Insei.
I'd like this please.
Maybe he got nervous because
he was playing Kuwabara-sensei,
or maybe he went out of it because of the
room of Yuugen, but he defeated himself.
Kuwabara-sensei went "Huh?" when Mashiba-kun
resigned, as if he played the game half asleep.
I feel sorry for that boy.
Kuwabara-sensei can be quite a bully at times.
Well, I'm hoping for a great game between a
hopeful new pro, and one of the top pros right now.
What!? Today!?
Did you read the sign outside?
There's a match between Touya and the Ouza
today in the room of Yuugen in the afternoon.
I wanna see!
You can.
There's a camera in the room
of Yuugen during matches,
and you can watch it on a monitor.
It'll be shown on that TV.
We have our own matches,
so we can't watch all of it.
But you can catch at least the second
half after your Insei matches are over.
Oh... I can't watch all of it.
While we're here, wanna look
at the room of Yuugen as well?
What!? We're allowed?
Here, this is the room of Yuugen.
It's so dark, I can't see anything.
Hikaru...
Sai...?
Maybe I feel it because of the state I'm in...
but the air here stings me.
Enough to make me smile
from quivering in anticipation.
How is it? Isn't it awesome?
Do the pros always play in places like this?
No. They usually play in the
main room where we play.
Rooms like these are used only for title matches.
Oh.
Using this room today, is kind of like
encouraging them to work hard so
that they can play a real game in here.
Next year, I too will...
We'll be taking a memorial
picture before the match.
Take some extras. He may
become big in the future.
Gotcha.
Could you face each other and converse a little?
Converse he said Touya-kun.
I'll be fighting you with all my
strength today. My regards to you.
Oh, you have my regards as well.
Don't be scared by my title of Ouza.
We're all the same once we're pro.
You can't win if you lose emotionally.
Come at me thinking that
I'm a new pro just like you.
Yes. I intend to do so.
He intends to do so? How arrogant of him.
Could you look this way please?
Change of plans...
I'll crush him.
Has Touya's match started yet?
Hikaru, concentrate on the
match before you for now!
I-I know!
This isn't the first time you've been in
the room of Yuugen right Touya-kun?
No, it's my first time.
It may be your first time playing, but
you've been in here before at least right?
Your father is a regular here.
Have you never come with him?
No, not even once.
You've never even sat here to
keep time or record the moves?
I was not an Insei, so I've
never kept time or records.
What? You were never an Insei?
Oh! But jobs like that come to new pros too right?
I'd better learn how to do it by April.
Heh! How annoying, feel at least a little nervous.
It's time, so we'll begin the match.
The new pro will move first, and
komi is a reverse-komi, 5.5 moku.
You each have 2 hours.
After you use it, you have a
minute per move on the byouyomi.
Well then. Good luck.
Good luck.
What? Ashiwara-sensei!
Hello.
Oh yes! Ashiwara-sensei
studies under Touya-Meijin!
I'm Touya-kun's friend. The closest to him in
age too. All of Touya-kun's friends are adults.
Is that why?
He's really calm. Every new pro I've seen
so far have been nervous or not confident,
but he's neither.
Oh yes, Mashiba-kun, you were frozen stiff.
Kuwabara-sensei was really scary.
Kuwabara-sensei slammed the stone onto
the board really load on his first move.
Hehe, you can't be getting swallowed
up by such obvious scare tactics.
Kuwabara-sensei's just the type of person to do it.
Well, let's see what happens with today's match.
Yume ni miteita shiawase nara
夢に見ていたシアワセなら
I thought that someone would bring me,
Dareka ga hakonde kureru to omotteta
誰かが運んでくれると思ってた
the happiness that I dreamed of.
Isogi ashi no machi de
急ぎ足の街で
In a quick paced city,
iiwake bakari...
言い訳ばかり
all I'm doing is listing off excuses,
Minna mo onaji to usobuiteta
みんなも同じとうそ ぶいてた
and lying to myself, that everyone was doing the same.
hontou ni kimi wa ima manzokushiteru no?
本当にキミはいま　満足してるの？
Are you really satisfied right now?
kokoro no mannaka minukaretayoude
心の真ん中 見抜かれたようで
It feels as if you've straight through my heart.
Anata to deaenakattara
あなたと出会えなかったら
If i had not met you,
Itsuwatta egao no mama!
偽った笑顔のまま
I would still only have a false smile!
Uwabe no taido ya kotoba wo
うわべの態度や言葉を
My words and disagreements
kurikaeshita ne
繰り返したね
would only have been superficial.
anata no hitomi no chikara de
あなたの瞳の力で
With the power of your gaze,
watashi wa kawatte yukou
私は変わってゆこう
I am starting to change!
Kinou no yuraida kimochi wo
昨日の揺らいだ気持ちを
In order to cast off
nugisuteru tame ni
脱ぎ捨てるために...
the swaying feelings of yesterday.
Umezawa Yukari's Go Go Igo!
Teacher Yukari
Yuuki
Mai
Mai might be in danger...
Oh! They were captured!!
Wow, Yuuki-kun, you took a lot.
That was harsh.
It's called Shichou when your stones
get captured in this stair like shape.
Shichou.
A method where you chase your opponent down
with Atari after Atari, and then finally capture them.
You go to Atari from where they escape,
and go to Atari from where they escape.
If you continue this, black can't escape.
If you think a Shichou is going to
happen, it's important to give up!!
If you get caught in Shichou, give
up as quickly as possible and look
for another good place to move.
To be continued...
Touya, you're... telling me to come here right?
Not yet... I won't end it like this.
Touya won't let it end here, with the
way he's been playing up to now!
I'll show you...
Each of my moves!