Fujiwarano Sai, a Go player from the Heian period
has passed through time and returned to
the world in the mind of Shindou Hikaru...
in order to obtain the Hand of God.
君が今僕を支えて
Kimi ga ima boku wo sasaete
Now you are,
holding me up strong!
僕が今君を支える
boku ga ima kimi wo sasaeru
Now I am,
holding you up as well!
だから迷いながらも共に生きていこうよ
Dakara Mayoi nagara mo tomo ni ikite ikou yo
So let us now, while wandering live together
未来へと
Mirai e to...
towards the future
Elite-Fansubs presents
Hikaru no Go
仲間と戯れ　それなりで居ても
Nakama to tawamaure sorenaride itemo
Even when I'm capricing with my friends,
もの足りなさを感じてしまう
mono tari na sa wo kanjite shimau
I feel an emptiness in my heart.
冷めた目で見られて
Sameta me de mirarete
Looked at with cold eyes,
乾いた時代の風に吹かれている
Kawaita jidai no kaze ni fukareteiru
I'm blown by the wind of a dry age
不安な 心と勇気が
Fuan na, kokoro to yuuki ga
Feelings of doubt and courage
背中合わせになっている
senaka awase ni natteiru
are back to back
だけど今なら夢をこの手で叶えてみせるよ
dakedo ima nara yume wo, kono te de kanaete miseru yo
but I'll make these dreams come true now with my own hands.
傷ついて壊れそうな日も
Kizutsuite koware sou na hi mo
The days where I'm hurt and about to break,
涙して困らせる日も
Namidashite komaraseru hi mo
the days where I cry and trouble you
あるけれど僕達はそれを
aru keredo bokura wa sore wo
They all exist, but we will
超えていくんだ誰より
koete ikunda dare yori...
get over it heading higher
上を目指して
ue wo mezashite!
than anyone else!
Oh, the Insei exams are going on today?
Who's taking it right now?
A guy, probably a little younger than me.
He'll...
probably pass.
Good luck
The Twenty-Second Match
The Insei Examination
Hikaru...
That was...
He won't respond to that expansion. The Tsuke
you played earlier was a mistake as well.
The three stone advantage Hikaru
started with has already been spent.
Hikaru is aware of that as well.
That's why his game is getting
rushed and he's making mistakes.
Against someone as strong as this person... he's...
Hikaru! You will lose at this rate.
Hikaru! If you wish, once again I will... Hikaru!
Hikaru?
He can't hear me.
It's too bad that he doesn't have the
strength to go along with his concentration.
I... I can't do it. I can't win.
If I go in too far, he'll crush me.
But the gap will just keep on widening like this...
Touya...
Touya!
Hey! Hey!
Don't get so nervous.
You don't have to win to pass. I'm
just seeing how strong you are.
Oh!
Couldn't you have said so earlier mister?
M-Mister!?
Hikaru, mister is a little too rude.
T-Teacher.
What is with that posture!?
I-I'm sorry!
M-My legs are asleep... I can't hang on....
Just say "excuse me" and
break your form in that case~
Couldn't you have said that earlier as well?
Oh, you look like you lost.
This is my third straight loss to Fuku.
I'm strong against Waya-kun.
I'm terrible against Fuku.
It's not good to think so negatively.
You're terrible against Touya-kun too, Waya-kun!
No one's good against Touya.
Hmm... let's stop here.
O-Okay.
You should have simply pulled back
here, that would've troubled white.
This formation is, a little difficult for black.
And? What is it? Did I pass? Or...
He's a little too weak, but it says here
he's only been playing for a year.
That's some incredible growth,
reminiscent of Kurata 5dan.
But, even Kurata-kun, who had a lot of talent,
got a pro teacher right after he started playing.
He doesn't even have that. If he became
this strong just from playing in a Jr. High
club, he may have incredible potential.
Is it true that you don't have a teacher?
Umm... ahh... no...
Well, I kinda do... a totally useless one.
What! A totally what one, Hikaru!?
But these three matches are...
you didn't read very deeply,
and your play is very careless.
Oh? They're all from the same day?
I played it simultaneously.
It was the first time I played three
games simultaneously, it was horrible!
Th...
Three games!? And it was his first time!?
He played this well on his first try!?
Okay. Come here starting next
month. Go get your mother.
Yeah! Yay!
Hikaru!
This is the central room. Looks
like most of the matches are over.
What about a furikawari here?
That might work.
Mark me down too.
This is your fourth straight win, Matsura!
Oh, there are kids younger than
Hikaru. No wonder he passed.
There's a pairings sheet over there.
Okay, okay.
Oh! Hikaru! Let's look over there.
What?
What would you do if he played here?
This is bad for black.
What about a tsuke?
I'll just pull back.
That might be too soft...
Did you pass?
Yeah...
You came to take the Insei exam?
Waya do you know him?
Oh, I heard him say "To surpass
Touya Akira" in the hall.
I used to say that too when I first joined.
You got a problem with that?
I played Touya twice during the
pro exam, but I don't like him.
You played Touya?
What about you? Have you played him before?
Yeah, during a team match for my Go club.
He was in the Kaiou Jr. High's Go club and...
Go club? Touya!? Really?
I remember hearing Mr. Kuwabara laugh
about it with Mr. Nishio a while ago.
About how the Meijin's son was participating
in a tournament with his Jr. High's Go club.
Oh so it's for real?
What? What are you talking about?
What an incredible first board
match for a Go club match.
Between a soon-to-be Insei and Touya Akira.
Nope. It was a third board match.
Third board!?
I wasn't strong enough to
play first board back then.
That may have been the case with you,
but Touya? Third board? Impossible.
He forced the teacher to make him third
board because he wanted to play against me.
Forced?
Like I said, that's the kind of guy he is.
The reason he joined the Go club
was just to play against me...
Hikaru!
Hikaru, let's go home.
He'll start coming here starting
next month. Nice to meet all of you.
Oh crap...
Touya Akira's what!?
Rival.
Rival?
Morning, what are you talking about?
Oh yeah, the guy coming today,
he might be really strong.
Touya Akira supposedly went to a
Go club tournament pursuing him.
And he...
M-Morning.
Mo...rning.
Sai? Isn't everyone glaring at me?
They probably think a horribly
strong enemy's arrived.
It's all because you talked about Touya, Hikaru.
But...
Did you hear? The guy coming today.
Yeah! I heard my parents talking about it.
Touya Akira views him as a rival!
He's in the seventh grade.
I'm playing him for my first match today.
He's probably really strong...
Tsk... they were talking about me.
Umm... who's Uchida?
That's me.
We're playing here.
A girl!?
I got a pairings chart, but it only has last names.
She's fifth in the second class. I'm
25th. I'm starting at the very bottom.
Is this room just for the second class?
Are there first class people here too?
They're all here. That half is the first class.
You can rise up to first class
if you're strong enough?
Yeah.
So second class isn't good enough for you.
I-I don't feel that way at all!
It's not that second class isn't good enough for me...
But Touya is above first class,
which is above second class.
I passed the Insei exam! I'm not
like I was in the Go club anymore!
I resign.
Thanks for the game.
Ahh! I totally read that part wrong!
I'm such an idiot!
Oh yeah, I wonder if his game is wrong.
You can't get any eyes with this shape.
In this situation, if you cut them...
you can target this area better.
This made black lose.
Looks like he lost.
How'd it go?
Uchida won
The Second Match
I resign.
And he's Touya's...
Rival?
Moving into here, I think that
was a little unreasonable.
Really?
Yeah, this happened, right?
Even if you moved here...
Yeah, you'd get crushed.
It would be bad even if it went like this.
There's nothing you can do.
Two straight losses...
Nothing to fear from here it seems.
Maybe he's just nervous since it's his first day?
Then wanna watch over him a little longer?
Waya, wanna go get lunch?
What are you doing for lunch?
I'm buying it too.
[note: Loae's Japanese 101
Obento = Lunch Box
Onigiri = Rice ball
Keep learning, and you too can be as l33t as Loae]
Obento Onigiri
Thank you. Come again.
What's your relationship with Touya?
Were you his classmate in elementary school?
You said you played him in a match
in a go tournament for your club.
But why a school tournament?
Touya pursue you? That's strange.
You're not strong at all. Are you really rivals?
Really! I'm his, and he's my rival!
There's too much of a gap!
I'll catch up eventually!
What's the reason for Touya
thinking of you as a rival?
He saw my incredible potential at Go,
and that's why he views me as a rival!
Your potential at Go?
Hikaru, that was cool.
But... that's a lie.
That doesn't matter, I'll make it come true.
What? Something else you want to ask?
How was the match against Kaiou?
3-0 loss.
Touya is special, but everyone
else in Kaiou is also strong.
I heard Kaiou's Go club is strong, but wow.
Kaiou's president's really strong.
I tried playing against him in a Go
Salon another day, but I totally lost.
That's not because he's strong,
that's because you suck.
Waaahhh! I hit the wrong button!
Isumi-san! A coffee came
out! You drink it Isumi-san!
Hey!
Drink it? But it's black!
I am the oldest... but Black is...
Waya...
Don't want it.
I guess I'll give it to the teacher.
Oh! Black coffee, that reminds me.
Remember that guy that used to drink
Black Coffee? In the seventh grade!
Oh yeah! He used to come
here. What was his name?
What's a "Black Coffee" Hikaru?
It's really bitter.
What kind of a guy would drink Black Coffee
in the seventh grade? Was he good at go?
Not at all! He was here for a year, and then quit.
Was he always second class?
Nope. He rose up to first class
once. I remember playing him.
Oh yeah, I played him too. He wasn't any good.
I beat him too.
You've both been in the first class since back then?
Being in first class for a long
time isn't something to be proud of.
When are we finally going to
pass the pro exam, Waya?
I wonder what that guy that got
pummeled in first class is doing now.
He was really smart!
Oh yeah, he went to Kaiou Jr.
High. What was his name?
He was tall and wore glasses...
He should be in the ninth grade right now...
Now I remember! It's Kishimoto! Kishimoto!
Back then it was...
He didn't look like a Jr. High student.
Yeah, yeah, and
And those glasses...
He's no good.
It was total domination.
Really?
But he doesn't look like a Jr. High student.
Well, let's get going.
Yeah! Yeah!
Oh yeah, that strong first board from Kaiou
you were talking about. What's his name?
Hey!
Kaiou's first board was... Kishimoto
was... always second class...
I... I... will I ever be able to make it to first class?
夢に見ていたシアワセなら
Yume ni miteita shiawase nara
I thought that someone would bring me,
誰かが運んでくれると思ってた
Dareka ga hakonde kureru to omotteta
the happiness that I dreamed of.
急ぎ足の街で
Isogi ashi no machi de
In a quick paced city,
言い訳ばかり
iiwake bakari...
all I'm doing is listing off excuses,
みんなも同じとうそ ぶいてた
Minna mo onaji to usobuiteta
and lying to myself, that everyone was doing the same.
本当にキミはいま　満足してるの？
hontou ni kimi wa ima manzokushiteru no?
Are you really satisfied right now?
心の真ん中 見抜かれたようで
kokoro no mannaka minukaretayoude
It feels as if you've straight through my heart.
あなたと出会えなかったら
Anata to deaenakattara
If i had not met you,
偽った笑顔のまま
Itsuwatta egao no mama!
I would still only have a false smile!
うわべの態度や言葉を
Uwabe no taido ya kotoba wo
My words and disagreements
繰り返したね
kurikaeshita ne
would only have been superficial.
あなたの瞳の力で
anata no hitomi no chikara de
With the power of your gaze,
私は変わってゆこう
watashi wa kawatte yukou
I am starting to change!
昨日の揺らいだ気持ちを
Kinou no yuraida kimochi wo
In order to cast off
脱ぎ捨てるために...
nugisuteru tame ni
the swaying feelings of yesterday.
Umezawa Yukari's Go Go Igo!
Sagamihara South Kamimizo
Private Jr. High School
Mai
Teacher  Yukari
We're at South Kamimizo Private Jr.
High school in Sagamihara city today.
Teacher Yukari immediately
started playing five games at once.
Kanagawa Prefecture Sagamihara city South Kamimizo Jr. High School Go-Shougi club. Formed in 1998. 15 members. Record for 2001: 7th in the prefecture - East Japan Tournament, 9th in the upper class - Prefecture Rookie Tournament second place.
I also played someone on a 9x9 board.
Have I gotten stronger than before?
Don't let your stones get cut apart.
The teacher gave them some
advice after the games.
Which one to take is up to you but,
Most of the kids here have been playing
go for less than a year. But they're really
strong and they surprised me.
A second or third Hikaru may
not be out of the question.
Please enjoy Go in the future as well.
Thank you
Thanks to everyone in
the South Kainan Jr.
High Go-Shougi club.
To be continued
He came to see if I was here.
He said he'd never appear before
me again... he's waiting for me.
Pursue me with his skills?
That's funny.
I'll go far beyond him then,
where he can't possibly reach me.