kono me kimi no me ni
この瞳君の瞳に
On this eye, this eye on yours,
utsuru donna mono mo
映るどんなモノも
everything will appear,
mikiwamete miseru yo shinjitsu wo
見極めて見せるよ 真実を
I will tell apart the truth.
------- -------- -- -- --- - --- --- ---- ---- ---
Real-Fansubbers
Presents
----- ----- ---- --- -- --
----- ---- ---- --- - - --
Hikaru
Hikaru no Go
bokutachi wa kono jidai ni
僕達はこの時代に
We had so many dreams
dore dake no yume kakaete
どれだけの夢抱えて
In this time we live in.
namida shite mayoi nagara
涙して迷いながら
We stare at it and run towards it,
sore ni kakete miteru no
それに賭けてみてるの
even as we wander about crying.
boku wa sore demo hito ni hiketoranu you na
僕は それでも 人にひけとらぬような
Even then, I will find a deciding move.
kimete mitsuke yume wo te ni suru darou
決め手見つけ夢を手にするだろう
just as good as anyone else's, and take hold of my dreams.
kono me kimi no me ni
この瞳君の瞳に
On this eye, this eye on yours,
utsuru donna mono mo
映るどんなモノも
everything will appear.
mikiwamete miseru yo shinjitsu dake
見極めて見せるよ 真実だけ
I'll tell apart, just the truth.
tatoe genjitsu ga
たとえ現実が
Even if the truth is
kitsuku umoresou demo
きつく埋もれそうでも
so harsh it's suffocating.
konna basho de owaru
こんな場所で終わる
I'm not going to end
boku janai
僕じゃない
in a place like this.
Hikaru will...
start walking the path to the divine move.
It won't be me...
but Hikaru.
Is there no way that I can escape this fate...
that God has in store for me?
The Sixtieth Match
Farewell Hikaru
Huh?
Is it just me?
It looks like the stain has faded
since the last time I was here.
Just as I thought...
There is no way for me to escape fate...
I guess it was always like that.
I guess it was just me.
Say, Hikaru.
What?
Are you free tomorrow?
Grandma and I are going to see a play.
Why don't you come with us?
A play!?
I-I have an overnight job tomorrow.
Two days and one night at a hotel.
I think there are supposed to
be around 150 customers.
I'm going to play tutoring games and stuff there.
Wow, you?
It's not just me.
A few other pros are going to be there, too.
Say, you came all this way,
you'll want to play, right?
Grandpa, I'll give you a thousand
yen if you beat me.
Why, you little brat.
Hikaru!
Let's go home... and play a game.
You can play Grandpa any time!
What are you talking about?
We can play any time we want.
I hardly ever see Grandpa, I
should play him when I do.
Let's go, Sai!
Hikaru, I...
Hikaru!
I'm going to disappear soon!
You and your stupid worries again?
That's ridiculous. You've been here for a
millennium already, how can you disappear?
You'd better not be trying to make me feel sorry
for you so that you can have your way.
You've been acting really selfish lately.
Why don't you just watch me play Grandpa?
What are you waiting for, Sai!?
Hikaru can...
WELCOME
Japanese
Go Institute
GO SEMINAR
Participants
Japanese
Go Institute
GO SEMINAR
Registration
Good morning!
Oh, Shindou-kun!
Here's the schedule.
Your room is 303, you're with
Nagai-kun and Yokoi-kun.
Master Ogata is here, too!?
I should stay away from him.
I wouldn't want him giving me trouble about Sai.
Japanese Go Institute GO SEMINAR
Master Ogata is a solid player
who plays all kinds of styles,
but his opponent Haruko-san is a forceful player.
What? Master Ogata played here?
In my opinion, this is a rather questionable move.
But who knows what Master Ogata
will say to me later if I deride it.
Ashiwara!
See?
Shindou Hikaru first dan
So, this Sagari isn't too useful right now, but...
you have other plans with it.
You can escape if you really want to,
but that's not enough.
Oh! I see.
Shindou!
You're still playing Go?
It's getting pretty late.
Ah! M-Master Ogata!
Hey, you don't have to be so scared.
Were you out drinking with Master Ogata?
Yup, on me.
We celebrated his Jyudan title.
Wow, he looks drunk.
Hey, Shindou!
Let me play Sai!
M-Master Ogata! I told you already!
I don't know Sai.
Hikaru.
Let's play.
Stop being selfish!
It will be alright if he's this drunk.
It won't amount to anything.
Drunk?
Oh yeah. It doesn't look like he'd
be able to play very well.
But are you alright with that?
I probably won't have any opportunities
to play a real game against him.
No matter what kind of a game it is,
I will be if it will let me respond to the
determination he showed at the hospital.
Let me play him, too!
Yeah. You're right.
I'll let him play you for a bit to congratulate
him on his Jyudan title.
Hey, Shindou.
Let me...
Master Ogata!
Play me, right now.
Right now?
There's no point in playing
him when he's this drunk.
Well, I guess I'll settle for you.
Will he really be able to play Go when he's this drunk?
Maybe he'll sober up a bit after playing you.
Why do you look so down?
Respond to me at least!
I'll let you play today for Master Ogata's sake,
but you've been really disagreeable lately.
Why?
Why is it not me, but Hikaru?
God...
Why is Hikaru...
Why is it only Hikaru...
I'm going to disappear! But Hikaru is going to...
I can't contain my jealousy towards
Hikaru for having an existence.
That's not it...
I don't...
want to leave Hikaru.
I didn't want to leave Torajirou either.
Torajirou...
said to me, while on the brink
of death from the plague...
'Sorry... Sai...'
I didn't want to leave him.
I didn't...
want to leave him...
I'm sorry, Hikaru...
I'll be going soon.
You were sleeping?
Sorry for turning the lights on.
I don't really care.
We can play without the lights on by the window.
Sit down.
You're drinking more?
I'm drunk either way, it won't matter.
Sorry, but I may not be able to play very well.
So it won't be strange at all if I crush you.
Hey, you can't challenge me when I'm this drunk.
Challenge me in an official match.
I have high expectations of you.
The day of your new first dan series match...
Master Kuwabara and I made a
bet that day on who would win.
I bet on Master Touya because
Master Kuwabara bet on you.
But the truth is I wanted to bet on you, too.
Like I can trust what a drunk tells me.
You little punk.
You're right, I am drunk for a change today.
Seems like I'm finally starting to feel the
joy of at last having become Jyudan.
We did have quite a ruckus with
Master Touya's retirement...
I did become Jyudan...
but the world won't recognize me,
until I successfully defend the title next year.
Just you wait, I'm going to
run all the way to the top.
Well Shindou, like I said earlier.
Let me play Sai!
Settle for playing me.
Alright, I guess.
Sixteen... you're going first.
Good luck.
I win.
This is over.
W-Wait!
You messed up on an easy life or death problem.
Master Ogata, you must be really drunk.
Forget about my mistake...
More importantly...
You played in such a strange
place on the top right...
and threatened a large cluster of my stones...
But...
I ended up playing poorly,
and my game fell apart.
I guess you had a little too much to drink.
I guess letting him play Sai didn't pay off...
But then again, it would have been troublesome
if he had realized that Sai was playing.
Well, I guess there's little chance of
that happening if he's this drunk.
Good night.
But...
I feel kind of sorry for him.
Such solid play...
Yes...
It was as if...
I was playing Sai...
Ridiculous!
I must be really drunk.
I guess he was somewhat satisfied.
I'll go home first thing tomorrow,
so that I won't see him again.
Sai?
In the actual game, White played here
to destroy Black's eye shape,
but first White should have connected
to the center like this,
and waited for Black to play here...
Oh! Good morning Master Ogata.
Have you seen Shindou?
He went home first thing this morning.
He said he doesn't have any more work to do here.
I slept a little on the bullet train, but I'm still tired.
I'm exhausted.
Hikaru, let's play a game.
But I'm about to collapse.
Man, I wish you'd worry about my health a little.
I'm going to sleep after one game, okay?
Sit down.
Come on.
A hundred forty years ago...
Torajirou lent his body to me.
If Torajirou existed for my sake...
then I existed for Hikaru's sake.
Then...
Hikaru exists for someone else as well.
And that someone will, too...
be there for another person.
A millennium becomes two,
built up slowly person by person.
The long path leading to the divine move...
My part in it...
is over...
Oh! Yes...
Hikaru...
Hikaru?
Hey, Hikaru?
Huh?
Can you hear my voice?
Hikaru...
It was fu...
Hey!
It's your turn.
I said it's your turn.
Sai!
Sai?
tsurai omoide toka ikutsu atta no kana?
つらい想い出とかいくつあったのかな？
How many sad memories did we have?
donna tanoshii hi wo
どんな楽しい日を
What kind of happy days are we going to
kore kara wa taisetsu ni shite iku no kana?
これからは大切にしていくのかな？
hold onto preciously from now on?
chikaku no kouen de atsumatta ne itsumo
近くの公園で集まったねいつも
We always gathered at the nearby park
yonaka made ookina koe dashite waratteta ne
夜中まで大きな声出して笑ってたね
and laughed out loud into the middle of the night,
zutto... zutto...
ずっとずっと
always... always...
onaji toki wo ima ikiteru kiseki ga
同じ時代を今生きてる奇跡が
Because I'm really happy for the miracle
sugoku ureshii kara ne
すごくうれしいからね
of being here when you are
tsugi au hi mo kitto nee
次あう日もきっとねぇ
Let's laugh together again
issho ni waratte iyou yo
一緒に笑っていようよ
the next time we meet
kondo wa donna yume wo
今度はどんな夢を
what kind of dreams
issho ni katariau no kana?
一緒に語りあうのかな？
are we going to talk about then?
Teacher Yukari
Mai
Today we have a problem based on a situation
you might see quite often in your games.
Black has a really good move
when White moves here.
Black has an opportunity when White plays there!
Can you take advantage of it?
Mai-chan, what would you do?
Here!
It's Atari, so I'll capture it.
That's Atari, so I'll connect.
Here.
Yup! That's right!
Yay! Mai is absolutely right!
Now these four White stones can't get away.
You were able to hurt White's territory a lot.
But had you connected here...
If you respond wrong...
White would have responded here, and his
territory would have been very large.
The correct move for White would have
been to move here at this point.
White should have played here!
Let's make sure not to miss opportunities like this.
Don't miss opportunities like this, respond correctly.
To be continued...
Sai!?
Are you there? Sai?
He wasn't in the shed where we met...
So I guess it's not a place where
he has memories with me...
I'll find him no matter what!
I can't just let him disappear all of a sudden!
I won't let it happen, Sai!