Fujiwarano Sai, a Go player from the Heian period...
has passed through time and returned to
this world in the mind of Shindou Hikaru,
in order to obtain the Hand of God.
君が今僕を支えて
Kimi ga ima boku wo sasaete
Now you are,
holding me up strong!
僕が今君を支える
boku ga ima kimi wo sasaeru
Now I am,
holding you up as well!
だから迷いながらも共に生きていこうよ
Dakara Mayoi nagara mo tomo ni ikite ikou yo
So let us now, while wandering live together
未来へと
Mirai e to...
towards the future
Elite-Fansubs presents
Hikaru no Go
仲間と戯れ　それなりで居ても
Nakama to tawamaure sorenaride itemo
Even when I'm capricing with my friends,
もの足りなさを感じてしまう
mono tari na sa wo kanjite shimau
I feel an emptiness in my heart.
冷めた目で見られて
Sameta me de mirarete
Looked at with cold eyes,
乾いた時代の風に吹かれている
Kawaita jidai no kaze ni fukareteiru
I'm blown by the wind of a dry age
不安な 心と勇気が
Fuan na, kokoro to yuuki ga
Feelings of doubt and courage
背中合わせになっている
senaka awase ni natteiru
are back to back
だけど今なら夢をこの手で叶えてみせるよ
dakedo ima nara yume wo, kono te de kanaete miseru yo
but I'll make these dreams come true now with my own hands.
傷ついて壊れそうな日も
Kizutsuite koware sou na hi mo
The days where I'm hurt and about to break,
涙して困らせる日も
Namidashite komaraseru hi mo
the days where I cry and trouble you
あるけれど僕達はそれを
aru keredo bokura wa sore wo
They all exist, but we will
超えていくんだ誰より
koete ikunda dare yori...
get over it heading higher
上を目指して
ue wo mezashite!
than anyone else!
Shindou Hikaru...
The Third Match
Akira Bears his fangs
Touya...
Hey Touya...
What's going on?
Umm...
You didn't go to the Go tournament?
What about you?
Me?
All I did was take a quick look at it.
But...
It was the first time that I've
seen something like that.
There were kids younger than me...
and they were all so serious about the game.
It kinda touched me.
Touched you?
Haven't you ever been serious before?
Huh?
Serious?
May I see your hands?
My hands?
His nails aren't worn down...
this can't be a hand that's in
contact with Go stones very often...
What was that about?!
Oh sorry.
Do you plan on becoming a pro?
Pro?
Me? Pro?
I've never even thought about anything like that.
Touya do you intend on becoming a pro?
I will.
Huh?
Oh, so you are aiming to become a pro...
how much money does a pro at Go make?
If you enter a title match...
then the Meijin match is $360,000...
and the Kisei match is $420,000.
Wait...
How many title matches are there?!
How much can you get if you win all of them?!
8 titles in all...
the total prize value is around $1.8 million.
A...A million?!
Hey Sai, with your skills you can win
a Meijin match or two easily right?!
How can you think about playing Go for money?!
It'll only be for a bit!
A little bit?
Oh!
I was thinking it might be good to become
a pro for a little bit, and take a title or two.
Become a pro for a bit...
and take a... title or two...
FUCK OFF!
Those words you just said are
an insult to pros everywhere!
You can't possibly be a Go Player,
someone who plays Go can't possibly
say something that insulting!
Become a pro for a bit?!
Do you have any idea how much effort is involved?!
Endurance, exertion, privation, mortification!
There are those who surpassed despair
and still failed to reach their goal!
I observed many people like that
at my father's side, and you!...
I've exerted myself, preparing to face all of that...
Since I was little...
every day, every passing day,
for hours and hours I played Go.
No matter how bitter it got at times, I kept playing.
Why did I lose to someone like this?!...
Do you want to play a match now?
Huh?
I will become a pro.
Someday I will.
If you think you can become a pro
and take a title or two effortlessly,
then you can't afford to lose to me here and now.
Let's play a match now!
Sai, what should I do?
Fine.
If I'm going to obtain the Hand of God...
I can't afford to lose this game.
Hikaru is not a beginner...
I have to play him with all of my strength...
it's just he uses some old joseki at times...
Joseki - set pattern of moves that
lead to equal benefit for both players.
kosumi is one of them...
Kosumi is a standard response to a
keima attack, prevalent 200 years ago.
that move was only considered good
because of the lack of komi at the time.
Unlike with Chess, with go, black makes the first move. Since
black is considered to have an advantage because of this,
5.5 moku is taken away from Black's final score, this 5.5 moku
is called komi. A moku is one intersection on the board.
That's it!
That's were my chance to break him lies!
Man, this guy doesn't know how to take a joke...
Joke?!
That was not a joke?!
Ahh! Why can't anyone take a joke or two!
After all, you only won the last match by 2 moku!
If you're only that much stronger
than a grade schooler, there's no
way you can get a title or two easily.
Hikaru...
I wasn't trying on the last game.
That was Tutoring Go.
Tutoring Go?
The purpose of Tutoring Go is to
lead the pupil in the right direction.
The teacher should not make any
insane moves for the sake of winning.
Oh, so I guess you're stronger than him at least.
But he's just a grade schooler like me,
I guess it makes sense that you're stronger than him.
He's not just a grade schooler.
Although still soft, he makes brilliant moves.
Each of his moves revelate me...
once he grows up, he will become
a dragon, or perhaps a lion.
And now... he's bearing his fangs upon me.
I'll be using an open spot in the back.
Akira-kun!
And you...
Hey again.
That boy!
That's the boy from last time!
The one that beat Akira-kun.
Wha? Wait a sec?
Huh?
Sit
Man, he seems to be used to
having this many people watch.
You're fine with an even match right?
Even match... you mean the
one where white gets komi?
I will nigiri.
[Note: Nigiri - The process of choosing who will play as
black. Please refer to episode 2 for more information]
I got it right! It's even! I'm black.
Komi is at 5 and a half moku.
O-Okay...
Good luck.
Good luck to you too...
Sai...
17-4 Upper Right Corner -komoku.
17-4...
I wonder what I should do...
this boy with his bright eyes and brighter future...
yet he's bearing his fangs upon me now...
should I dodge his fangs, and
give him a pat on the head?
or...
He's used 3 minutes on his first move already...
Star? ...
16-17
16-17...
Star again?
Unthinkable in the age of Shuusaku.
There must have been a great deal of
new developments in the last 140 years...
but...
5 and a half moku...
it's not a problem against him...
but against someone of equal strength,
it can be rather burdensome...
I must make each of my moves count more...
15-3
the search for the best move...
what gratification.
What's up with this guy? Is he mad?
The next move...
perhaps kosumi is a little weak here
and a Hasami would be better...
[Note: Hasami - attacking a stone from 2 sides.]
He's waiting for me to Kosumi?
Then, might as well let it be...
15-16... Kosumi.
Come, let's see what you have in mind!
I forfeit...
Sai?
It's a forfeiture...
he has declared his loss.
But we've only played about half
as much as we did last time...
Touya! You're awesome!
You were so serious!
With every move, I could feel
your drive just attacking me!
The kids at the national tournament
were awesome too, but...
Really...
Everyone's so... serious...
He's not listening to me...
he's not listening to anything I have to say...
I'm going home...
See you.
Dad...
Dad!
Dad... do you think I have talent at Go?
Talent at Go?
I'm not sure if you have that or not.
But even if you don't, you have
two much greater talents.
One is your willingness to
try harder than anyone else.
The other is your undying love of Go.
Dad...
Until now...
I've walked straight forward,
feeling pride from what you told me.
But now...
there's an obstacle in my way!
Some large obstacle that I can't see...
What did you do Sai...
Weren't you going to win by 2 moku again?!
Hey Sai!
I had no choice but to cut his head off...
I couldn't pat him gently on the head...
What's with this guy?!
He surprised me...
Have you never been serious before?!
Serious...
It was so funny...
These old couples lived at this place on the
other side of the river, and next to them...
Hey Hikaru, are you even listening?
Hikaru!
Hey Hikaru, this is the way home...
I have something...
Are you going to your Go classes again?
Today isn't the day for the Go classes...
Hikaru! You've been acting really weird lately!
Domestic and
international travel
Sky Blue Travel
Tours of various locales -- Rental
Go Salon
Weekdays 1PM~10PM
Weekends 12PM~9PM
6F
Hair Studio
Joy
Touya...
where does your seriousness come from?
What is it about Go?
Are you another person who's
trying to obtain the hand of god?
Hikaru are we going to play Go again today?
No
But we came all this way!
I'm not in the mood for it right now.
Hey you! Hold on!
Mr. Touya, I found that boy walking down the street!
That boy that commented on 1-2
at the children's Go tournament...
Oh it's you, Akira-kun isn't here today.
Oh...
so you were the one that beat Akira...
You look familiar...
Oh!
Touya's Dad... the one that's closest
to obtaining the Hand of God...
I want to know how strong you are...
Sit down.
Umm! I!
Hikaru!
Let me play against this man!
When I was Honinbou Shuusaku, a
great number of men came to fight me.
This man's spirit, it's the same as all of those people!
Place three stones,
that's what I play Akira at.
That's how strong Akira is!
He has the same eyes that Touya does.
I'm sure Sai does too...
I'm the only one left out.
I...
I want to play!
Me!
Let's begin!
5-3 Kakari!
5-3...
So cool...
3-3 Tsuke!
I thought Touya placed the stones well...
but this guy...
I've taught Akira Go since he was 2.
He plays me every morning.
He is just as strong as a pro now.
Oh wow!
It's like his fingertips are shining!
4-4 Hoshi!
I will not let him go to any Amateur Tournaments.
If he plays another boy his age, it'll be
like cutting off a bud before it blooms.
Akira is above all other children.
And THAT is why I can't believe
that any child could defeat Akira!
3-2 Sagari
His fingers lift the stone...
places them inbetween and lifts it...
those fingers place the stone onto the board...
those shining finger tips...
if I could play like that...
10-16 Star!
If I...
could play like...
like that!
Hikaru...
どこにあるのかな
Dokoni aru no kana?
Where is it?
ボクだけの宝物
bokudakeno takaramono
The treasure that belongs to me
今　大きな冒険へ
ima ookina bouken e
Now with a great adventure...
やわらかな日差し
yawarakana hizashi
the gentle sunlight
旅立ちの予感
tabitachi no yokan
a feeling of departure
空も花も　ホラ 笑っている
sora mo hana mo hora waratte iru
The sky and the flower are both laughing!
この先には何が待つのだろう
kono saki ni wa nani ga matsu no darou?
I wonder what waits ahead for me.
深呼吸
shinkokyuu
take a deep breath...
夢の扉にそっと手をかけて　行こう
yume no tobira ni soutto te wo kakete... ikou!
place your hand gently on the door to your dreams... let's go!
風に吹かれながら
kaze ni fukare nagara
Because I was blown by the wind!
心揺らしながら
kokoro yurashi nagara
Because my heart was touched!
真っ白な地図を片手に持ちながら
masshiro na chizu wo katate ni mochinagara
holding my belongings in one hand
風に吹かれながら
kaze ni fukare nagara
Because I was blown by the wind!
明日を描きながら
asu wo kaki nagara
Because I can't cause strife!
遠くまで　何処まで
tooku made, doko made?
far away
たどり着けるまで
tadori tsukeru made
until I reach that place...
絶対負けないよ　絶対泣かないよ
zettai makenaiyo zettai nakanaiyo
I won't lose! I won't lose!
この夢を叶えるその日までは
kono yume wo kanaeru sono hi made wa
Until the day that I make this dream come true!
あの空は笑っていた
ano sora wa waratteita
That sky is fleeting!
あの花はも笑っていた
ano hana mo waratteita
That flower is fleeting!
ボクもいつか笑うから
boku mo itsuka warau kara
Some day I will laugh with you!
どんな壁も越えるから
donna kabe mo koeru kara
I will surpass any obstacle!
もう　何も何も　コワクナイ
mou nani mo... nani mo kowakunai
I'm not afraid of anything any more!
Umezawa Yukari's Go Go Igo!
Go! Go! Igo!
Teacher Yukari
Our Go classroom is about to start,
but Yuuki is nowhere to be seen!
Mai
Teacher Yukari
Yuuki
What are you doing dressed like that?
I'm going to become a pro Go player!
Pro Go player
But getting dressed like that has nothing to do with it!
And oh yeah, Ms. Yukari, how
do you become a pro at Go?
How do you become a pro?
Well in the Japanese Go Kiin that I'm in,
Take the annual Pro Examination
there's an annual pro examination.
But only 4 or 5 people can make it each year...
Only a few people can pass the exam each year
Wow there's a lot involved in becoming a pro!
Yeah, but if Yuuki-kun tries hard
he may be able to become one...
even if you're a child, if you pass the pro
examination, you can become a Pro Go player.
I want to eat some too...
to be continued...
What's so special about Touya Akira?!
He's a worthless moron who lost to me at the game!
You said you won against Touya?!
Hikaru... stop
he doesn't seem like someone
you should mess with...
Hey, don't get too elated.