この瞳君の瞳に
kono me kimi no me ni
On this eye, this eye on yours,
映るどんなモノも
utsuru donna mono mo
everything will appear,
見極めて見せるよ 真実を
mikiwamete miseru yo shinjitsu wo
I will tell apart the truth.
Elite-Fansubs
Presents
Hikaru
Elite-Fansubs
Presents
no Go
Hikaru no Go
僕達はこの時代に
bokutachi wa kono jidai ni
We had so many dreams
どれだけの夢抱えて
dore dake no yume kakaete
In this time we live in.
涙して迷いながら
namida shite mayoi nagara
We stare at it and run towards it,
それに賭けてみてるの
sore ni kakete miteru no
even as we wander about crying.
僕は それでも 人にひけとらぬような
boku wa sore demo hito ni hiketoranu you na
Even then, I will find a deciding move.
決め手見つけ夢を手にするだろう
kimete mitsuke yume wo te ni suru darou
just as good as anyone else's, and take hold of my dreams.
この瞳君の瞳に
kono me kimi no me ni
On this eye, this eye on yours,
映るどんなモノも
utsuru donna mono mo
everything will appear.
見極めて見せるよ 真実だけ
mikiwamete miseru yo shinjitsu dake
I'll tell apart, just the truth.
たとえ現実が
tatoe genjitsu ga
Even if the truth is
きつく埋もれそうでも
kitsuku umoresou demo
so harsh it's suffocating.
こんな場所で終わる
konna basho de owaru
I'm not going to end
僕じゃない
boku janai
in a place like this.
Shindou's changed since the preliminaries...
Hikaru! You don't seem scared
of the bearded man anymore.
Hehe, instead I used him to calm down.
That's a huge improvement!
Let's go to the match hall early.
It's begun. The long long pro exam....
Only three people will pass.
This year I'll...
My goal isn't to just pass.
It's to pass in first place.
Six straight wins!?
Shindou... Shindou has six straight wins...
The Thirty-Eighth Match
The Challengers
Seventh Match of the Pro Exam Finals
Japanese Go Research Center
It's finally time!
I was so happy last night, I couldn't sleep.
Sorry but I'm going to have to win again.
Seems like you're getting a lot of wins, but I'll
show you that good luck can't last forever.
Then if I beat Tsubaki-san today my straight wins
won't be due to good luck,
but due to my skill right?
You little brat, you're starting to talk back?
You were scared to death during the
preliminaries. You seem calm now.
I'm not calm at all. I always come here really
nervous, just like you Tsubaki-san.
What'd you say!?
I understand why you want to try
to calm down by bugging me.
It was the same during the preliminaries too right?
Shut up.
I thought it was a plot on your
side to try to get me nervous.
A plot to get you nervous!?
I don't do stuff like that!
And your voice is just naturally loud.
Shindou-kun morning!
Oh, Fuku!
Let me ride on your bike sometime Tsubaki-san!
He really has changed... dammit
I can't afford to lose.
Shindou's changed?
Didn't Iijima-san say that too?
It's time for lunch, so please stop your clocks.
The turn you stop your clocks on?
That doesn't matter at all!
You said you should stop it on your
own turn during the preliminaries!
You have more time in the finals
than during the preliminaries.
It's better to rest during the finals.
Stop making things up.
I'm not making it up!
Shut up.
What? This is the break room.
If you want to be alone, get out of here.
You seem relaxed.
I guess you can just go back to work
even if you fail the pro exams.
You idiot!
I don't have a job I can go back to!
Yeah, I did take some days off
of work for the preliminaries,
but I had to quit for the finals!
The exam goes for two months,
they're going to fire me if I ask
them for days off every week!
It probably wasn't a very good job anyways.
What!?
No matter what job it is, you really can't
take this many days off of it usually.
I've always been a part time job hopper.
Always?
This is my fifth year taking the exam. I was
hoping you'd recognize me by now.
Though it is my first time making
it past the preliminaries.
You're from Tokyo?
Yes.
I'm from Nagano. It costs me around
20,000 to take a trip here.
I go back during the day on Tuesday, and I stay
at a friend's house during the weekend.
Saves on hotel costs.
I stay at a hotel, but hotels aren't good.
I lose a lot of sleep brooding over things.
You can forget about the exam at a
friend's house, that's a lot better.
Isn't it great how easy a student in Tokyo has it?
You can just go to college. You're smart aren't you?
What good will going to a third rate college do me?
But there are people who pass the pro exams
while going to a first rate college.
There was someone who became
a pro in high school,
and got into a first rate college while
working as a pro wasn't there?
I heard there was a pro with a lawyer's license.
They've got their life set for them.
Let's stop talking about it.
Yeah. All you have to do is win. It doesn't
matter if you're smart or not.
But Tsubaki-san, your voice is too loud.
Yup, yup, and the stuff you say
tends to irritate people too.
What'd you say!?
Come on, lunch is ending.
Please begin.
Though they all have different talents and walked different paths,
they all love Go and concentrate on Go.
In this race none of that matters, and
whoever wins the most can become pro...
Hikaru had a victory against Tsubaki.
Eighth Match of the Pro Exam Finals
After Eight matches, Isumi-kun, Ochi-kun, Waya-kun,
and even Shindou-kun are still undefeated!
Ninth Match of the Pro Exam Finals
Waya lost!? His opponent was... Adachi...
Isumi-san you won?
Well even though he's lost, it's only his first loss.
I only have two losses too...
Shindou won today too?
It'll be the fifteenth match when
I go up against Isumi-san.
I'll play Shindou on the last day.
How are you doing?
Horrible. Tomorrow's already the tenth match!?
Tomorrow... after the tenth match...
Touya's coming tomorrow night.
I'll be going now.
Ochi-kun...
According to the internet, he's still undefeated.
So he has to be rather strong.
What will he say about Shindou?
I want to know... how strong Shindou is.
Maybe it's just me... but I can hear Shindou
catching up to me from behind...
It's Touya.
We've been waiting, please come in.
Good luck.
He looks like a normal guy.
He's playing seriously!
Ochi...
if he's this strong, he's probably
one of the strongest Insei.
But he can't take my place.
If only he was as strong as me... then I'd be able
to tell through his match against Shindou...
whether Shindou is as strong as I am.
Sorry for making you wait.
Are you okay? You went to the bathroom right
after you finished, and you wouldn't come out.
I'm okay.
But...
I'm okay now, so you can go away grandpa!
Please teach him well.
So this is Touya Akira...
no wonder everyone's raising a fuss over him.
He's going to be my rival once I become pro?
It was supposed to be a tutoring game, but
it seemed like you wanted a real one,
so I didn't take it easy on you.
Should we go over the match?
I know why I lost.
I tried to surround the right side forcefully
with these two moves, but this was bad.
Once you came out, it was all over.
I should have simply extended here.
Yes that is part of it, but maybe you care
a little too much about territory.
You should use strength to attack.
Ochi will play Shindou on the last day.
There's still a month and a half away.
I can pull him up a little before then.
You're strong enough to be pro.
I looked at the Go Institute Home Page.
There are three people who are undefeated.
You, Isumi, and Shindou...
Shindou lost today.
Lost!? To who!?
An outsider.
What was the game like!?
I don't know. The pro exam is long,
so there are occasional losses because you
fell off the rhythm or weren't feeling well.
Oh... so he lost a match...
You seem to be concerned about Shindou.
Is there something about him?
When Shindou became an Insei, a rumor spread
around... that Touya Akira thought
of Shindou as a rival...
Shindou... no one believed him because he
was in second class for a long time but...
What do you think of Shindou?
He's not strong enough to be a concern.
My rivals are Isumi-san, Waya, and Honda-san.
Then there's Adachi-san, Komiya-san,
and Shindou right below us I guess.
Just so that you know, I've
never lost against Shindou.
When was the last time you played Shindou?
Three months ago.
Three months ago... that's far in the past.
Why you...
You'll be playing Shindou on the last day right?
I need to train Ochi before then,
so that he can take my place.
If you'd like, I can come here
until then whenever I can.
You don't think I can beat Shindou
without your help?
I didn't say that you can't beat him.
It's just that if you're aiming to pass without
a loss, playing me might be of help.
I get it.
Ochi-kun.
You just want to see how strong
Shindou is by using me!
I can beat him without your help!
Kousuke, what's wrong?
Besides why do you care so much about Shindou!?
I'm sorry. I'll excuse myself for today.
For today!? Don't come back!
Kousuke!
You seem to think little of me, but I'll
be your rival some day! Go away!
I don't know what happened,
but please excuse Kousuke.
I'll call again when we'd like your
help. So please don't mind him.
I don't need someone like you.
Kousuke!
I'll be waiting.
Shindou... why Shindou!?
He came up to first class before I realized it,
and he was at the top before I realized it.
Now he's going through the pro
exams with only one loss.
He's changed.
Eleventh Match of the Pro Exam Finals
Oh, Honda-kun. How many pairs are still playing?
One pair.
I guess it'll be awhile still...
We'll be leaving now.
I managed to win today too, to remain at
2 losses. But you leaders just won't fall.
Ochi and Isumi-san are both undefeated.
Waya and Shindou are still at one loss.
I've got to work extra hard this year.
I have to graduate this year after all.
I'm only one year younger than
you, so it's no different.
My parents say why don't I give up
if I can't do it by the time I'm 20.
I can keep taking the pro exam until
I'm thirty, but I have a feeling that
I'll never pass if I don't pass now.
Isumi-san's playing Shindou next?
I hope Shindou beats Isumi-san somehow...
Either Isumi-san or Ochi needs to
get a loss, or I'll have no chance.
But Shindou's going to win then.
Shindou will mess up somewhere along the way.
Are you sure? He had one loss, but
he won today without falling apart.
Oh yeah, Iijima said that Shindou's changed,
and that we'd find out when we played him.
Oh and Komiya said that Shindou's
gotten stronger when he lost.
Well, I'm sure Shindou's gotten stronger,
but I can't afford to lose to Shindou.
Of course not.
You'll finally be playing Isumi-san tomorrow.
Make sure you don't feel sick the way
you did when you lost that game.
If you face up to him in full mental and physical
health, you can beat him, Hikaru.
Hikaru?
It's your turn, Sai.
You'll lose if you don't pay attention to the game.
Me? Lose to Hikaru?
Have I ever lost a single game to you before!?
Get off your high horse!
Here I'll cut you in half!
I wonder what Hikaru's doing...
I won't let you!
Take this!
Oh, I didn't know you could do that!
Why you! Take this!
What are you raising a commotion over up there?
Twelfth Match of the Pro Exam Finals
What do you think of Shindou?
Isumi-san will give Shindou his second loss today.
That's my answer to you, Touya Akira.
Play the way I usually do, without
getting intimidated.
Calm down...
Oh yes, Hikaru. That thing where you stamped
your hand during the preliminaries.
You stopped doing it.
Oh, that.
Okay! Let's do it now!
Okay!
Hikaru, your opponent for today is here.
伝えたい想いが今
Tsutaetai omoi ga ima
These feelings I want to tell you
溢れているよ
Afurete iru yo
are spilling out right now
言葉にできなくて 戸惑っている
Kotoba ni dekinakute tomadotte iru
but I'm hesitating, not knowing how to put it into words
出会いから　数えきれぬ 季節が巡り
Deai kara kazoekirenu kisetsu ga meguri
so many seasons passed by since we met
語りあかした夜が なつかしいよね
Katari akashita yoru ga natsukashii yo ne
I miss that time we stayed up all night talking
夢へ近づくたびに
Yume e chikazuku tabi ni
As I walk towards my dreams
儚さを知ったよ
Hakanasa wo shitta yo
I learn what vain all my effort are
それぞれの旅立ち
Sorezore no tabidachi
Let's start each of
ここから始めよう
Koko kara hajimeyou
our departure here
今までの僕達とは違う
Ima made no bokura to wa chigau
I'm not like I was before
もう負けない 歩き出していくよ
Mou makenai arukidashite iku yo
I won't give up anymore, I'll keep on walking,
どんな未来へでも
Donna mirai e demo
no matter what the future holds.
強くなれるように...
Tsuyoku nareru you ni
So that I can become stronger.
Teacher Yukari
Let's cover Tsumego today!
Yuuki
Mai
"Tsumego" are problems that deal with
life and death in a particular shape.
"Tsumego" are problems dealing with life
and death in a particular shape.
Can you look at this?
This is Black First White Dies
Black First White Dies
It's a situation where White dies if Black goes first.
It's a problem where White dies if Black goes first.
Then Mai-chan why don't you try it first?
You should all think about it!!
Here?
If I take it?
If you take it...
If I take it...
I live.
Oh no... she got two eyes.
Too bad.
We'll continue this next week!
To be continued...
I'll beat Isumi-san today to set a rhythm for myself.
I was wondering if you had an over inflated
opinion of Shindou too Isumi-san.
I'm confident that I'm stronger than Shindou.
Shindou... he's desperate.