Everyone, Happy New Years!
[note: This episode should be seen
inbetween episodes 12 and 13]
We received a great deal of positive
feedback from all of you last year.
Please keep watching
Hikaru no Go this year as well.
We would be very grateful.
Sai!
Why'd you hit me?
You're talking too much for New Years!
What!? You've gotta be kidding!
Hikaru!
Akari! Wow, that Spring dress looks great on you!
Really Hikaru, what have you been doing!
You promised that you'd go
with me to greet Yukari-sensei.
Oh yeah!
Let's go! Let's go!
I wonder if Yukari-sensei is in a spring dress too...
But anyways, who's that guy?
Don't worry about little
things like that on New Years!
Come on let's go to Yukari-sensei's place, let's go.
I want to meet Yukari-sensei too!
Umezawa
May I get smarter please.
Mai
I'm done!
Yuuki-kun, are you done?
To become a Pro.
Yuuki
He's still trying for it.
[note: Ozouni is a dish made specially on New Years]
The Ozouni is done!
Teacher Yukari
Sorry for the wait.
Here you go.
Teacher, you look great!
Mai-chan, you look great.
No, no, you look better.
No Mai-chan, you do.
No. you do.
Mai-chan.
What do you think, Yuuki-kun?
Since it's new years, let's try Uchizome.
Uchizome
Uchizome?
In the Japanese Go Institute, January
Fifth is considered the day of Go, and
they do a Uchizome Ceremony.
In the Japanese Go Institute The Uchizome ceremony is held on January Fifth.
Mai wants to play you, teacher!
Me too!
Okay, then I'll play the two of you simultaneously.
Good luck!
Oh Mai-chan, you place the stones fairly well.
You took it, Yuuki-kun!
Easy win!
Huh?
Teacher, let's draw on the loser's face as a penalty!
Let's draw on the face.
What?
Maybe the teacher will lose to us.
Maybe the teacher will lose!!
We resign.
Too bad.
Hmm... you both have much to learn.
Well, I don't want to lose first thing on New Years.
I don't want to lose on New Years.
She's so childish.
New Years
Greeting
Well then...
that's that.
I wonder if that's Hikaru-kun.
New Years Greeting
Hikaru no Go
Wishes you a happy new year!