Real Fansubbers presents
Hikaru no Go
胸の鼓動　熱くゆるがす
mune no kodou atsuku yurugasu
My heart walks, searching for something exciting
刺激求めて歩く My Heart
shigeki motomete aruku MY HEART
That will passionately sway the beating in my chest.
時間だけが過ぎる毎日じゃ
jikan dake ga sugiru mainichi jya
If I just wait for the time to pass everyday.
変化はない
henka ha nai
nothing's going to change.
Woo Wooo
止まらない　信じたい　進みたい
tomaranai shinjitai susumitai
I won't stop. I want to believe. I want to move forward.
自分の力試す My Life
jibun no chikara tamesu MY LIFE
I will test my strength during my life.
でも早歩きしたって見落とすだけ
demo hayaaruki shitatte miotosudake
But even if I walk faster.
I will definitely lose track of
そう確実に
sou kakujitsu ni
the important things.
Baby for you...
明日は明日の風が吹く
ashita ha ashita no kaze ga fuku
Tomorrow's wind will blow tomorrow.
それでも　今この瞬間を強く生きたい
soredemo
but I want to make the most out of this moment now.
ima kono shunkan wo tsuyoku ikitai
It's fantasy
さまよったとしても
samayotta to shitemo
Even if I'm wandering,
見たことない世界でも
mitakotonai sekai demo
even if I'm in a strange new world,
何よりも 自分を信じ立ち向かおう
nani yori mo jibun wo shinji tachimukaou
I'll stand up to it,
believing in myself more than anything else.
It's destiny
どんな場所にいても
donna basho ni itemo
No matter where I am,
つつむ空は一つだから
tsutsumu sora ha hitotsu dakara
I'm surrounded by the same sky.
ねぇ　もっと 翼広げて
nee motto tsubasa hirogete
so I'll be able to fly
羽ばたけるよね
habatakeruyone
with my wings spread out.
Everyone watching the TV,
long time no see. I'm Sai.
This time, we're showing a Hikaru no Go side story.
And it's the story of when Akira met Hikaru.
Yes! That time in the sixth grade!
Yes! That... that great scene when I look
down upon Akira from far above...
that great scene is going to be replayed!!!
It's not?...
Then I'll...
I... don't appear in this episode?
My... My hopes...
The Sixty-Sixth Match
The Fated Encounter
Is this backpack Akira-kun's?
Oh, sorry. I'll put that away right now.
This is in such good shape. My grandson is in
the sixth grade, and his is all scratched up.
It's just Akira-Kun. He's never gone
anywhere after school for fun.
I see.
Thank you.
And where is Akira-Kun?
Couldn't you have gone with a Keima there?
Why? If I reply with a Kosumi to your Keima,
Black's going to get strength in the center.
But if black plays in the corner, White's
stones there are in trouble.
You think?
I think it's fine to make a one-space
jump into the center.
Hey, you two. Here's some tea.
Mr. Ashiwara, do you have time to play
a tutoring game with me today?
Sure.
Akira-kun's going into Junior High next year.
You're going to become a pro now, right?
Huh?
What do you mean, 'Huh'? Are you
not going to take the exam?
Your good enough to pass, aren't you?
Right, Mr. Ashiwara?
I mean, even you were able to become a pro.
Ichikawa-san, that wasn't funny.
You should have taken it this year. Why
are you so hesitant to become a pro?
I just think I should get a little better first...
You're bored, right?
N-No, not at all!
See? I'm right.
Bored? What do you mean?
Well, there's no one around Akira's
age that can become his rival in Go.
I'm sure that's really boring.
There are alot of guys like that
for me, so it's a lot of fun.
That's impossible.
There can't be anyone Akira-Kun's
age who can be his rival.
I don't really... want... a rival.
I'll make Ogata-san or my
father my rival some day.
What about me, Akira?
Ashiwara-san, you're a friend.
Why, you!
Really.
I see now. That's why he plays
you so much, Mr. Ashiwara.
I wonder why...
I'm just dissatisfied...
With becoming a pro right now.
Maybe I do need someone else...
just like Ashiwara-san says.
This is the end.
I can't beat you... excuse me, I can't beat
you, Master, even with four stones.
You lost because of your Kosumi here.
There wouldn't have been any problem
had you filled in the center instead.
You have a point. You cut me here, and
everything went downhill from there.
Excuse me.
Didn't I say the other day that
I don't drink orange juice?
The Master drinks banana juice. Banana juice.
Oh, I'm sorry. I'll bring it immediately.
I'm sorry about that. The usual girl isn't here today.
But I can see why you won the
Children's Meijin tournament.
You're very good.
That thing's worthless.
How is that worthless?
You won in a tournament of over 2000
children from all over the nation.
You're the top child player in Japan.
I heard a rumor about him after
the awards ceremony.
Him?
Touya Akira.
Isn't he the strongest Go player amongst kids?
Yeah, Touya Akira.
He's Touya Meijin's son, and he doesn't
play in Amateur tournaments.
Isn't he trying to become a
pro in the Insei program?
Insei? Not at all.
Then why doesn't he come out to the tournaments?
He said that all the other kids would
stop trying if he were to play.
What did he seriously say that?
What an annoying guy.
He doesn't show his face in the world, he
just looks down at us from the shadows.
I wonder if he's actually any good.
Touya Meijin's son...
The Go salon in front of the train station,
doesn't Touya Meijin own that?
Touya Meijin?
If he's the Meijin's son, he may
play there occasionally.
Here you are.
Thanks.
Where is it?
Where... is that Go salon?
Sir, who is that child?
He's the son of an important customer of ours.
They know how much I love Go, so they
send him over once a week to play me.
Basically they want to show off their son.
Yes? Oh, Mom.
Yeah, I know. Cram school, right?
Oh, don't forget to tell dad about the money.
Yeah, I just played him.
Welcome.
Huh?
Hey, you!
Who is he?
Him? You mean Akira-kun?
Touya Akira?
Yeah.
So that's him...
How much is it to play here?
500 yen for children.
Here.
Thank you very much.
I heard Touya Akira is good, is that true?
Yes. You doubt it?
Yeah.
Then why don't you ask Akira-kun
to play a game against you?
Yeah, that's what I came here for.
Akira-kun.
A customer?
Yes, he wants to play you,
Akira-kun. Is that alright?
Sure. How strong are you?
I won the Children's Meijin tournament.
Really? That's incredible!
What's incredible about it? You weren't in it.
I came here to beat you.
Children's Meijin isn't enough. I have to
beat you for people to recognize me.
That's impossible. Poor kid.
That's why Akira-kun should become a pro already.
I'll go get some tea.
Dammit... he doesn't seem to care... okay.
I am Isobe Hideki.
If I win, tell everyone that you
lost to Isobe Hideki, alright?
Sure! I'll tell everyone!
Isobe Hideki-kun, right?
Let's play! Do you mind if I Nigiri?
What's with him?
He doesn't seem that good at all.
You're going first.
Y-Yeah...
Good luck.
I can't possibly lose...
against someone like him!
His... His expression's changed...
You should have played here instead
of making a Keima jump.
A Tsuke is perfect in this situation.
Ohh! I see.
I have a hard time playing Tsuke, it scares me.
Wow. Akira's playing a kid
Master Ashiwara, you're still under
20 right? You look like a kid to me.
He's not... very good.
I resign.
Your ideas are too focused on territory.
They won't work on Akira.
Ashiwara-san.
You had to move into the White territory
and base the match on survival.
But even so, you're plenty good.
It's just your opponent was too strong.
I'm going
You don't have to...
Thanks for the game.
Who was he?
Huh? Umm... who was it? I forget.
Hey...
Become a pro already, Akira.
Yeah... You're right.
In the past, you ignored this and
let me cut your stones apart.
But your Kaketsugi today, whether it was
good or bad, lead to a decent shape.
No judging from the shape Black was
in, it strengthened Black a great deal.
You played a good game today, for
the first time in a great while.
Your handicap may change from three
stones to two in the near future.
I see...
great hope for you.
Father!
Father...
Oh, hi Akira-kun.
Hello, Ichikawa-san. Can you take this again?
Okay.
You look happy. Did something
good happen to you?
Father complimented my game this morning!
Oh? Doesn't he compliment you all the time?
Not at all! He hasn't for awhile.
But Master Touya is always bragging about his son.
Really?
Really.
He's very proud of you. You have to live up to that.
Father expects a lot from me. Ashiwara-san
is waiting for me, too.
Yeah, I should recognize my own strength.
I'm not being overconfident. I will stand at the
top of the Go world. Just like my father.
And I'll pull along those who follow me.
I'll forget about my worries. I just
need to walk straight forward.
Walk straight... down the path of the pros.
Oh, there's a kid!
Can I play him?
Ah... umm...
He's...
Are you looking for someone to
play? Wanna play in the back?
I'm Touya Akira.
I'm Shindou Hikaru. I'm in the sixth grade.
Ring
My
Bell
noizu darake no mune de
ノイズだらけの胸で
I listen to my fate through the din in my heart.
noizu darake no mune deunmei wo kikiwakeru
ノイズだらけの胸で運命を聴きわける
It occurs to me.
hirameku
閃く
hiramekuyume ha watashi no naka demezame o matteta
閃く夢は私の中で目覚めを待ってた
My dream was waiting for the time
to wake up within me.
mezame o matteta
閃く夢は私の中で目覚めを待ってた
Music
Is
My
Thing
I can be more like myself
jibun rashiku nareru
自分らしくなれる
Music
In
My
Heart
ときめきならして
Let the pounding of my heart be heard
tokimeki narashite
ときめきならして
Music
Is
My
Thing
karada wo ugokasu
体を動かす
I move my body
karada wo ugokasu
体を動かす
Music
In
My
Heart
Feel the light
hikari wo kanjite
光を感じて
Music
Is
My
Thing
shiro to kuro de egaku
白と黒で描く
I draw with black and white
shiro to kuro de egaku
白と黒で描く
Music
In
My
Heart
owaranai haamoni
The unending Harmony
終わらないハーモニー
owaranai haamoni
Let's cover an interesting Tesuji
called "Under the Stone" today.
Black lives if Black goes first here.
Yuuki-kun, why don't you try?
Okay!
If I take it?
Yup! Now you can take these three stones.
So, you have two eyes, here
and here, so you're alive.
Yuuki-kun, you're right.
As you can see, you can move under the stone that
was taken, so it's called "Under the Stone".
Give Mai a problem, too.
Next week then.
Le Ping? You lost to him?
Isumi-kun, come here. Let's play a game.
I'm going to test how good you are.
I'm sorry but I can't let you stay here if you can't
even beat Le Ping. You'll have to leave.
L...Leave? Yang Hai-san?