kono me kimi no me ni
この瞳君の瞳に
On this eye, this eye on yours,
utsuru donna mono mo
映るどんなモノも
everything will appear.
mikiwamete miseru yo shinjitsu wo
見極めて見せるよ 真実を
I will tell apart the truth.
------- -------- -- -- --- - --- --- ---- ---- ---
Real-Fansubbers
Presents
----- ----- ---- --- -- --
----- ---- ---- --- - - --
Hikaru
Hikaru no Go
bokutachi wa kono jidai ni
僕達はこの時代に
How many dreams did we carry with us,
dore dake no yume kakaete
どれだけの夢抱えて
through this day and age?
namida shite mayoi nagara
涙して迷いながら
We gave them all a try, even as we cried
sore ni kakete miteru no
それに賭けてみてるの
wandering around so very lost.
boku wa sore demo hito ni hiketoranu you na
僕は それでも 人にひけとらぬような
Even then, I will find a deciding move,
kimete mitsuke yume wo te ni suru darou
決め手見つけ夢を手にするだろう
just as good as anyone else's, and take hold of my dreams.
kono me kimi no me ni
この瞳君の瞳に
On this eye, this eye of yours,
utsuru donna mono mo
映るどんなモノも
everything will appear.
mikiwamete miseru yo shinjitsu dake
見極めて見せるよ 真実だけ
I'll tell apart, just the truth.
tatoe genjitsu ga
たとえ現実が
Even if the truth is
kitsuku umoresou demo
きつく埋もれそうでも
so harsh it's suffocating.
konna basho de owaru
こんな場所で終わる
I'm not going to end
boku janai
僕じゃない
in a place like this.
Rain...
Waya won.
If Shindou losses, he'll have a playoff
match against me, at four losses.
It's over.
The Forty-Seventh Match
To the World of the Pros
NcDonalds
Isumi-san quit the Kyuseikai!?
That's not all.
He's not an Insei anymore either.
Although, even those that graduate
usually stay until March.
Kyuseikai is the Go school that Isumi-san
always studied at, right?
I wonder what Isumi-san's going to do now that
he's quit the Kyuseikai and the Insei program.
Waya, do you know anything?
No... I couldn't bring myself to call him.
So I went to take a look during
an Insei study session.
And Shinoda-sensei told me that Isumi-san quit.
What... What did he say!?
That this may be better for Isumi-san.
Why!?
Here. It's hot.
Thanks...
Well, everyone is different.
He's probably trying to look at himself
from a different perspective.
Even though he has quit the Kyuseikai
and the Insei program,
playing games isn't the only
way to get better at Go.
At his level, it's more than enough
to replay other games.
Sometimes it's important to be alone for awhile.
That's what he said.
I don't really get it...
How can the teacher say that?
Isumi-san might have given up on becoming a pro.
The teacher said 'Isumi-kun still hasn't
given up, he'll come back next year'.
Serious?
Yeah. He looked serious.
'He definitely doesn't think that
his Go will end here.' He said.
Let Isumi-kun worry about himself.
You have yourself to worry about, too.
You're a pro already.
Is what he said to me.
You too, Hikaru.
But anyways...
I thought I'd teach you how to record games today.
Record games?
We have to do it sometimes.
Though they don't usually ask people
going to school to do it.
We record all pro matches after
the third elimination round.
I know how to record a Kifu.
You have to record the times, too.
Here's an example.
What is this?
You record how long they spent
on each move, or the total time.
Hikaru, you can't possibly do this.
And there's byou-yomi, too.
Waya, you can do this!?
Of course.
How can Waya do something like this!?
What'd you say!?
You called me out over something like this?
I'm doing this as a favor for you! Remember that!
But...
Don't mess up when you're doing it.
And? How are you supposed to do this?
Hikaru is finally taking a step
into the world of the pros.
But anyways, pros have to play
games, right?! Games!
When do I get to play Touya!?
Do you know, Waya?
Of course not!
I'll be playing lots of people, right?
Like you, or Saeki-san, or...
Am I going to play Touya-Meijin, too!?
Yes! Yes!
Will I be playing him!?
Listen here...
It's going to be at least five years
before you play the top pros.
Even if I keep winning?
I still can't play them?
Yes, can we!?
Well, if you keep winning you
will reach the top, but...
That's impossible.
The second elimination round is as far
as pros lower than 4-dan can go.
But I am connected!
To Touya, and to Touya's dad.
Yes! Yes!
We're in the same world already!
I'll be playing them someday!
'I'...?
I want to play Murakami 2-dan from
the Wakajishisen again, too.
And I want to play Ogata 9-dan or
that old guy who's Honinbou, too.
Don't be elated!
Hikaru...
But I want to play Touya first!
I want to play against Touya!
I...
He's still a lower-dan player.
So, if you're lucky, you'll get
to play him sometime soon.
Our pairings are randomly made.
Random?
I...
I'll get to play Shirakawa-sensei or
Morishita-sensei in a real match, too!
Like I keep saying...
You won't play high-dan players for a long time.
But we are connected!
That means we'll be playing sometime!
I mean, we're in the same world already!
Yes...
I'm not the one that's connected...
Hikaru...
It's just Hikaru.
Will Hikaru...
not let me play anymore?
That is true, but...
Right!? Let's see who becomes 2-dan first!
The 48th Ouza Title Match
The 23rd graduating class of
Koike Jr. High School, Reunion
Ten minutes before the match starts...
Good morning, Master Zama.
Good morning.
Now that I think about it, I still
haven't congratulated you...
for the sixth successful defense of the Meijin title.
Congratulations, Master Touya.
Thank you.
But you lost the challenger rights to the Kisei title.
I'm sure it's because you're exhausted from
playing too many matches, Master Touya.
You may be right.
I may have lost the final match
to decide the challenger
for the Kisei title, because I was tired.
But I am in the best condition today.
I believe it is your son who
is in the best of conditions.
Isn't he undefeated?
He has had twenty straight wins so far.
The only match Akira lost was the new first dan
series match, from right before he became pro...
Master Zama,
just that match against you.
Then you'll be trying to get revenge
for your beloved little boy today!
You first, Zama Ouza.
The First Game of the Ouza Title Match
Japanese Go Institute
What is it, Master Kuwabara?
Is there an interesting article?
The results of the pro exam are on this.
Pro exam?
Ochi Kousuke (13)
Shindou Hikaru (14)
Waya Yoshitaka (15)
That boy passed...
I see, his name is Shindou.
Shindou? Who is that?
Just a boy I passed by once.
That you just passed by?
Yes... right over there.
I think it was six months ago...
When I got off the elevator,
I saw a lot of youngsters from the Insei program.
And...
I felt something exceptional about that boy.
Something exceptional?
That sounds interesting!
Yes, it's very interesting.
He may be part of the new wave
that Ogata was speaking of.
A new wave... 'nouvelle vague.'
I look forward to it.
I'm really looking forward to it!
Spring... it starts in the spring!
I wonder who my first match is going to be against.
Hey, Sai!
Sai?
What's wrong? Come on, let's play!
Just like Hikaru can't wait to play other pros,
they are also waiting for Hikaru...
They aren't waiting for me.
Hikaru...
Hikaru!
It's Hikaru.
You come to report that you
passed after all this time!?
We've known about it forever!
That hurts!
You're late! You should have come earlier!
It's all thanks to me that you
passed, remember that!
How is it thanks to you, Kawai-san?
What? That boy said he passed the pro exam.
Terauchi-san, you don't know Shindou-kun, do you?
So you think it's not all thanks to me?
He came here almost every day
during his summer break.
It's not all thanks to you, Kawai-san!
What'd you say?
The results of the pro exam were
in Weekly Go, a little while ago.
Here, this one.
Shindou Hikaru is his name...
Say this when you get a title,
'It's all thanks to Kawai-san that I am here today.'
What are you talking about!?
A title? sounds good!
Get four of them, just like Touya Meijin!
Nah, he'll have five of them soon.
Five titles? Touya Meijin?
If he wins the Ouza match.
There is a good chance of it, since he won
both the first and second games.
I'd hate to be Zama Ouza right now.
And? How many times do you
have to win to become Ouza?
The Ouza match is a five game match!
You become Ouza if you win three times!
He's even defending the Tengen title
in between the Ouza games.
Touya Meijin sure has it tough.
Tengen?
Is that a title, too?
It might be a little tough for him to get
a title if he doesn't even know that...
Actually, are you sure he's going to become a pro?
Why you! Don't embarrass me like that!
It doesn't concern you, Kawai-san!
Why you!
Calm down. I'll give you some
old papers, so read up on it.
Th-Thanks, master...
Oh, this is Touya's dad.
It says he's going to play the Ouza match.
There's a Kifu for it.
His opponent is Zama Ouza.
So this guy is Ouza...
Hikaru, this is only part of the Kifu.
The rest is on the back.
This is...
'First game of the Tengen match'...
It's Touya Meijin who has the Tengen title and...
Ichiryuu Kisei is the challenger.
Look.
Touya's dad is in this one, too!
Hikaru, turn the page! Turn the page!
Let's see...  Touya Meijin...
sixth successful defense!?
He really is incredible...
Don't put it on top, put it next
to what I'm reading, Hikaru!
Oh boy.
Let's see...
Here... There's still...
What? They're not in order, and some are missing.
This is August... this is May...
This one below it is...
January!
It's old!
It's Touya!
It's Zama Ouza standing next to him...
Oh! This is the new first dan series match!
Hikaru! Turn the page!
Yeah, this is it!
We all watched this match
together on that monitor.
The new first dan series...
Yeah... I forgot about this...
I'm getting really excited!
Right, Sai?
Hikaru, show me that one!
The new first dan series...
It was snowing...
It was snowing that day.
It's my turn now.
I'm going to begin with this match.
When the new year comes...
Sorry for interviewing you during New Years.
But now that you have your fifth title, Meijin,
you and Touya are both going to get busier.
It's too bad your winning streak
stopped at 26 last year.
But, I'm expecting just as much from you this year.
I'll try my best.
Well I'll be leaving for today, then.
Thank you for your time.
Amano-san.
Yes?
That thing where you have a new
pro player play a top pro...
The new first dan series?
You're going to play in it!?
You were too busy to play in it last
year and the year before that.
So I wasn't going to ask this year.
Are you really going in it for us?
But I would like to choose my opponent for it.
So there's a new player good enough
for you to request to play?
It's been two years since I last met him.
He's finally here.
You mean...
Shindou Hikaru.
I-I see... that stops me from fighting back...
S-Sai...
Your expression's been scary lately...
H-Hey...
About these newspapers...
Mom is going to yell at me again
if I don't clean it up already...
I know that you can't look at it
unless it's spread out, but...
Go ahead, put them away.
I have already memorized,
all of his games that are there.
Oh yeah, Mom's out shopping.
Hello, this is Shindou.
Yeah... I mean, yes, it's me.
The new first dan series? Yes, I know what that is.
Okay.
Umm, who's my opponent?
Touya Meijin!?
Y-Yes! I understand.
Did you hear that, Sai!?
I'm going to be playing Touya Meijin!
Remember the new first dan series?
We watched it last year, remember?
Between Touya and Zama Ouza!
Oh yeah, Touya... will he... will he come watch?
Yeah, he'll definitely come!
Okay! I'll show him how strong I am now!
Hikaru...
What?
Let me...
Let me play!
Let me play that match!
tsurai omoide toka ikutsu atta no kana?
つらい想い出とかいくつあったのかな？
How many sad memories did we have?
donna tanoshii hi wo
どんな楽しい日を
What kind of happy days are we going to
kore kara wa taisetsu ni shite iku no kana?
これからは大切にしていくのかな？
hold onto preciously from now on?
chikaku no kouen de atsumatta ne itsumo
近くの公園で集まったねいつも
We always gathered at the nearby park
yonaka made ookina koe dashite waratteta ne
夜中まで大きな声出して笑ってたね
and laughed out loud into the middle of the night,
zutto... zutto...
ずっとずっと
always... always...
onaji toki wo ima ikiteru kiseki ga
同じ時代を今生きてる奇跡が
Because I'm really happy for the miracle
sugoku ureshii kara ne
すごくうれしいからね
of being here when you are
tsugi au hi mo kitto nee
次あう日もきっとねぇ
Let's laugh together again
issho ni waratte iyou yo
一緒に笑っていようよ
the next time we meet
kondo wa donna yume wo
今度はどんな夢を
what kind of dreams
issho ni katariau no kana?
一緒に語りあうのかな？
are we going to talk about then?
August 30th     Japanese Go Institute
Go Go Igo Cup Junior Pair Go Tournament was held.
Yuuki
Mai
It's finally the day of the Go Tournament!
Yup, let's do our best!
Yup!
In the morning, 300 pairs played in the preliminaries
Start your clocks!
Only 32 pairs can go to the finals!!
Go Go Igo cup's Junior Pair Go Tournament
was finally held today. I'm glad.
Yukari
Teacher
Katou Masao Honinbou and Suzuki Isao 7 dan
came to cheer them on
It was a good match.
Good luck next time.
In the mean while Mai and Yuuki were...
Unfortunately eliminated from the preliminaries, with 1 win and 4 losses
How was it?
I wanted to go to the finals.
What about you, Yuuki-kun?
I wanted to go to the finals, too.
I'm sorry for the both of you.
But you tried your best.
The finals tournament is next!!
I'm going to be hidden in your shadow again.
Then hide in my shadow!
I can't!
I understand how you feel, but...
Show me how strong you are.