kono me kimi no me ni
この瞳君の瞳に
On this eye, this eye on yours,
utsuru donna mono mo
映るどんなモノも
everything will appear.
mikiwamete miseru yo shinjitsu wo
見極めて見せるよ真実を
I will tell apart the truth.
------- -------- -- -- --- - --- --- ---- ---- ---
Real-Fansubbers
Presents
----- ----- ---- --- -- --
----- ---- ---- --- - - --
Hikaru
Hikaru no Go
bokutachi wa kono jidai ni
僕達はこの時代に
How many dreams did we carry with us,
dore dake no yume kakaete
どれだけの夢抱えて
through this day and age?
namida shite mayoi nagara
涙して迷いながら
We gave them all a try, even as we cried
sore ni kakete miteru no
それに賭けてみてるの
wandering around so very lost.
boku wa sore demo hito ni hiketoranu you na
僕はそれでも人にひけとらぬような
Even then, I will find a deciding move,
kimete mitsuke yume wo te ni suru darou
決め手見つけ夢を手にするだろう
just as good as anyone else's, and take hold of my dreams.
kono me kimi no me ni
この瞳君の瞳に
On this eye, this eye of yours,
utsuru donna mono mo
映るどんなモノも
everything will appear.
mikiwamete miseru yo shinjitsu dake
見極めて見せるよ真実だけ
I'll tell apart, just the truth.
tatoe genjitsu ga
たとえ現実が
Even if the truth is
kitsuku umoresou demo
きつく埋もれそうでも
so harsh it's suffocating.
konna basho de owaru
こんな場所で終わる
I'm not going to end
boku janai
僕じゃない
in a place like this.
Or is Internet Go mere fun
and games for Touya-san?
Yes it is,
but there are games that I can't lose.
I knew that he would walk the same path
as I do, ever since I first met him.
The same path to master the divine move...
Tomorrow! My wish will be granted!
How much closer can I get...
to the divine move!?
The Fifty-Fifth Match
How long will that study session last, Akira-san?
Until late afternoon, probably...
Oh, you'll be eating dinner at home, then?
Mother, what about the hospital?
Your father told me not to go today.
Not to go!?
He wants to play Go on the Internet
without intrusions.
He's leaving the hospital tomorrow. He
should take this chance to rest up.
Why is Go the only thing that
either of you think about?
I-I'll be going then.
Wow, he's getting out tomorrow.
I was really worried when he collapsed ten days ago.
I was supposed to play Shindou on that day.
The next chance I'll have to play him will
be during the Wakajishisen, next month.
But I can watch Shindou's matches against
other pro players before then.
I'll measure Shindou's strength from them.
Yes... It won't be too long now...
until I find out exactly who he is!
But for my father to want to play Internet
Go, without being interrupted?
He certainly seems absorbed in it.
He didn't seem to like it very much when he started.
Finally, this day has come.
Let's go, Sai.
Welcome!
She's not Mitani's sister.
Maybe it's her day off. Or maybe she quit.
You can use this machine.
Okay, thanks.
I wonder if Master Touya is there.
But... is he serious about retiring if he loses?
If I were to lose, I will retire.
He's probably serious.
Man, why is that family so stubborn!?
Players
Display all Users
Refresh
PLAY
BACK
USER-ID
Nation
Wins
Loss
Information
PAIR GO
SETUP
Current Display Settings
He's not there yet.
Sai?
There he is!
If...
If Sai wins...
Refresh
PLAY
EXIT
Information
PAIR GO
is he really going to retire?
PLAY
An even match with a komi of 5.5...
Three hours on each of our clocks...
Request toya koyo-san for a game
Board Size
Komi
Time on Clock
Byou-Yomi
Chat
Info
Request
Cancel
For a player with five titles to disappear...
Isn't that a big deal!?
I can't let it happen!
Master Touya is black...
Request
Cancel
Request toya koyo-san for a game
Board Size
Komi
Time on Clock
Byou-Yomi
Chat
Info
Request
Cancel
WHITE
Captured: 0 Stones
Rem. Time: 180 / 180
BLACK
Captured: 0 Stones
Rem. Time: 180 / 180
GAME INFO
Komi: 5.5 Moku
Move:
Auto
Chat
Chat-Win
Stop Observing
I can feel it, even through the net.
The same... no... an even greater tension
than I felt during the new first dan series.
Touya Meijin...
It is Touya Meijin!
I don't care if he has to retire!
I get to watch this match from here!
I get to watch this match between Sai and Touya Meijin!
I'm home!
Yoshitaka! What were you out all night!?
I thought the tutoring game was
supposed to end last night!
I played Go at Saeki-san's place, and stayed there.
I told you to call home whenever you do that.
I tried to call your cell, but you had turned it off.
Oh, sorry.
Breakfast?
I had it already!
Maybe I'll get my own place, just like Saeki-san.
I'll get more referrals from the Master,
and pick up more record keeper jobs.
I'll have the money from my matches, too.
I should be able to pay for my own room...
But what about food and laundry?
Maybe I'll try playing on the net for a change.
Yoshitaka, are you going to be home today?
You're eating lunch and dinner at home, right?
Yeah! I'll have them at home.
Hmm? Sai?
It must be the fake Sai from before.
He showed up again?
Or is it a different fake Sai?
toya... koyo...?
What!? Touya Kouyou!?
There's a fake Touya Meijin, too!?
There's no way that the Meijin
would play Go on the Internet.
He's the type that looks down on
it, just like Master Morishita.
Besides, isn't he still in the hospital?
Well, I guess he could play
if he had a private room.
It can't be him, though.
He's in a match. Who is he playing?
BLACK
WHITE
Sai!?
What!? They're playing each other?
WHITE
Captured: 0 Stones
Rem. Time: 165 / 180
BLACK
Captured: 0 Stones
Rem. Time: 165 / 180
MATCH INFO
Komi: 5.5 Moku
Move:
Auto
Chat
Chat-Win
Stop Observing
It just started.
Touya Kouyou against Sai!?
It would be an incredible match
if they were the real thing.
Hmm? They have three hours!? On the net!?
BLACK
Captured: 0 Stones
Rem.Time: 165 / 180
MATCH INFO
Could it be.... the Meijin!?
Could it be...
Sai!?
Is it the real Sai!?
Hello?
Oh, Meneer Ooijer. Thanks for the other day.
And why are you calling me
at this time of the night?
Yes?
What? Touya Kouyou is playing on the net?
And who is he playing?
What!?
It's Sai. The person you told
me about the other day.
I don't know if he's the real thing, though.
Sai, you say!?
Playing Touya Kouyou!?
Hurry! Hurry!
It's around noon in Japan right now.
Touya Kouyou and... Sai...
This is it!
So this is Sai...
He is...
a worthy opponent!
See, it's Sai!
Yeah! And he's playing Toya Koyo!
I came here because I wanted
to watch them play together.
Look at the clock, they have three hours!
There's plenty of time.
Wow! This is incredible.
I'll go make some coffee.
Yeah, make some for me, too.
This is incredible, is it really that Sai!?
The Sai who disappeared from the net
after the match against Akira?
Then it's an incredible match.
Sai vs. toya koyo.
The match has progressed peacefully so
far. I wonder how it'll go from here.
He's not just an amateur.
But he doesn't remind me of any pro.
I have no intentions of taking back my
word that I will retire if I lose, but...
If I win...
You have to tell me...
who you are!
What a surprise, Sai is here!
And he's playing Toya Koyo!
I played Toya Koyo before, he's Touya Meijin
from Japan. There's no doubt about it.
Sai is playing the Meijin evenly,
too. He's definitely the Sai...
from two years ago.
He's attacking.
I see what he's trying to do.
Then...
Touya made a move!
Isn't this what White....
what Sai wanted?
This is the answer that the Meijin
came up with after all that time?
This should be exactly what you wanted. But...
by cautiously attacking from the Boushi...
the situation turns into one that's not bad at all for me.
It's Touya Meijin! It's him!
I... I had no idea things could turn out this way.
It looked as if Sai had the advantage...
But now that we're here...
That first move that Sai made... it's...
It's lost its meaning!
Wow! You're awesome, Master Touya!
This is my Go. The Go of the Meijin, Touya Kouyou!
I won't hold back. I will win and
make you name yourself!
Touya Meijin was okay this time, but...
he has a full schedule of matches
outside the country next week.
I wouldn't be surprised if he collapses again.
Come on.
That's why we young ones have
to take on a title or two from him,
to lighten his load a bit.
Ogata-san is doing well in the Jyudan
match with two wins and two losses.
And Kurata has finally gotten the challenger
spot for the next Honinbou match.
We've got to keep moving, too.
Hey, how's it going?
Why are you so late?
Hello.
Oh? Touya-kun, you're here, too?
Yeah, I invited him.
He comes up with all these great moves.
We've been learning from him all day.
How is Master Touya's health? Is he okay?
Yes.
Didn't you see the fourth game of the Jyudan
match? He's healthier than you are.
He'll be leaving the hospital in two days.
I'm sure he's playing on the Internet right now.
Internet? Master Touya?
Wow, he doesn't look like the type.
Are they playing right now?
You have a PC. Turn it on.
I don't play on the Internet much, but...
Then what do you use your PC for?
It's useful for organizing records of games.
Hold on...
What's his handle?
His real name.
Touya...
Internet Go... maybe I'll get a PC, too.
There he is, toya koyo.
Where? Here?
There are a lot of spectators.
He is Touya Kouyou.
Players  :
USER-ID
Nation
GAMES:
Refresh
Observe
Back
WHITE
BLACK
MOVE
SIZE
HAND
KOMI
TIME
WHITE
Captured: 1 Stone
Rem. Time: 127 / 180
BLACK
Captured: 0 Stones
Rem. Time: 122 / 180
GAME INFO
Komi: 5.5 Moku
Move:
Auto
Chat
Chat-Win
Stop Observing
Is this it?
Wow, this is incredible. What's going
on with white on the top side?
The lower left looks interesting, too.
The game is... I wonder...
Huh? I can't tell how the game went.
White isn't bad.
Master Touya is black. He's incredible.
Yes, but white is strong.
Yeah, it's an even game. He's playing
this well in an even game.
Wait! They have three hours on the clock!
Yes. This is not just any player.
Exactly who is he playing?
Let's see....
His opponent's name is...
Sai?
Who's Sai?
How am I supposed to know?
Well you can't know, but he has to be a pro.
Yeah.
This is...
This is Sai!
It's Sai!
My father is...
playing Sai!
tsurai omoide toka ikutsu atta no kana?
つらい想い出とかいくつあったのかな？
How many sad memories did we have?
donna tanoshii hi wo
どんな楽しい日を
What kind of happy days are we going to
kore kara wa taisetsu ni shite iku no kana?
これからは大切にしていくのかな？
hold onto preciously from now on?
chikaku no kouen de atsumatta ne itsumo
近くの公園で集まったねいつも
We always gathered at the nearby park
yonaka made ookina koe dashite waratteta ne
夜中まで大きな声出して笑ってたね
and laughed out loud into the middle of the night,
zutto... zutto...
ずっと...ずっと...
always... always...
onaji toki wo ima ikiteru kiseki ga
同じ時代を今生きてる奇跡が
Because I'm really happy for the miracle
sugoku ureshii kara ne
すごくうれしいからね
of being here when you are
tsugi au hi mo kitto ne
次あう日もきっとねぇ
Let's laugh together again,
issho ni waratte iyou yo
一緒に笑っていようよ
the next time we meet.
kondo wa donna yume wo
今度はどんな夢を
What kind of dreams
issho ni katariau no kana?
一緒に語りあうのかな？
are we going to talk about then?
Let's cover a Fuseki problem today.
Yuuki
Teacher Yukari
Mai
Let's do a Fuseki problem today
Fuseki is the opening of the game.
White just went to 3,3 and here's the problem.
Should black go here, or go here? Which is better?
Which side is it better to                          play from?
Your hint is that black is trying
to gain territory on this side.
If black blocks off from this side,
the game will progress like this...
And he gets a lot of territory.
If black blocks from the other
side, it will progress like this,
and we have no idea where
black can make territory.
So, this is a situation in which you
want to block from this side.
To be continued...
My father arranged to play against Sai ahead of time.
My father knows who Sai is!?
They're both neck and neck now!
He can play this well against Touya Kouyou,
yet we know nothing about him.
It's the old Shindou that I see in Sai!