Fujiwarano Sai, a Go player from the Heian period
has passed through time and returned to the world in the mind of Shindou Hikaru...
in order to obtain the Hand of God.
君が今僕を支えて
Kimi ga ima boku wo sasaete
Now you are,
holding me up strong!
僕が今君を支える
boku ga ima kimi wo sasaeru
Now I am,
holding you up as well!
だから迷いながらも共に生きていこうよ
Dakara Mayoi nagara mo tomo ni ikite ikou yo
So let us now, while wandering live together
未来へと
Mirai e to...
towards the future
Elite-Fansubs presents
Hikaru no Go
仲間と戯れ　それなりで居ても
Nakama to tawamaure sorenaride itemo
Even when I'm capricing with my friends,
もの足りなさを感じてしまう
mono tari na sa wo kanjite shimau
I feel an emptiness in my heart.
冷めた目で見られて
Sameta me de mirarete
Looked at with cold eyes,
乾いた時代の風に吹かれている
Kawaita jidai no kaze ni fukareteiru
I'm blown by the wind of a dry age
不安な 心と勇気が
Fuan na, kokoro to yuuki ga
Feelings of doubt and courage
背中合わせになっている
senaka awase ni natteiru
are back to back
だけど今なら夢をこの手で叶えてみせるよ
dakedo ima nara yume wo, kono te de kanaete miseru yo
but I'll make these dreams come true now with my own hands.
傷ついて壊れそうな日も
Kizutsuite koware sou na hi mo
The days where I'm hurt and about to break,
涙して困らせる日も
Namidashite komaraseru hi mo
the days where I cry and trouble you
あるけれど僕達はそれを
aru keredo bokura wa sore wo
They all exist, but we will
超えていくんだ誰より
koete ikunda dare yori...
get over it heading higher
上を目指して
ue wo mezashite!
than anyone else!
I really want a guy who can play to join...
Hey, let's put a new poster up!
One that'll attract more attention.
We'll put a really hard tsumego on it,
and ask people who can solve it to come!
I don't care if they're strong or not any more!
The Tenth Match
The Third Member
Chemistry Lab
Shindou-kun!
The new poster you put up to get members...
...you put a tsumego on it right!?
Uh... Yeah
What about it, Tsutsui-san?
Looking for
new Go club Members!
Q: White to go, what is the key spot to kill Black?
Someone answered it!
Look! And it's right too!
There is someone who can play!
This problem is for an upper-kyu
player, so he's definitely strong!
So all we have to do is find him!
I'm starting to see a beacon of hope.
If we go around all the classes asking...
Yeah! Definitely!
Umm... I...
know the person who wrote that.
W-Who!?
How do you know?
Because... I was watching.
So who is it!? Who!
A name! A name!
I think... Mitani-kun from class 3.
Why didn't you ask him to come to the club!
Well, if he wants to join, he'll come himself.
Since he hasn't come, that
means he doesn't want to join.
So you drag him here whether he likes it or not!
You're so stupid!
But I'm not a Go club member.
What!? Fujisaki-san you're a Go club member!
Chemistry Lab
Oh man, this is why Akari is...
What!? I'm going home!
Are you sure you shouldn't go after her?
She'll be fine tomorrow.
That's the kind of person she is.
But... Mitani of Class 3... I don't know him.
Oh well, I'll try asking him tomorrow.
Yeah, please do.
'Cause we want to find a third person,
and go to the tournament again...
After all, we may have been disqualified,
but we did win against Kaiou Junior High.
Not this again...
I won because of my opponent's mistake.
Shindou-kun won because
he got into a lucky streak.
Even Touya Akira came to challenge you!
Yeah, yeah, lucky streak.
You're laughing too much.
Speaking of Touya,  he's in Kaiou Junior High right?
I wonder if he's in the Go club too...
No way.
Why?
Because... Touya Akira's strength is...
Shindou-kun, you don't know
what an Insei is do you?
Insei?
They're children who place themselves
under the guidance of the Japanese Go
Institute's Pro preparation program.
They're being trained, so no
matter how strong they are...
...they're forbidden from
entering amateur tournaments.
I hear there are former Insei in Kaiou's Go Club.
There are many who give up on becoming
pro, and quit the Insei program.
But, Touya isn't an Insei.
In other words, to him, even an Insei is too weak.
Even an Insei...
Oh! Glass stones chip easily so be careful.
Well, there's no way Touya would join the Go club.
Maybe it was a too farfetched a goal to beat Touya...
Hikaru!
Before Touya, first you have to....
Yeah, first, I have to beat Kaiou's third board.
No, before that..
first you have to win against Tsutsui-san.
Oh yeah.
Hmm? What is it?
Oh, nothing.
Good point about Tsutsui-san...
but before that, we have to find a third member.
What will I do...
Chinese Noodles
but, let's eat some Ramen first.
You really like Ramen don't you Hikaru?
I think it's the greatest food in the world.
Hey go make a delivery.
Okay. The Go salon behind us right?
Hikaru! Hikaru! They said Go Salon!
What about it?
I wanna go there!
Hikaru plays every day at the Go club!
But I haven't played at all lately!
Speaking of, there's a really good
Junior High kid at the Go salon.
I played him once, but I didn't stand a chance.
Chinese Noodles
Thanks for the food!
A strong Junior High kid?
Hikaru! Hurry! Hurry!
Who is it?
That way!
At a place like this?
Delivery!
Isn't this a little scary?
But it's a Go salon right?
Here you go 700 yen right?
Thanks!
Are you going to play?
500 yen for children.
Hikaru! Over there!
Must be him...
Hey! Shuu-san! Can you bring some tea over here!?
I can hear you without yelling.
If you're going to watch, sit down.
Here's some tea.
Oh, thanks.
Hikaru that child!
What?
He's cheating at seichi!
[note: After a game of Go is over, you form the territory you've conquered
into squares to make it easier to count. What Mitani is doing here, is cheating,
and making his squares larger than it should be at the cost of his opponents.]
He's moving the stones purposefully to increase
his territory, and decrease his opponents!
I have no idea what you're talking about.
White, 46 moku.
Black, 44 moku.
I was a little short... I thought
I was winning though...
Man...
Here ya go.
What? Going home already?
That's three straight losses now!
It's time for me to go home already.
I told my parents I'm at a club.
Man...
A school uniform...
...is he from Haze Jr. High?
Could he be...
Sai! What was that guy's name?
That Akari was talking about.
Mitani?
Hey kid! You're playing too right?
Sit down. I'll play Ban-go or Me-go with you.
[note: Ban-go is where you bet a set amount of money on the
game, and Me-go is where the money you win or lose is
dependent on the territory difference at the end of the game.]
Ban-Go? Me-Go?
Hey what are you trying to do!
It's his first time here!
Then Shuu-san let's play!
It's looked down upon for an employee to gamble...
Hey! Are you... Mitani...
Do you know him, son?
He's making quite a bit of money...
...especially as of late.
I can't imagine him getting stronger so suddenly...
No, no, Mitani-kun really is a strong player.
So he is Mitani!
Hikaru!
Let's ask him to join the Go club.
It's sad that he's cheating at Seichi as a child.
Have him join the Go club...
and Hikaru, in my place, give him a stern word...
Mitani! Hey Mitani!
Wait up Mitani!
Did you want something?
If you can play Go, come to the Go club.
I'm not going.
Because you can't make any money at the club?
Yeah.
You were cheating when you were
counting territories, weren't you?
You have good eyes.
Is there something you need money for?
Not really.
Ever since the economy went on a down turn,
my parents stopped giving me an allowance.
Then come play at the Go club! It's free!
There are CDs and shirts I want you know?
Cya.
Just once! Just come once okay!?
Hey you!
This way! This way!
Tsutsui-san, I brought Mitani!
Mitani-kun?
Come on in!
Try playing a game against Mitani!
He's really strong! He'll make a great member!
Is this guy always this forceful?
Hikaru, you forced him to come?
But you came all this way so...
Go club huh? Not too exciting...
You solved the Tsumego on
the poster right? Play a game!
I guess one game's okay.
Let's start then.
Yeah!
I'll take black.
Then, Good luck.
Yeah, sure.
Hey, umm, there's a tournament soon.
A Go tournament, for Junior High Schools.
And?
It's a team tournament.
3 people to a team, the side with 2 wins, wins.
So?
So, if you join we'll have 3!
Are you the type that thinks a lot?
Oh, sorry!
This child has quite a bit of potential.
He makes honest and good moves.
If he plays against Hikaru they would both grow... but...
Why did he do what he did yesterday?
What was he trying to get through his cheating?
There's nothing in the world worth
possessing at the cost of disgracing a match.
It's a matter of timing if I want to capture territory here...
Should I surround the center or stop the right side?
Hey!
S-Sorry.
Before going to the lower right, I should play here first.
Mitani-kun will respond to that on the
upper-right, so then I'll stop the right side.
Okay, Tsuke!
Your loss.
I haven't played yet.
I just hit it against the side.
It's your loss because you
made 2 consecutive moves.
Cya.
H-hey!
Are you going there again today?
It's more fun than this place.
So that's the kind of guy he is, how about it?
Wait, do you mean!?
Yeah.
I found him at a Go salon yesterday but...
he cheated after the game like this...
Cheated!?
At Seichi!?
But he's strong right!? He'll make a good member!
But...
what if he cheats during the tournament?
He has the nerves to do it at
a Go Salon against adults.
He probably wouldn't hesitate
to against kids in a tournament.
His opponent won't notice, we won't notice.
But, can you form a team with a guy like that?
I'll make him stop!
Make him stop?
Yes, we'll make him stop Hikaru!
We can't let him do things like that!
He's still a child!
Let's go after him Hikaru! Right now!
Hey, Mitani-kun.
We'll be done soon, so can you play him later?
Oh?
A kid comes here?
Rare these days.
This kid is strong.
So, what happened?
You went to the barbecue place
with Akemi-chan, and then?
We took a picture!
She put her face right up like this!
You're only going to have
girls while you have money.
He's not very good.
He can barely hold the stones too.
Just because you won at the horse races...
With komi, I win by 3 and a half moku.
Here ya go.
Thanks much.
I'm not Akemi-chan, but...
Dake-san I love you!
Anyways, play him Mitani-kun.
Sorry he's a little drunk.
For the game.
He should probably place 4 stones...
Would 2 stones be enough for him?
2 stones is a little lacking.
Why don't you give him at least 3.
I can't place stones against a kid!
Even match. Even match.
Wanna bet on it?
Sure I'm fine with it. Ban-Go?
How's 500 yen a game sound?
Same as before is fine.
But you're a Junior High kid.
You have 10,000 yen?
Hey, Mitani-kun, you usually play 1000 yen.
I have it, just barely.
But it's 10,000 yen.
Kids these days.
Well I'm gonna nigiri then.
Make him stop...
Sai, how!?
I don't know.
But I'm sure we can do it...
we have to make him stop!
Akemi-chan I love you.
You hold the stones well.
Compared to you I do.
Oops!
Sorry about that!
Mitani!
どこにあるのかな
Dokoni aru no kana?
Where is it?
ボクだけの宝物
bokudakeno takaramono
The treasure that belongs to me
今　大きな冒険へ
ima ookina bouken e
Now with a great adventure...
やわらかな日差し
yawarakana hizashi
the gentle sunlight
旅立ちの予感
tabitachi no yokan
a feeling of departure
空も花も　ホラ 笑っている
sora mo hana mo hora waratte iru
The sky and the flower are both laughing!
この先には何が待つのだろう
kono saki ni wa nani ga matsu no darou?
I wonder what waits ahead for me.
深呼吸
shinkokyuu
take a deep breath...
夢の扉にそっと手をかけて　行こう
yume no tobira ni soutto te wo kakete... ikou!
place your hand gently on the door to your dreams... let's go!
風に吹かれながら
kaze ni fukare nagara
Because I was blown by the wind!
心揺らしながら
kokoro yurashi nagara
Because my heart was touched!
真っ白な地図を片手に持ちながら
masshiro na chizu wo katate ni mochinagara
holding my belongings in one hand
風に吹かれながら
kaze ni fukare nagara
Because I was blown by the wind!
明日を描きながら
asu wo kaki nagara
Because I can't cause strife!
遠くまで　何処まで
tooku made, doko made?
far away
たどり着けるまで
tadori tsukeru made
until I reach that place...
絶対負けないよ　絶対泣かないよ
zettai makenaiyo zettai nakanaiyo
I won't lose! I won't lose!
この夢を叶えるその日までは
kono yume wo kanaeru sono hi made wa
Until the day that I make this dream come true!
あの空は笑っていた
ano sora wa waratteita
That sky is fleeting!
あの花はも笑っていた
ano hana mo waratteita
That flower is fleeting!
ボクもいつか笑うから
boku mo itsuka warau kara
Some day I will laugh with you!
どんな壁も越えるから
donna kabe mo koeru kara
I will surpass any obstacle!
もう　何も何も　コワクナイ
mou nani mo... nani mo kowakunai
I'm not afraid of anything any more!
Umezawa Yukari's
Go Go Igo!
Go! Go! Igo!
Teacher Yukari
Mai
Yuuki
P
o
k
!
How can I place it well?
In order to play the stone properly...
Mai wants to know too!
You sandwich it between your index and
middle fingers, and place it like this.
Sandwich
it
between
your
index
and
midddle
fingers.
hmm...
drop
Yuuki-kun, you've always got it
reversed. Your figners are wrong.
You're putting your middle finger under the stone.
Yuuki is holding the stone the other way.
I guess it's pretty hard.
To be continued
Have you heard the phrase "You don't know
the outcome of a match until it's over"?
Cheating at Seichi takes advantage of that trust...
it's the most horrifice thing you can do.
Sai it's a trap! Mitani's been tricked!
It won't go to Seichi, he'll resign.