胸の鼓動　熱くゆるがす
mune no kodou atsuku yurugasu
My heart walks, searching for something exciting
刺激求めて歩く My Heart
shigeki motomete aruku MY HEART
That will passionately sway the beating in my chest.
時間だけが過ぎる毎日じゃ
jikan dake ga sugiru mainichi jya
If I just wait for the time to pass everyday.
変化はない
henka ha nai
nothing's going to change.
Woo Wooo
止まらない　信じたい　進みたい
tomaranai shinjitai susumitai
I won't stop. I want to believe. I want to move forward.
自分の力試す My Life
jibun no chikara tamesu MY LIFE
I will test my strength during my life.
でも早歩きしたって見落とすだけ
demo hayaaruki shitatte miotosudake
But even if I walk faster.
I will definitely lose track of
そう確実に
sou kakujitsu ni
the important things.
Baby for you...
明日は明日の風が吹く
ashita ha ashita no kaze ga fuku
Tomorrow's wind will blow tomorrow.
それでも　今この瞬間を強く生きたい
soredemo
but I want to make the most out of this moment now.
ima kono shunkan wo tsuyoku ikitai
It's fantasy
さまよったとしても
samayotta to shitemo
Even if I'm wandering,
見たことない世界でも
mitakotonai sekai demo
even if I'm in a strange new world,
何よりも 自分を信じ立ち向かおう
nani yori mo jibun wo shinji tachimukaou
I'll stand up to it,
believing in myself more than anything else.
It's destiny
どんな場所にいても
donna basho ni itemo
No matter where I am,
つつむ空は一つだから
tsutsumu sora ha hitotsu dakara
I'm surrounded by the same sky.
ねぇ　もっと 翼広げて
nee motto tsubasa hirogete
so I'll be able to fly
羽ばたけるよね
habatakeruyone
with my wings spread out.
Did you really think this would work?
You underestimated me.
I won't lose, not to the likes of you, Isumi-kun.
Last year, my determination to beat
Ochi was what let me get back up
after losing three straight games
to Shindou, Waya, and Fuku.
"My Go is supporting me."
"I'll believe in my own strength."
I was able to tell myself that back then.
But will I be able to say the same thing
here in the Chinese Go Institute?
Will my Go support me?
The Sixty-Seventh Match
Isumi Tested
Don't lose courage.
If I go to Japan from here without confidence,
I won't stand a chance in the pro exams.
Waya, Shindou, Ochi... I won't be able
to look them in the eye again!
Isumi-kun, hey.
Yes?
Phone call.
Phone call? For me?
Thank you.
Hello?
Shinichirou!
Dad!
Call us if you're going to stay in China.
The only reason we weren't panicking
was because Sakurano-san called us.
Sorry, there was a lot going on, I forgot.
I don't mind if you want to do it, but...
how long are you going to be there?
Sakurano-san said three or four days, is she right?
Shinichirou!
I'll be here until the pro exam starts.
Yeah, two months.
Two months!?
If I don't lose confidence here, but instead gain it,
I'll be able to face the pro exams...
maybe even the world of the pros.
Yang Hai-san, umm...
Oh, you came.
I told you I wouldn't earlier but...
Use that bed.
Yes. Thank you. I won't be troubling you.
You have a Go board in your room?
Yeah.
I'm glad I came here instead of going to the hotel
I'll be able to study at night if there's
a Go board in the room.
Well, well. You really are studious.
Well, I'll leave the Go board out, so
use it to replay games or whatever.
Thank you.
I'll just be fiddling with my computers.
Isumi-kun, do you use computers?
No, not at all.
Oh
How long are you going to be here?
Two months is my plan.
Oh? Did you play anyone today?
I played a child called Le Ping and... I lost.
Le Ping!? You lost to him!?
It was a league match, with an
hour and a half on the clock.
Le Ping laughed mockingly at me.
Tsk. You should have crushed him.
He laughed at you mockingly? That brat.
Isumi-kun, come here.
Sit down. We're playing a game.
I'm testing you.
I'm sorry, but if you can't even beat Le
Ping, I can't let you stay in this room.
I'm going to have to ask you to leave.
Make me leave? Yang Hai-san...
Come on, place two stones.
Oh no, it's 7:30 already.
You can use whatever's around, Isumi-kun.
Okay.
I'll be sleeping, go on ahead without me.
He's about as strong as Le Ping.
He has a lot of potential.
He never told me to get out.
I guess he accepted me.
The game I played against Yang Hai-san last night
with two stones, was not played for win or loss.
It was a tutoring game from a top class player.
I saw you played Wang Xing today.
Yes.
Even Hua Song Li-san joined in for the
discussion afterwards. I was amazed.
They're top players in China,
even I had heard of them.
Both of them came back from a match today.
The top pros in China sure are young,
it's not like Japan at all.
Yeah, the younger players start dragging
you down by the time you're past thirty.
That's why you're over if you don't
work hard during your teens.
But that Le Ping...
Le Ping?
What do you want to do tonight? Wanna play?
Yes! Please!
Tomorrow's a day off. So I'll play against
you for however long you want.
Li Lao Shi isn't around on the days off,
and not many people are playing.
Isumi-san!
Zhao-kun! You're back!
Y-Yeah...
I stayed here. I wanted to play
you again, so I stayed here.
I'll be here for a while...
Zhao Shi!
Welcome back!
Le Ping!
How was your match?
I won.
Let's go outside! Let's go bowling! Bowling!
Yes, but...
Isumi-kun? He's studying here
for a while, but he sucks.
He sucks?
I played him and I owned him.
He can't beat me no matter
how much he studies here.
I can't let that comment go.
Yang Hai-san.
Le Ping, try playing Isumi-kun again.
This time your going to lose.
No way!
I'm playing with Zhao today because
we have the day off!
You play enough during the week.
But Yang Hai Xian Sheng, all you do is play on your computer!
Never mind what I do.
Then if I play Isumi-kun again and beat
him, will you stop yelling at me?
Fine, but if you lose to Isumi-kun,
be more studious.
Let's go, Zhao Shi!
Le Ping!
We'll have the match in a week. Don't forget.
Whatever.
Sai...
Shindou?
Nase!
I heard you haven't been going to the matches.
Waya was worried...
Shindou!
Shindou...
Le Ping and I both came from Yun'an province.
When I went to Yun'an province for a match,
both of Le Ping's parents asked
me how Le Ping was doing.
They were quite worried as to how
their only precious son was doing.
With his current grades, he's going to get
sent back to the provinces next year!
Isumi-kun, teach him a lesson
so that he'll start studying.
I'm sorry for using you like this.
Don't worry. I have to thank Le Ping then.
Thanks to him you're playing
against me every night.
But that gives me all the more reason to beat him.
Come on! I set up the match because
I thought you could win.
On a different note, how did the
game you lost to him go?
I lost to Zhao the day before it.
Maybe I was too determined not to lose
against a small child twice in a row.
I wasn't able to play like myself.
I tried to pretend that the game
was part of the pro exam.
But instead of improving my game,
it just made me too aggressive.
How did your pro exams go last year?
I was bothered by something someone else said,
and I made a great mistake during a game.
I lost track of myself, and it took some time
before I was able to get back on my feet.
And the three losses I had in the
meantime caused me to fail...
You're bad at controlling your emotions.
Don't worry about what the people around you say,
Irritation, eagerness, worry, aggression, tension,
pressure. Don't let these emotions control you.
Thats the most important lesson for you.
Just look at the stones. You can do this
with practice and determination.
Your personality doesn't matter.
This is a skill that you can learn.
A skill that I can learn!
I had never thought of it that way...
I can learn to control my emotions!?
You'll have a great weapon in your arsenal
once you learn how to do that.
Huh? Game between Le Ping and Isumi-kun?
What are you talking about?
Yang Hai Xian Sheng is training Isumi-kun?
Why?
Who said that Isumi-kun sucked? I played
him and I think he's better than Le Ping.
He's started to calm down lately.
He seemed a little nervous before.
Cheng Yi lost to Isumi-kun in a league match!
Isumi-kun's not here.
It's time already!
Man! I would be at the arcade already
if it wasn't for this stupid match.
He sure is late, what is he doing?
Yang Hai Xian Sheng said that the
match would be at around 1:30.
Are we going to be late for the match?
We're fine. It starts around 1:40 so let's
relax and go at the last minute.
There's no risk at all to you in today's game, so take it easy.
Not at all. I can't look you in the
face if I lose, Yang Hai-san.
If that were to happen, I wouldn't
feel comfortable staying here.
No. I wouldn't feel comfortable staying
in the Chinese Go Institute.
I'd have to go back to Japan feeling
wretched about myself.
Hey! You don't have to pressure
yourself that much!
You haven't changed, Isumi-kun.
Yes I have. I can look at myself from
the third person despite that.
When I create another personality
inside me, I start to calm down.
Okay. Let's go then.
Your late! It's already 1:40!
I only said "around" 1:30.
Man!
Isumi-kun, let's have a private conversation.
If I talk to you in Japanese, Le Ping might
think that I'm telling you a plan.
Yang Hai-san?
And I told him to come here 10 minutes before the
match starts, so he's angry at having to wait.
You know how emotions can
affect your game play, right?
Yang Hai-san! Never do that again!
Sorry, Le Ping!
Oh crap! Isumi-kun's a serious guy!
Sorry I was late. I'll take twice the amount
of time I was late away from my time.
What good does it do for me to make Isumi-kun emotional!?
Oh, it's about to start.
Ah! I'm an idiot! An idiot!
What are you doing, Yang Hai-san?
Man, not only does he get here
late, he's playing really slow, too.
What are you doing!? Don't waste
so much time on your first move!
You don't have that much time!
I'll have to apologize to Isumi-kun
if he loses because of me...
It's not that I didn't have faith in Isumi-kun...
it's that I wanted some insurance...
There's still some weakness in White's
territory on the lower right.
Isumi-kun is preparing so that
he can make an attack on it.
Le Ping would have to cover his stone.
But Isumi-kun's move was quite powerful.
The section proceeded just as I had expected.
He's calm.
Isumi-kun was always calm when playing against
me, no matter how much trouble he was in.
So, he can always play a game like this so long as he plays calmly.
Isumi-kun...
He played a move that I didn't expect. That's
a great Tesuji for the end game, Le Ping.
Yup, that's right.
Though it is a skill you can learn, it will
take him some time to master it.
But it seems like he has gotten past a major obstacle.
Game's over.
Isumi-kun wins by two and a half moku.
I was panicking because of what you
did before the game, Yang Hai-san!
But you played calmly.
No, not at all.
Isumi-kun!
Le Ping!
Isumi-kun! One more game!
How many games of 10 second
Go did you think we played?
He's upset that you're about even.
He wants to be better than you.
B-But!
Oh well, looks like there was no need for me
to tell him to be more studious if he lost.
Come on! Hurry!
Alright! Alright!
I never expected Le Ping to drag
Isumi-kun to the game room.
I'll be gone for a bit then.
You're playing Zhao next.
Zhao?
Zhao's idol strap is mine if you win.
But if you lose he gets my MD player.
Good luck.
What!?
Hurry!
Le Ping's been clinging onto Isumi-kun,
and studying Go a lot.
He was probably urged on by looking
at Isumi-kun's motivation.
We have to thank Isumi-kun.
I'm very glad that he didn't leave early.
Hello? Dad? It's me.
Can you apply for the pro exam for me?
Yeah, I'll be home a week before the pro exam,
With confidence to walk bravely into
it... no, into the world of the pros.
Yes! To the world that everyone
has been in for a year now!
Ring
My
Bell
noizu darake no mune de
ノイズだらけの胸で
I listen to my fate through the din in my heart.
noizu darake no mune deunmei wo kikiwakeru
ノイズだらけの胸で運命を聴きわける
It occurs to me.
hirameku
閃く
hiramekuyume ha watashi no naka demezame o matteta
閃く夢は私の中で目覚めを待ってた
My dream was waiting for the time
to wake up within me.
mezame o matteta
閃く夢は私の中で目覚めを待ってた
Music
Is
My
Thing
I can be more like myself
jibun rashiku nareru
自分らしくなれる
Music
In
My
Heart
ときめきならして
Let the pounding of my heart be heard
tokimeki narashite
ときめきならして
Music
Is
My
Thing
karada wo ugokasu
体を動かす
I move my body
karada wo ugokasu
体を動かす
Music
In
My
Heart
Feel the light
hikari wo kanjite
光を感じて
Music
Is
My
Thing
shiro to kuro de egaku
白と黒で描く
I draw with black and white
shiro to kuro de egaku
白と黒で描く
Music
In
My
Heart
owaranai haamoni
The unending Harmony
終わらないハーモニー
owaranai haamoni