Fujiwarano Sai, a Go player from the Heian period
has passed through time and returned to the world in the mind of Shindou Hikaru...
in order to obtain the Hand of God.
君が今僕を支えて
Kimi ga ima boku wo sasaete
Now you are,
holding me up strong!
僕が今君を支える
boku ga ima kimi wo sasaeru
Now I am,
holding you up as well!
だから迷いながらも共に生きていこうよ
Dakara Mayoi nagara mo tomo ni ikite ikou yo
So let us now, while wandering live together
未来へと
Mirai e to...
towards the future
Elite-Fansubs presents
Hikaru no Go
仲間と戯れ　それなりで居ても
Nakama to tawamaure sorenaride itemo
Even when I'm capricing with my friends,
もの足りなさを感じてしまう
mono tari na sa wo kanjite shimau
I feel an emptiness in my heart.
冷めた目で見られて
Sameta me de mirarete
Looked at with cold eyes,
乾いた時代の風に吹かれている
Kawaita jidai no kaze ni fukareteiru
I'm blown by the wind of a dry age
不安な 心と勇気が
Fuan na, kokoro to yuuki ga
Feelings of doubt and courage
背中合わせになっている
senaka awase ni natteiru
are back to back
だけど今なら夢をこの手で叶えてみせるよ
dakedo ima nara yume wo, kono te de kanaete miseru yo
but I'll make these dreams come true now with my own hands.
傷ついて壊れそうな日も
Kizutsuite koware sou na hi mo
The days where I'm hurt and about to break,
涙して困らせる日も
Namidashite komaraseru hi mo
the days where I cry and trouble you
あるけれど僕達はそれを
aru keredo bokura wa sore wo
They all exist, but we will
超えていくんだ誰より
koete ikunda dare yori...
get over it heading higher
上を目指して
ue wo mezashite!
than anyone else!
It's me.
Kaiou's third board is me.
Shindou...
Why are you?
The Thirteenth Match
Each of Their Decision
Hey, isn't that Touya?
He's wearing a uniform from Kaiou!
I read about him in a Go magazine once...
Everyone's waiting for him to join
the pros because he's a genius.
What's a guy like that doing here?
Isn't he an Insei?
I thought Inseis couldn't go
to Amateur competitions.
Touya is a member of Kaiou!?
Hey, aren't we playing Kaiou in the first round?
Touya said he is the third board.
What!? Third board!?
I don't want to play him!
So you're the Shindou Hikaru that
Touya's always talking about.
Someone that even Touya looks up to,
I look forward to your game with Touya.
Hmm...
So you're from Kaiou.
I heard you guys are good,
but you lost to Haze Junior earlier?
Who are you?
We'll be playing Kaiou in the second round.
I think I'll win too.
Oh wow.
How do you plan on winning
against Kishimoto-kun!?
Hitaka!
He plans on winning by cheating.
Tsutsui-san, Mitani-kun wouldn't do that.
Tsutsui?
Oh, the guy that got lucky against us earlier!
He was so angry.
He lost because he missed something really simple.
Winning by cheating, or winning by luck.
What a great team Haze has.
Mitani-kun, right?
You're just a freshman who's only playing
first board to try to con a win, right?
What!?
What do you mean by con a win!?
Mitani is...
he's only a freshman, but he's
ten times better than I am!
He is our first board!
Don't underestimate him.
Nice to meet you.
I am the first board, Kishimoto.
I look forward to playing you in the second round.
Let's make it a game suitable for the first board.
Yeah... Talk to us after winning the first round.
Yeah... we have to win the first round.
I only told the truth...
you're our first board so...
you're good so...
don't cheat.
Then let's begin now.
Yeah.
Anyone currently in a game,
please stop and put your stones away.
Well, will each school go to your assigned seats as they are announced?
First is Ayu Junior High against
Hamachi Junior High in seat A
Kawahagi Junior High against
Tai Junior High in seat B
Iwana Junior High against
Haze Junior High in seat C
Kaiou Junior High against
Sawara Junior High in seat D
I'm black.
Good luck.
He's fast.
Oh no!
Look, I'm so good.
Even Tsutsui-san, who dislikes me,
said that I was ten times better.
Let's make it a game suitable for the first board.
Fine, we'll see.
I resign.
Already!?
I'm going to go watch Kaiou.
The old men from the Go salon developed
their own style of play but him...
Junior High clubs are this good!?
I resign.
Thank you for the game.
Did you learn anything? Mitani-kun?
I see...
This guy thinks that I'm a weak little freshman
who's only playing first board for strategic purposes too...
That handshake was just to be polite.
He doesn't care about his game against me at all.
Shindou's not doing well in his game right now.
Tsutsui-san, I promise you.
I'll stop cheating for a while.
I want to play against Kishimoto of Kaiou.
So don't you lose!
Damn, I'm not doing well.
I've gotta do something!
Haha, I've just about won!
You laughed!?
Don't laugh until the game's actually over!
What!?
These children, they've all
changed from coming here...
Hikaru is growing... steadily.
But Hikaru isn't the only one who's growing...
Touya Akira he is as well...
White 72 and a half moku.
Black 56 moku.
I won!
By 16 and a half moku!
Thanks for the game.
Thanks for the game!
I resign.
Thanks for the game.
You took your time.
Mr. Yun!
I thought it would calm myself down a bit.
Haze Junior High won 3-0.
You saw Shindou's game?
How was it?
You'll know once you play him.
We'd like to break for lunch now.
The afternoon session will begin at 1.
Hitaka, wanna go grab lunch?
Yeah, sure.
Hey, let's grab Touya too.
Hitaka
Can I talk to you for a bit?
What is it?
Hikaru! Lunch!
I'll pass.
Pass?
Hikaru!
That was a splendid come back.
Yeah! Wasn't it great?
It wasn't luck!
It was my strength! Mine!
I'm a lot better than I was before!
But you still can't beat Tsutsui-san.
Your next opponent is finally Touya.
I'm playing him!
You don't have to come out and say it...
I don't care how much Touya wants to play you.
The team from Haze Junior High
is Tsutsui-san, Mitani, and me.
You're not a part of it Sai.
I know.
Can't Touya come after I've gotten better?
And? What do you want to
talk about Kishimoto-kun?
About Touya getting bullied?
Did it really happen?
Yeah.
Touya was a loner in the club...
They wanted to either shame
Touya, or chase him out of the club.
Damn!
4-9 huh?
But no matter how shamed he was,
Touya probably wouldn't have left the club.
Probably not.
I saw it too.
The look on Touya's face as he faced Mr. Yun.
Weren't you going to make me third board!?
You said it yourself that I was the only
one who stood a chance against Shindou!
Then I'll quit the club after this tournament!
Touya...
Teacher!
Fine...
you're the third board.
He knew how selfish he was acting,
so it must have been hard on him too.
Touya's quitting the club?
After today?
Well, I'm sure the club'll
settle down with Touya gone.
Yeah right
I'm sure you're disappointed.
You wanted to play against
Touya more than anyone else.
Touya got bullied...
I guess he had it coming.
He only thinks of himself.
But Touya isn't the type of
person who's disliked by others.
He probably swallowed his
pride to become third board.
He should of course be first board.
He's only thinking about you...
Sai...
You play.
Is it okay?
You said that you wanted to play.
You play.
Hikaru!
You were here?
The second round's about to begin.
You sure you don't want any food?
I'll eat after the tournament.
What about Tsutsui-san and Mitani?
They're playing, against each other.
Playing!?
Those two!?
Mitani-kun's excited.
He says he's going to gather his strength
and stomp down on the Kaiou first board.
Tsutsui-san's just as motivated too.
First and second boards really should be like that.
So you should be excited too, Hikaru.
Let's go back, the afternoon's going to begin.
I'll be waiting then.
Hikaru...
I told you... you play.
He is very determined,
if you worry about me, you'll lose.
Yes, I'll probably have to go all out on him.
Oh, Hikaru.
What were you doing?
You haven't eaten?
Can you really play Kaiou without eating anything?
Please stop any games you're playing.
We're about to start the second round.
Schools that have been called upon
should go to the seat they're assigned.
Seat A is Kaiou Junior High
against Haze Junior High.
Seat B is Ayu Junior High against Tai Junior High.
Come on, let's go.
Now for the girls.
Seat F Kaiou Junior High
against Sawara Junior High.
Kaiou Junior High and Haze Junior High right?
Shindou-kun.
We came all this way, aimed for Kaiou.
It doesn't matter if we lose, let's just do our best.
Mitani is here too after all.
But I might win out of luck again.
夢に見ていたシアワセなら
Yume ni miteita shiawase nara
I thought that someone would bring me,
誰かが運んでくれると思ってた
Dareka ga hakonde kureru to omotteta
the happiness that I dreamed of.
急ぎ足の街で
Isogi ashi no machi de
In a quick paced city,
言い訳ばかり
iiwake bakari...
all I'm doing is listing off excuses,
みんなも同じとうそ ぶいてた
Minna mo onaji to usobuiteta
and lying to myself, that everyone was doing the same.
本当にキミはいま　満足してるの？
hontou ni kimi wa ima manzokushiteru no?
Are you really satisfied right now?
心の真ん中 見抜かれたようで
kokoro no mannaka minukaretayoude
It feels as if you've straight through my heart.
あなたと出会えなかったら
Anata to deaenakattara
If i had not met you,
偽った笑顔のまま
Itsuwatta egao no mama!
I would still only have a false smile!
うわべの態度や言葉を
Uwabe no taido ya kotoba wo
My words and disagreements
繰り返したね
kurikaeshita ne
would only have been superficial.
あなたの瞳の力で
anata no hitomi no chikara de
With the power of your gaze,
私は変わってゆこう
watashi wa kawatte yukou
I am starting to change!
昨日の揺らいだ気持ちを
Kinou no yuraida kimochi wo
In order to cast off
脱ぎ捨てるために...
nugisuteru tame ni
the swaying feelings of yesterday.
Umezawa Yukari's
Go Go Igo!
Go! Go! Igo!
December Second, 2001.
Hikaru no Go, Beginners Go Class.
Today, we're at the Japanese Go Institute.
We're going to participate in the Hikaru
no Go, Beginners Go Class today.
Yuuki
Mai
Let's go then.
Hikaru no Go Junior Beginners Go Class.
Between the morning and afternoon, more than
500 children gathered in the Japanese Go Institute.
We came on to the stage, and were
surprised by the number of participants.
Now let me introduce to you.
Yuki and I went up on the
stage and introduced ourselves.
I'm Mai
I'm Yuuki.
Once the class started, Teacher Yukari,
Teacher Yukari, and various other
pros will teach you the game!
and various other Pros taught us how to play the
game in a way that even beginners can understand.
Other than the club,
you could win gifts through the raffle,
[note: "Yuugen no Ma" (The Room of Artistic
Epitome) would be a rough translation. Yuugen is
an artistic epitome in Japan, and the room named
"Yugen no Ma" (The Room of Artistic Epitome) is
the room in which the top pro games are played in.]
or visit the "Yuugen no Ma" and it was a lot of fun.
Look at the "Yuugen no Ma"
Please come if you get a chance!
Thank you to all of the pros who came!
To be continued.
I finally get another chance to play you.
I can't see it unless I play him myself...
I want to know...
the gap between him and I.
Touya's too busy chasing after me, that he can't see Hikaru's strength!
And I thought I saw the
hand of god in you earlier...