胸の鼓動　熱くゆるがす
mune no kodou atsuku yurugasu
My heart walks, searching for something exciting
刺激求めて歩く My Heart
shigeki motomete aruku MY HEART
That will passionately sway the beating in my chest.
時間だけが過ぎる毎日じゃ
jikan dake ga sugiru mainichi jya
If I just wait for the time to pass everyday.
変化はない
henka ha nai
nothing's going to change.
Woo Wooo
止まらない　信じたい　進みたい
tomaranai shinjitai susumitai
I won't stop. I want to believe. I want to move forward.
自分の力試す My Life
jibun no chikara tamesu MY LIFE
I will test my strength during my life.
でも早歩きしたって見落とすだけ
demo hayaaruki shitatte miotosudake
But even if I walk faster.
I will definitely lose track of
そう確実に
sou kakujitsu ni
the important things.
Baby for you...
明日は明日の風が吹く
ashita ha ashita no kaze ga fuku
Tomorrow's wind will blow tomorrow.
それでも　今この瞬間を強く生きたい
soredemo
but I want to make the most out of this moment now.
ima kono shunkan wo tsuyoku ikitai
It's fantasy
さまよったとしても
samayotta to shitemo
Even if I'm wandering,
見たことない世界でも
mitakotonai sekai demo
even if I'm in a strange new world,
何よりも 自分を信じ立ち向かおう
nani yori mo jibun wo shinji tachimukaou
I'll stand up to it,
believing in myself more than anything else.
It's destiny
どんな場所にいても
donna basho ni itemo
No matter where I am,
つつむ空は一つだから
tsutsumu sora ha hitotsu dakara
I'm surrounded by the same sky.
ねぇ　もっと 翼広げて
nee motto tsubasa hirogete
so I'll be able to fly
羽ばたけるよね
habatakeruyone
with my wings spread out.
Everyone! Everyone watching the TV!
Long time no see!
It's Sai!
We're doing something special today by
broadcasting a Hikaru no Go side story.
It will show Hikaru when he was in the 7th grade, back when he was still cute.
So look forward to it.
Huh? Me?
I'll be... just as cool as ever of course!
After all I am the MAIN CHARACTER!
Well then, enjoy the show!
The Sixty-Fourth Match
Keichou Flowerpots
Oh man, that English teacher just wouldn't shut up.
It's because you were sleeping in his class, Hikaru.
You were asleep, too!
Man, this is so stupid.
I've had three straight losses to Mitani,
Maybe I'll ditch the Go club today.
What!? Hikaru you can't be serious!
You said you were going to train because you lost 3-0 to Kaiou in the last tournament!
Tsutsui-san's waiting for you!
Come on, Hikaru. Akari-chan must be waiting, too.
Ouch!
Sorry bout that!
It was your fault for walking there
without paying attention.
What'd you say!? I think it's because
you guys suck too much.
Where are you trying to hit the ball!?
Even I can do better, even
though I'm in the Go club.
What!? Give it your best shot.
Okay! I'll blast a homer and get rid of some stress.
Hikaru! What are you doing with that stick?
Okay! This is the baseball team's pitch!
Oh! He threw a small ball!
Oh! Wow! Wow! The ball went straight in there!
Scared now? Go club members
should stay away from here.
Shut up!
Sai! Out of the way!
It's still only one strike.
Come on!
All right!
You hit it in the wrong direction.
It's totally a foul.
Oh no.
It's Kaga!
Note: Silence a crying baby is a Japanese idiom. Meaning someone is so
horrifying that it would cause even a baby to stop crying in fear of upsetting him.
Kaga! Who can silence a crying baby!
It's Kaga...
Go! This is all your fault!
K... Kaga...
So you're the culprit.
Do you have any idea as to what you've done?
S-Sorry. It's a mess.
Your trophies...
That junk doesn't matter.
More importantly, look at this!
T-This? What about this teacup?
It's my beloved teacup that I used all the time! It's very important, you idiot!
F-Fine! I'll bring you another one tomorrow!
You'll be in for it if you get me crap.
Man...
What kind of teacups would Kaga like anyways?
I only have 200 yen left from my allowance, too...
Oh! Hikaru!
A teacup!
Eh, Really?
Where?
What!? 5,000yen!? That's so expensive!
No way. Let's look somewhere else.
What!? This is a Keichou flowerpot!?
Keichou flowerpot!?
Sai?
During the early years of the Edo,
in the Keichou period, there was a brilliant potter called Sanwa Yaemon.
I know! I know!
Oh? You do?
Flowerpots were Yaemon's specialties right?
So that's why we call flowerpots made by Yaemon, Keichou flowerpots, right?
Oh, you know a lot about this.
Hey, Sai!
It really is different!
It's beautiful, but also elegant.
You have a good eye.
Not at all.
Sai, what's wrong?
It's a rare find. How about it?
Hikaru! This is a fake.
Torajirou knew enough about Yaemon's flowerpots
to have his own unique views on them.
So I am familiar with several of them as well.
But, this...
The Indigo is rather bland,
The finish is uneven...
The shape doesn't have the class
that a work of Yaemon would.
1,500,000, and not a yen less.
1,500,000!?
For this fake!?
Hey, can I see it, too?
No! You can't!
I-I-It's not my fault! I didn't do anything!
You sure are breaking a lot of things today, Hikaru.
You may be a child, but I'm going
to have to make you pay for that.
1,500,000.
Hikaru! Come on, tell him!
This isn't a Keichou flowerpot!
You've been saying that, but do you
even know what a real one is like?
Umm... umm... ahh...
The Indigo is more brilliant, and...!
The Indigo is more brilliant, and...
The finish isn't this uneven, and most importantly...
The shape doesn't have class
You have good eyes, for a brat.
He...! He looks just like a toad
when he smiles! I hate toads!
What is the meaning of this!? It's a fake!?
The 1,500,000 was a lie!?
Oops, I said too much in front of the foolish target.
Foolish target!? Are you talking about me!?
But I like people who have an eye for things.
Hikaru! Don't get liked by people like him!
It's your fault that he has taken a liking to me!
After doing this business for awhile, you start
developing an eye for people as well as for things.
Kid. There are only two types
of people in the world.
There are people who have an eye for things, and...
idiots who don't.
Kid, I won't make you pay for that
in respect to your knowledge.
Hello?
Oh. That pot.
Oh, so they said it was worth 1,000 yen?
And what about it?
You happily paid 200,000 for it, didn't you?
You should feel ashamed for not being able to tell
the difference rather than calling to complain.
Someone like you who can't even judge the
value of things shouldn't have meddled.
Understand?
Mister!
It is grandpa's!
Hey! What do you think you're doing!?
Hey! Keep your hands off the merchandise!
But this is grandpa's! It was stolen six months ago!
That....
Sai?
Hikaru! This flowerpot...
Are you sure it was stolen?
We got broken into...
That's none of my business. Someone
came to sell it and I bought it.
I've seen this flowerpot before
in the palace in Kyoto.
That one time when Torajirou
and I went there to tutor go...
It has to be the flowerpot we saw then.
A Keichou flowerpot...
Then it's genuine?
Please! Give it back!
It may be a cheap pot, but there's
no reason for me to give it to you.
He said it's a cheap pot.
There's a secret to this flowerpot.
This man... he hasn't realized what the secret is.
Bring me money if you want it.
100,000!
Sai?
I told you. I can't stand toads.
100,000!?
But you just said it's a cheap pot!
In my store I decide the prices for everything.
And it's up to the customer
whether to buy it or not.
But...
But that's grandpa's!
Hey! What do you think you're doing!? Let go!
Are you okay?
Not at all! She broke this teacup!
Pay for it!
But you pushed her into it!
Shouldn't you worry whether she's alright or not!?
You certainly have courage when
this guy's not smiling.
Are you hurt?
No...
This teacup is worth 50,000! 50,000!
Really? I'm highly doubtful that
it's actually worth that much.
Sai. Is it?
I don't know anything about teacups.
Hikaru, look at that.
A Go board?
Yes.
It seems like this person plays Go.
And?
Come on little girl, pay up.
50,000!
What's wrong, huh?
It's no use talking to you about it, little girl.
Tell me your home phone number.
Hey, mister!
Mister, you play Go, right?
Want to play me?
You play Go aswell?
Let's play a game, with the price
of the teacup on the line.
T-That's ridiculous!
I like you even more now. All right,
I accept your challenge.
Can you really play Go like that?
H-Hey! Look at that!
This person has a fifth-dan certificate!
You can't play him at Go!
That certificate isn't fake, it's totally genuine.
W-Wait a second, I'm not sure now...
Hey, Sai!
You don't have to play if you're scared, boy.
Me!? Get scared!?
Just so that you know, I'm not going to take it easy
on you. I said that I took a liking to you, but...
I HATE self-righteous, arrogant little brats!
Hikaru!
Okay, let's play!
Sai, you can't stand his face,
right? Will you be all right?
Don't worry about it. He won't be smiling at all.
I'm playing first.
It's been awhile since I last played black.
Okay, I'm going to play now.
Hikaru, are you ready?
Yeah!
16-17, Komoku!
18-5, Hane!
8-18, Kaketsugi.
2-17, Ate!
W-Why is he so good?
Mister?
It's one sided...
It's completely one sided... I don't play
very well, but even I can see it...
The overwhelming difference in skill...
This is it...
W-What a child!
I lost... how could I lose...?
To see that old flowerpot again at a place like this...
I hear the palace was short on funds at the time.
Did someone in the palace
at the time secretly sell it?
Yaemon's flowerpot...
Both Torajirou and I were so awed by its
beauty, that our desire to play Go faded.
Hikaru, the secret to that flowerpot is...
Mister!
Switch stones with me.
What? What are you going to do?
Your captured stones, too
We'll switch sides and continue this game.
And, if I manage to turn the game around,
will you return that flowerpot to her?
W-What?
Turn this game that I resigned from around!?
There's no way you can do that!
How dare you act so cocky!?
Give it your best shot!
Let's go, Hikaru.
Okay!
16-2, Keima.
3-9, Cut.
T-Th-This...
is impossible!
Give that flowerpot back.
Really!? He's giving it back to me!?
J-Just who is he!?
I'll give you that worthless flowerpot!
Hey, mister. Can you pour the water in
that flower vase into the flowerpot?
This?
What are you going to do?
You're going to pour water in it?
Grandpa just kept it stored away, and never
used it because it was too precious.
He said he'd give it to me when I got married.
To be able to see this flowerpot again...
What deep joy I feel...
This flowerpot has, like me, survived
through a long period of time.
T-This...
Flowers are starting to appear
at the bottom of the pot...
How pretty!
A flowerpot is only a flowerpot
if it has flowers in it.
It's supposedly Yaemon's final masterpiece.
There is a special finish on it, so it looks
different from his other works
I-I've heard of it before.
This is that legendary...
T-This is mine!
Give it up!
Aren't there only two types of people in this world?
People who know the value of
things, and idiots who don't?
I guess you're an idiot who doesn't
know the value of things, mister.
Thank you!
Yeah, see ya!
Case closed!
Hikaru.
Haven't we forgotten something?
Kaga's teacup!
This thing?
Yup! It's called a Keichou teacup, and it's
a masterpiece from the early Edo period!
Those pictures of swimming fish were drawn by the
genius Yaemon, who was said to draw like a god!
This thing?
Yup! It's beautiful, and its shape
is absolutely marvelous!
It's a very rare work.
Don't fuck with me!
Ring
My
Bell
noizu darake no mune de
ノイズだらけの胸で
I listen to my fate through the din in my heart.
noizu darake no mune deunmei wo kikiwakeru
ノイズだらけの胸で運命を聴きわける
It occurs to me.
hirameku
閃く
hiramekuyume ha watashi no naka demezame o matteta
閃く夢は私の中で目覚めを待ってた
My dream was waiting for the time
to wake up within me.
mezame o matteta
閃く夢は私の中で目覚めを待ってた
Music
Is
My
Thing
I can be more like myself
jibun rashiku nareru
自分らしくなれる
Music
In
My
Heart
ときめきならして
Let the pounding of my heart be heard
tokimeki narashite
ときめきならして
Music
Is
My
Thing
karada wo ugokasu
体を動かす
I move my body
karada wo ugokasu
体を動かす
Music
In
My
Heart
Feel the light
hikari wo kanjite
光を感じて
Music
Is
My
Thing
shiro to kuro de egaku
白と黒で描く
I draw with black and white
shiro to kuro de egaku
白と黒で描く
Music
In
My
Heart
owaranai haamoni
The unending Harmony
終わらないハーモニー
owaranai haamoni