この瞳君の瞳に
kono me kimi no me ni
On this eye, this eye on yours,
映るどんなモノも
utsuru donna mono mo
everything will appear,
見極めて見せるよ 真実を
mikiwamete miseru yo shinjitsu wo
I will tell apart the truth.
Elite-Fansubs
Presents
Hikaru
Elite-Fansubs
Presents
no Go
Hikaru no Go
僕達はこの時代に
bokutachi wa kono jidai ni
We had so many dreams
どれだけの夢抱えて
dore dake no yume kakaete
In this time we live in.
涙して迷いながら
namida shite mayoi nagara
We stare at it and run towards it,
それに賭けてみてるの
sore ni kakete miteru no
even as we wander about crying.
僕は それでも 人にひけとらぬような
boku wa sore demo hito ni hiketoranu you na
Even then, I will find a deciding move.
決め手見つけ夢を手にするだろう
kimete mitsuke yume wo te ni suru darou
just as good as anyone else's, and take hold of my dreams.
この瞳君の瞳に
kono me kimi no me ni
On this eye, this eye on yours,
映るどんなモノも
utsuru donna mono mo
everything will appear.
見極めて見せるよ 真実だけ
mikiwamete miseru yo shinjitsu dake
I'll tell apart, just the truth.
たとえ現実が
tatoe genjitsu ga
Even if the truth is
きつく埋もれそうでも
kitsuku umoresou demo
so harsh it's suffocating.
こんな場所で終わる
konna basho de owaru
I'm not going to end
僕じゃない
boku janai
in a place like this.
Looks like you're not precise enough at counting.
This next match, try to force a draw.
Intentionally make the game a draw.
Intentionally?
I heard about your four way game played this morning.
But I...
No buts!
Don't waste your effort at a place like this!
Are you irritated about something?
No, I'm not.
Don't worry! Don't worry! No
one's coming up to get you.
But...
He passed the preliminaries for the pro exam.
You missed by one moku against me.
One moku...
Even if he missed by one moku, he forced
a draw on the other three right?
Isn't that good enough?
Yeah... more than enough.
I've finally seen someone grow before my eyes...
The Thirty-Fifth Match
There is Only One Winner
Huh? Forced four draws!?
Hikaru it wasn't four.
Umm... I messed one up though.
Yup.
But it was like a game, it was a lot of fun!
After I cleared one, I went to two.
After I cleared two, I went to three.
I kept leveling up.
Yup! Yup! I wanted to try too!
If it was me, I would've been able to
do 5 or even 10 instead of just 4.
If I put my mind to it I can...
But anyways, I tried out a lot of new stuff over
the summer. I'm sure I'm a lot stronger now.
Oh? You're confident.
Isumi-san, which Go Salon are we going to today?
Yeah. I forgot about it until just yesterday,
but, I'm thinking about going here.
The person I played told us about it this one time
when Waya and I went to a Go Salon together.
Oh him!
Try going here, you want to
play good players right?
Are you sure?
It might be some weird place.
He looked scary, but he seemed
nice, so we'll be fine.
Sounds good! Let's go there!
I want to meet good players.
He's changed a lot.
I wonder what opponents await us today Hikaru.
Yeah, I'm excited.
Oh! That's it!
Okay. Let's go.
Oh I'm gonna go get a drink, wait for me.
That sign...
That's...
Welcome!
Your total comes to 147 yen.
Thank you very much.
Hey! You dropped that.
Hey! Pick it up!
Damn it...
What's wrong with him.
Hey! You!
You heard me right? Don't ignore me!
Why you!
Hikaru. There's probably a reason
behind it. Leave him alone.
But!
Hey Shindou!
Hurry up. What are you doing?
Nothing.
Well hurry up.
Man I'm pissed.
What's wrong with him?
What is it?
Nothing!
Okay! I'm first board today!
U-Umm...
What is it Shindou?
Isumi-san... this is...
Yes, most of the customers aren't Japanese.
Don't just stand there, come on in.
O-Okay.
<Korean Dialog>
The guy from earlier!
Su-Young did something happen?
He suddenly started yelling at me in the store.
What language are they speaking in?
It's Korean.
Oh, they're Korean...
No wonder...
Yeah, I understand why he told
us about this place now.
Oh... so he just didn't understand
my Japanese earlier...
Did he do something?
Oh, don't worry about it.
Sorry about earlier. I feel bad
about shouting at you.
Su-Young, he honestly apologized.
Say something back to him.
This is the first time I saw a child
enter a Go Salon in Japan.
I thought Go was already dead in Japan.
Don't say that. Why don't you play against them?
Let me introduce you.
He's Hong Su-Young, and he's 12. He's my nephew
and he's visiting Japan from Korea.
He plays Go?
Yes. Su-Young is trying to become a pro in Korea.
Oh... Pro!?
Then is he an Insei of the Korean Go Institute?
We're Insei too!
Oh! So you're all Insei!
Insei?
It's the Japanese equivalent of the Kenkyuusei.
They're trying to become pro
just like you, Su-Young.
Pro?
Pro...
He must be walking the same path as Hikaru...
Oh? Japanese Insei? Sounds interesting.
Hong-kun play them.
Isumi-san, is this Korean Institute of
Go like the Japanese Institute of Go?
Yes.
Oh pros existed in Korea too. Wow...
Shindou!
And? Is Korea any good?
[note: In a recent international tournament, ALL of Japan's title
holders were defeated by the new Korean pros in the first round.]
You've gotta be kidding! You don't
know about Korean pros!?
Is it because you still think Japan's
at the top of the world right now!?
Is that what you think so lowly of Korea!?
In that case you're a total moron!
What? What's he saying?
He's angry because you said something so tactless.
Shindou... You should apologize.
Japan fell from the top a long time ago.
You're so stupid.
How am I supposed to know about other countries?
I don't even know about Japan!
Don't brag, you idiot!
Korea... Korean kenkyuusei...
aren't as soft as you people!
Huh? Soft?
Japanese Insei just aren't on the same
level as Korean Kenkyuusei.
Huh?
You'll know how soft we are if you play us.
Shindou, calm down.
Su-Young...
Japanese Go Institute
Three wins two losses. One of
which is a win by default...
Shindou
Ogata 9dan and Touya-kun were
concerned about him but...
maybe he'll get better...
What is it?
Huh? Oh the Pro Exam preliminaries.
Is there someone taking it that
you have your eyes on?
Yeah, maybe he'll get better...
Speaking of new players, Korea
keeps getting better.
Look at this. The Japan-Korea
New Players Tournament.
Yeah, Japan did horribly.
China is strong too.
Japan's lost every match in the Japan-China
Shuuei Tournament.
Though Master Touya did win in
the Japan-China Tengen match.
We were so close on the Japan-Korea
Survival Tournament.
Just when we thought Master Kaji would
win, Korea made a comeback.
Korea is just too strong...
Amano-san.
The pictures are done.
What's wrong? There's no reason to get depressed
because Japan's doing poorly.
Miss Kinouchi had an overwhelming victory
in the Japan China Women's Tournament,
and you haven't forgotten Mr. Kurata's performance
at last years Japan-Korea matches right?
I haven't forgotten,
but Japan is losing overall.
Well, we may be right now...
The Go world is just too depressing if there
aren't any good young players...
Yeah, we need new players.
A new wave to follow Kurata 6dan.
Shindou Hikaru... let's see if he transforms...
into a respected Go player of Touya Akira's class.
I'll find out how soft you are once I play you?
It'll be more fun for me to play the
customers here than to play you.
What!?
He said it'll be more fun to play me than you.
Well why don't we play a game then?
Wait a second!
How can you say that without even playing me!?
Stop shouting, you're so annoying.
You're that scared of losing to me!?
Hey you! You've said too much.
Hong-kun play him.
Teach him what Go is like in Korea.
Oh, fine.
Okay. Sit down.
I'll play a tutoring game with you.
Tutoring game?
Su-Young!
Shindou!
I don't want to play a tutoring game!
Hikaru...
Shindou.
Come on! Nigiri!
That's the spirit!
Waya...
It'll be fun! A Japan vs Korea Insei match!
What is it? What's starting?
Hong-kun is playing an even match!?
Shindou's white...
Don't lose, you're representing Japan!
You're not a match to me.
I'm on the top half amongst the highly
competitive Korean Kenkyuusei.
Who's Hong-kun playing?
His opponent's an Insei from
the Japanese Go Institute.
I'm strong.
I can't possibly lose to a Japanese Insei.
You don't know about Korea? I can't tell
how soft you are without playing?
A Japan vs Korea Insei Match?
Sounds interesting.
Not something you see everyday.
Go Hong-kun!
Crush the Japanese Insei!
Oh wow, everyone's gathering around.
We're like supporters for the away team...
Though we are in Japan...
I'll show you how strong I am.
I'll show you!
And then, leave this place!
Let's go!
He's good. No wonder he's a Kenkyuusei at Korea.
Yeah, but Shindou's doing well too.
Umm...
How strong is Hong-kun among the Kenkyuusei?
There are 10 classes in Korea. 10 people per class.
Every month the four lowest ranked
students drop down a class,
and the four highest ranked students rise a class.
Su-Young consistently rose through the classes.
Everyone around him thinks
he will soon become a pro.
He must be exceptional.
But, he's hit a road block...
He dropped a class for the first time.
That seemed to discourage Su-Young.
He dropped down another class in the next month.
He failed the pro exam this month too...
So his parents thought they should give
him a break, and sent him over here.
What about you guys?
There are two classes, and we're
at the top of first class.
You're not at the same level.
There are far more children trying to
become a pro in Korea than in Japan.
They're much stronger than in Japan.
Of course! We all know how strong Hong-kun is!
Damn it. I know Korean players are
strong, but man this is annoying.
Go Shindou! Win the game, and show
them how strong Japan is!
Su-Young isn't just any child... but
can Su-Young beat him right now?
It's not a matter of skill...
Hong dropped a class.
This is the first time right?
Maybe that's why he's been so irritated lately.
Hey Hong, don't give up so easily.
This game is so stupid.
I don't feel like playing anymore.
Man I'm pissed.
Damn it. I don't care anymore.
And I keep losing with this state of mind...
Damn this is stupid.
Hong dropped another class this month.
I wonder how far he's going to go down.
Your Go isn't what it should be Hong.
Shut up!
Hong!
I lost...
I'll drop...
I'll lose again...
Who cares? I don't care anymore.
I'm pissed...
It's like I've forgotten how to win.
What am I doing?
I can't let my guard down from any of his moves.
He's stronger than I thought.
But I can't afford to lose here.
You!
If I lose to you, I'll remember your name!
Yeah, I'll make you remember!
Well said, Shindou!
Su-Young.
He's finally looking straight at the game.
Let's make him remember...
the name Shindou Hikaru!
伝えたい想いが今
Tsutaetai omoi ga ima
These feelings I want to tell you
溢れているよ
Afurete iru yo
are spilling out right now
言葉にできなくて 戸惑っている
Kotoba ni dekinakute tomadotte iru
but I'm hesitating, not knowing how to put it into words
出会いから　数えきれぬ 季節が巡り
Deai kara kazoekirenu kisetsu ga meguri
so many seasons passed by since we met
語りあかした夜が なつかしいよね
Katari akashita yoru ga natsukashii yo ne
I miss that time we stayed up all night talking
夢へ近づくたびに
Yume e chikazuku tabi ni
As I walk towards my dreams
儚さを知ったよ
Hakanasa wo shitta yo
I learn what vain all my effort are
それぞれの旅立ち
Sorezore no tabidachi
Let's start each of
ここから始めよう
Koko kara hajimeyou
our departure here
今までの僕達とは違う
Ima made no bokura to wa chigau
I'm not like I was before
もう負けない 歩き出していくよ
Mou makenai arukidashite iku yo
I won't give up anymore, I'll keep on walking,
どんな未来へでも
Donna mirai e demo
no matter what the future holds.
強くなれるように...
Tsuyoku nareru you ni
So that I can become stronger.
Go
Igo!
Umezawa Yukari's
Honinbou Shuusaku
I'm in Innoshima, the land of Honinbou Shuusaku!
Teacher Yukari
Ishikiri Shrine - Shuusaku Memorial Museum
Hiroshima Prefecture
Innoshima City
Shuusaku (Torajirou) was strong enough to be
called "The Godly Genius Child" at the age of 6
Shuusaku had the child's name "Torajirou".
He learned Go from his mother,
and at six, no one in the area was a match for him.
Written by Shuusaku at the age of 16
At age 9, he goes to Edo and studies under Honinbou Jyouwa
He went to Edo at the age of 9, entered the
Honinbou family, and studied under Jyouwa.
The Go board he used
with his mother
He was given the name Honinbou
from a Shogun at the age of 20,
The opening style developed by Shuusaku was
eventually called "the Shuusaku Style"
He then creates an incredible
record of 19 straight wins.
It is considered to guarantee victory
without Komi, and is still used today.
Shuusaku's grave
He collapsed of disease in 1862,
and died at the young age of 34.
Torajirou grew up on this beautiful island.
To be continued...
Though it started from a quibble.
This match touches me in the heart.
So you were this bad after all.
The move Shindou-kun just made right now...
What was he thinking?
The move he just made was a mistake.