Real Fansubbers presents
Hikaru no Go
胸の鼓動　熱くゆるがす
mune no kodou atsuku yurugasu
My heart walks, searching for something exciting
刺激求めて歩く My Heart
shigeki motomete aruku MY HEART
That will passionately sway the beating in my chest.
時間だけが過ぎる毎日じゃ
jikan dake ga sugiru mainichi jya
If I just wait for the time to pass everyday.
変化はない
henka ha nai
nothing's going to change.
Woo Wooo
止まらない　信じたい　進みたい
tomaranai shinjitai susumitai
I won't stop. I want to believe. I want to move forward.
自分の力試す My Life
jibun no chikara tamesu MY LIFE
I will test my strength during my life.
でも早歩きしたって見落とすだけ
demo hayaaruki shitatte miotosudake
But even if I walk faster.
I will definitely lose track of
そう確実に
sou kakujitsu ni
the important things.
Baby for you...
明日は明日の風が吹く
ashita ha ashita no kaze ga fuku
Tomorrow's wind will blow tomorrow.
それでも　今この瞬間を強く生きたい
soredemo
but I want to make the most out of this moment now.
ima kono shunkan wo tsuyoku ikitai
It's fantasy
さまよったとしても
samayotta to shitemo
Even if I'm wandering,
見たことない世界でも
mitakotonai sekai demo
even if I'm in a strange new world,
何よりも 自分を信じ立ち向かおう
nani yori mo jibun wo shinji tachimukaou
I'll stand up to it,
believing in myself more than anything else.
It's destiny
どんな場所にいても
donna basho ni itemo
No matter where I am,
つつむ空は一つだから
tsutsumu sora ha hitotsu dakara
I'm surrounded by the same sky.
ねぇ　もっと 翼広げて
nee motto tsubasa hirogete
so I'll be able to fly
羽ばたけるよね
habatakeruyone
with my wings spread out.
You there, want to play me?
Who are you, mister?
He's the man representing Japan in the next International Amateur Go Tournament.
Shuuhei is the top amateur player.
No time?
Why don't you try thinking a bit?
He's playing quickly, but he is playing solidly.
I see. He may be a child, but he is a pro.
He instantly read through my deciding move and responded correctly!
He's... incomparable to what he was like last year.
When did he change so much?
Okay!
Sai! How was it?
The Sixty-Third Match
I Won't Play Anymore
I wouldn't be surprised if there's a ghost in that room.
It's behind here.
Eh, here? But I didn't think
there was anything here.
But there is a room!
Give me a second.
You didn't know about this room?
No.
I'll turn on the light now.
What... is this place?
What is this?
Books?
Yeah.
They're Kifu, Old Kifu.
These are old Kifu from back when they were first printed.
The oldest thing we have here
is the Bouyuuseirakushuu.
Bouyuuseirakushuu is a collection of Kifu from the Northern Song
Dynasty of China (960~1170AD). The oldest match in the collection
is between two famous characters from a classical Chinese tale.
So this is what you meant by
"a room where I might find a ghost".
There weren't any ghosts here. Too bad.
Oh, yeah. Do you want to look at anything?
It's okay.
But you came all this way.
Then... Shuusaku.
Shuusaku! Let's see... I think
Shuusaku was from Kaei...
Kaei (1844~1853) is part of Japanese history. It occurs in the latter
years of the Edo period. A notable event of the period is the landing
of Commodore Perry in Uraga in the sixth year of Kaei.
Oh yeah. I've never seen a Kifu
played by Shuusaku before.
You've never seen one before?
You haven't even seen any of the
ones that are still in print?
You should study old Kifu.
They'll teach you something.
Oh, here it is
Ahh! What are you doing!?
I'm sorry.
Be careful. Those are important.
Okay.
I'll leave them here.
I'll be going now. Come get me when you're done.
I'm going home in half an hour.
So don't take too long.
Sai... played these, right?
Torajirou let Sai play everything...
Oh yeah. Take good care of those books.
O-Okay.
I know the Sai from right now.
Who cares about the old Sai...?
This move by Sai...
It's an incredible move. It attacks
all of the surrounding sides.
His opponent would lose all of his will
to fight after seeing a move like this.
Sai.
He's... a genius.
I should have let him play more.
That would have been much
better than my playing...
Why didn't I realize this before!?
Yeah...
I'm sure Touya would have been much happier if Sai had played.
I should have let Sai, the genius, play everything!
Yeah..
That's what Torajirou did...
Unlike me, Torajirou was strong enough to
try to become a pro when he met Sai...
Therefore he was able to see how strong Sai was.
And he let Sai play.
I... didn't know anything about Go.
And I had no idea how strong Sai was!
I just thought about how I wanted to play.
When I finally realized how good Sai
was... I still put myself ahead of him.
I'm... an idiot!
I'm an idiot!
Sai...
O-Oh no.
I should have let Sai play...
from the beginning...
Anyone would agree...
It would have been better to
let Sai play all the games.
All of them! All of them! All of them!
I don't need to play! I won't ask to play again!
So...
God! Please! Turn back time!
Turn time back to when I first met him!
What's wrong, Akira?
The games are going to start soon.
Yes.
Shindou... why aren't you here?
He's late.
What is he doing? Did he oversleep?
And I thought that I would finally get
a chance to watch you play today.
Or... are you not coming!?
Touya is bothered by Shindou's absence, too...
Oh no, the game is about to start.
Good luck!
About these four examples I gave...
They're all examples of conjugate modifiers...
Well then,
let's think about what the differences are between
the conjugate modifiers in the following sentences.
Sai...
Come back...
I'll let you play all the games.
I...
won't play anymore...
I'll let you play all the games...
So come back... Sai...
Shindou-Kun isn't here?
Yes... and it's already time... let's begin.
Shindou didn't come to the Ooteai this week either!
Huh? Seriously?
Is he sick?
If he is... He didn't bother telling anyone about it!
He didn't come to Master Morishita's
study sessions either.
What's wrong with him!?
Shindou!
The Fujiwara clan is a clan who dominated Japanese politics during much
of the Heian period (794~1185). Though Japan was ruled by the Imperial
family, and not by the Fujiwara clan, they had a great deal of control over
the Emperors of the time by marrying females of the clan off to them.
Sai of the Fujiwara doesn't exist?
What's with that look on your face? I researched it.
The nature of their control over Japan changed at the end of the Heian period,
when they defeated the Taira clan in the Genpei conflict. For more information
about the Fujiwara clan, take a class on Japanese history or literature.
A noble who tutored the Emperor in Go during the Heian period, right?
I even called my teacher to check.
But...
Sai...
exists...
What do you mean!? What are you basing that on!?
Well... it is wrong of me to say that he didn't exist...
To be accurate, we don't know
whether he existed or not...
It just means that he's not in any books or records.
Thank you very much.
You don't know if he existed or not...
Sai existed!
I'm the only one who knows.
Hikaru!
What's up?
What were you talking to Mr. Matsui,
the social studies teacher, about?
Nothing.
Hey, I need one less handicap stone
against Kaneko-san now.
Play me again when you have time.
I'm not playing any more.
What? Meanie!
You taught me before...
How are you doing with your pro matches?
I said I'm not playing anymore.
What are you talking about!? Are
you even listening to me!?
I won't go to Master Morishita's study sessions anymore.
I won't go to Kawai-san's Go salon anymore, either.
See ya!
Touya...
I wanted you to look towards me instead of Sai...
Even though that's impossible.
I... can't surpass Sai.
Sai...
I wonder why he disappeared.
You're neater than I expected!
Actually, he just doesn't have anything... at all.
Don't you at least need a fridge?
Aren't you going to cook?
Waya, what about laundry?
I plan on doing laundry at home.
And I'll probably eat at home
or eat at my teacher's place.
What!? How are you living on your own then?
All I need is my Go board and stones for now.
I envy you. I want to live on my own, too.
You're free to come and stay here anytime, Komiya.
If you bring me food.
A bunch of pros are going to come
here on Saturdays, too!
Pros? Who?
Saeki-san, and Okada-san,
and Nakayama-san, and...
What about Shindou?
He hasn't shown up at the Institute
at all. I haven't told him yet.
What happened to Shindou?
Really... Master Morishita was angry, and
told me to forget about him. But...
Say, Waya...
That study session on Saturday...
Can I go to it, too?
I don't study with my teacher on Saturdays, so...
Of course! You should all come!
Honda-kun and Komiya can because they're good.
I'd feel uncomfortable because I would
only lower the level of discussion.
How can you study if you worry
about stuff like that?
I'm starting at the preliminaries again
this year for the pro exams!
Iijima-kun already quit being an Insei...
Maybe I'm at my limit now, too.
Oh yeah!
Waya, have you heard?
Afew pros from the Kyuseikai went to China to
study and to promote international relations.
And?
I heard that Isumi-kun went with them.
He did!?
Isumi-san is continuing Go...
Oh... he is taking the pro exams again this year...
Isumi-san's an outsider, so he'll begin at
the preliminaries two months from now.
He's going to be playing us again in the finals.
Isumi-san... in China.
Touya-Kun?
Umm... Has Shindou gone home yet?
Hikaru?
I'm in a different class...
Shindou was in the library.
Kaneko-san...
Go up those stairs, turn right on the second
floor, and the library will be on your right.
Thanks.
Hikaru's at the library? What is he doing?
Nothing. He was just staring into space.
Staring into space?
Yeah.
That's so unlike him.
I wonder what's wrong.
Sai...
Did something happen to him after...
the game against Master Touya on the Internet?
Shindou...
W-Wh-What is it,Touya?
Why do you always appear so suddenly!?
It's bad for my heart! What are you here for?
Shindou...
Why didn't you come to the Wakajishisen?
Why aren't you going to your matches?
Is there a reason?
I'm no good.
You're no good?
What do you mean?
I mean, it's a waste for someone like me to play!
Be quiet.
I disagree.
Touya...
That's...
because you see Sai inside me.
I won't play anymore.
You won't play!? You've got to be kidding!
Shut up!
You're waiting for Sai, not me. But...
Sai has... disappeared...
Sorry!
Shindou!
Sorry, Touya!
Sai is gone!
I want to let you play him, but...
Shindou!
What did you become a pro for!?
Why did you disappear, Sai!?
Why!?
Wasn't it to play me? Shindou!
Shindou...
Sai!
つらい想い出とかいくつあったのかな？
tsurai omoide toka ikutsu atta no kana?
How many sad memories did we have?
どんな楽しい日を
donna tanoshii hi wo
What kind of happy days are we going to
これからは大切にしていくのかな？
kore kara wa taisetsu ni shite iku no kana?
hold onto preciously from now on?
近くの公園で集まったねいつも
chikaku no kouen de atsumatta ne itsumo
We always gathered at the nearby park
夜中まで大きな声出して笑ってたね
yonaka made ookina koe dashite waratteta ne
and laughed out loud into the middle of the night,
ずっとずっと
zutto... zutto...
always... always...
同じ時代を今生きてる奇跡が
onaji toki wo ima ikiteru kiseki ga
Because I'm really happy for the miracle
すごくうれしいからね
sugoku ureshii kara ne
of being here when you are
次あう日もきっとねぇ
tsugi au hi mo kitto nee
Let's laugh together again
一緒に笑っていようよ
issho ni waratte iyou yo
the next time we meet
今度はどんな夢を
kondo wa donna yume wo
what kind of dreams
一緒に語りあうのかな？
issho ni katariau no kana?
are we going to talk about then?
Merry Christmas!
UmezawaYukari's
Teacher, aren't the stars pretty?
Teacher Yukari
Yuuki
Mai
They really are.
Oh yes, have you heard this story about Go?
There are 361 intersections on a 19x19 board.
This is the same as the number
of days in ancient China.
There are 361 intersections on a 19x19 board
There were 361 days in an old Chinese year
And it's said that one rotation around the
first line of the board represents a year.
There is a theory that one rotation around the first line is one year.
And the white Go stones represent the Day,
and the black ones represent the Night.
White Stones
Black Stones
Represent Day   (Yang)
Represent Night (Ying)
In other words, the Go board shows
the flow of time on Earth...
Go boards represent the flow of time on Earth
and Go Stones represent the sky
and the Go stones... the sky.
What do you picture when these
two are brought together?
Space?
The Universe
Yup!
There's a theory that Go boards and
stones were used for fortune telling.
There is a theory that
Go Boards and Stones were once used for fortune telling.
To be Continued...
Don't touch the merchandise!
But this is Grandpa's!
Mister, you play Go? Want to play me?
He has a 5-dan certificate! Don't
play him in a game of Go!
Hikaru, let's go!
Yeah!