Sai...
Sai!
You're here in my dream!
Sai?
Don't go!
Say something!
Don't go away!
Sai!
The Road to the Hokuto Cup
Is Hikaru playing?
Huh? Did you say something, dear?
Is Hikaru playing again?
Yes. As soon as he came home, he
was like, "I'm hungry! Ramen!"
...and ate it all in a flash.
He's been in his room ever since.
He's been like this for a while now.
Sai, I've been doing pretty well lately.
I'm moving up in the Honinbou League as well.
I can't wait to play against people with higher dans.
I want to keep winning and winning,
and someday... someday, I'll...
Hikaru!
Someone from the Institute's on the phone.
I'll be right there!
Hello?
Oh, Shindou-kun?
This is Kosemura from the Japanese
Institute's publishing department.
I've got a few questions I'd like to ask...
Yes.
What? The Hokuto Cup?
A team match between Japan, China, and Korea?
Team matches between Japan, China, and Korea?!
Yeah.
Sounds fun, doesn't it?
It's called the Hokuto Cup.
Looks like each team will consist of three
people, all under the age of 18.
I know about it.
I heard that the preliminary elimination
matches are going to be held in April.
Do you think I could participate?
I passed the pro exam this year!
Isumi-san, didn't Shindou just
say "under the age of 18?"
Junior...
From this year's successful candidates, Isumi-san
and Kadowaki-san won't be able to participate...
...but Honda-san is 18, right?
Oh yeah, do you remember Soo Young?
Soo Young? Oh, that Korean boy we
met at a go salon some time back.
According to a guy from the publishing department,
he's supposed to be a pro now, too.
There's also the possibility that he might
participate in the Hokuto Cup.
Korean teenagers are incredible.
Ko-Young Ha is already at the top with 16,
and the same goes for China.
Well, Japan does have Touya Akira, but...
You forgot about me!
I don't intend to stare at
Touya's back forever, you know.
So this is the game you played this week?
Yeah.
It's the final match of the first
preliminaries from the Honinbou League.
That's horrible go you play there.
You're losing.
What are you talking about?!
I made a comeback, didn't I?
I won by one and a half moku.
The reason you were able to make a comeback
was because your opponent was naive.
Don't tell me you think you won because
you were better than your opponent.
The way you talk really pisses me off!
I'm just pointing out the truth.
What did you say?!
If I had been your opponent in this match,
I wouldn't have let you make a comeback.
Note: keshi (reduction) means playing a move outside or
on the apparent boundary of the opponent's territory.
If it were me, I'd have started keshi before
you could surround the center.
If you don't gain control of the central area,
black has practically no chance of winning.
How about it? You can't make
a comeback now, can you?
Wait, then I'd change it this way.
Now the match won't proceed as you planned it.
But if you did that, it would make you
vulnerable over here, wouldn't it?
If you leave the center open...
it would not only prevent your comeback, it
would also give me more of your territory.
That's not true!
Note: kosumu means placing a stone adjacent to one of the same
color that is already on the board, forming the "diagonal shape."
If I kosumi here in the white territory,
it wouldn't be such a bad move.
How can you say it's not a bad move?!
You can't play in a position like that!
Yes I can!
This little kosumi here is enough for me!
Don't you think it's getting worse by the day?
Yeah.
So you're not giving in?
Nope.
Talk big while you can, I'll beat you
in a formal match someday.
Huh? Wait a sec... there's the
preliminary matches in the Hokuto Cup!
You know, right?
With the team matches...
I just might be able to play a match with you then.
I'm not going to be participating in the
preliminary matches for the Hokuto Cup.
I've already been chosen as one of the three players.
What?
What the hell is that?!
Why are you the only one not participating?!
That's not fair!
Hey now, even in the other matches, those
with a good record get seeded, right?
The young master over there is already participating
in the leagues, so don't complain about it!