胸の鼓動　熱くゆるがす
mune no kodou atsuku yurugasu
My heart walks, searching for something exciting
刺激求めて歩く My Heart
shigeki motomete aruku MY HEART
That will passionately sway the beating in my chest.
時間だけが過ぎる毎日じゃ
jikan dake ga sugiru mainichi jya
If I just wait for the time to pass everyday.
変化はない
henka ha nai
nothing's going to change.
Woo Wooo
止まらない　信じたい　進みたい
tomaranai shinjitai susumitai
I won't stop. I want to believe. I want to move forward.
自分の力試す My Life
jibun no chikara tamesu MY LIFE
I will test my strength during my life.
でも早歩きしたって見落とすだけ
demo hayaaruki shitatte miotosudake
But even if I walk faster.
I will definitely lose track of
そう確実に
sou kakujitsu ni
the important things.
Baby for you...
明日は明日の風が吹く
ashita ha ashita no kaze ga fuku
Tomorrow's wind will blow tomorrow.
それでも　今この瞬間を強く生きたい
soredemo
but I want to make the most out of this moment now.
ima kono shunkan wo tsuyoku ikitai
It's fantasy
さまよったとしても
samayotta to shitemo
Even if I'm wandering,
見たことない世界でも
mitakotonai sekai demo
even if I'm in a strange new world,
何よりも 自分を信じ立ち向かおう
nani yori mo jibun wo shinji tachimukaou
I'll stand up to it,
believing in myself more than anything else.
It's destiny
どんな場所にいても
donna basho ni itemo
No matter where I am,
つつむ空は一つだから
tsutsumu sora ha hitotsu dakara
I'm surrounded by the same sky.
ねぇ　もっと 翼広げて
nee motto tsubasa hirogete
so I'll be able to fly
羽ばたけるよね
habatakeruyone
with my wings spread out.
Touya... let's play.
We can't start until we play.
Sai, who you wanted to play, is no longer here.
I don't know if you'll notice or not,
But Sai is in the games I play.
I'll become just as good as you,
and play against you from now on.
Touya.
We finally get to play.
I haven't played you since the third
board match in the Go club.
It's been two years and four months.
It's been that long?
Yeah... it was a long time.
Today I will show you my strength.
The Seventy-Fourth Match
Forever Inside You
If you're going to respond with another
Kakari, I'll do a low pincer.
I'll spread the fight across the board and
we'll enter a kill-or-be killed fight.
I finally got the chance to play against you.
It's been since the game in the Go tournament...
No, Sai played the first half of that game.
Touya, this is the first real game between you and me!
That's a daring pincer.
Okay, I'll break out here.
So that's how you want to play it.
I have to do a Suberi!
If I want to win.
There you go!
He responded correctly in an instant.
He's just as good as a high-dan pro.
This... this is a Kifu from a game
Shindou played, Mr. Yun!?
Yes. I happened to see him when he
was playing a game in a Go salon.
Both Black and White are good enough to be pros...
But White especially...
Shindou-kun is White. Black is a Korean
kenkyuusei, Hong Su-Young.
I wanted you to see it.
Especially considering how disappointed you
were after playing him in the tournament.
This is how good he is now.
Hello? It's me. How did the pro exams turn out?
Yeah?
Yeah, okay.
They've been decided? All three?
So there are no playoffs?
That means Waya-kun beat Fukui-kun,
and Shindou beat Ochi-kun?
You're always looking up, aren't you?
So you probably don't know about
the scary guy beneath you.
Beneath me?
He's not really beneath you,
but immediately behind you.
You and he are the two who will be threatening me.
He just became a pro this year.
His name is Shindou Hikaru.
You should watch out for him.
I wanted to know how strong you were all this time,
and you're just as strong as I had thought.
There's no doubt about it. You
will become my lifelong rival.
Sai...
This is publishing.
Oh, yes. Thank you.
Yes, good work.
How do you pronounce this Korean child's name?
It's "kou" from "kouzui" (kouzui is
flood) so would it be Hong? Hong...
The child who beat Kim Kang Il? It's Su-Young.
His name is Hong Su-Young.
Hong Su-Young, 14. Yet another
incredible new player for Korea.
The sixteen year old Ko Young Ha is setting the
record for the longest winning streak right now.
The young players are really good in Korea.
Hong Su-Young, Ko Young Ha... I wonder
if they're the ones who will be coming.
Coming to what?
It's just a rumor right now,
but there may be a Japan, China,
Korea Junior Tournament.
I hear a corporation is trying to sponsor
a team tournament between pros
from Japan, China, and Korea under the age of 18.
Japan, China, Korea Junior Tournament!?
Under the age of 18!?
There's no one of that age in Japan who
can go up against China and Korea!
We have Touya Akira!
But Touya-kun isn't enough by himself.
What about that boy, Ochi-kun?
Ochi-kun... he still hasn't lost, right?
I think he's 14. That's an impressive age.
But I doubt he can do much
against China and Korea.
Touya-kun is the only one we can really count on.
There's Shindou-kun.
We have Shindou-kun.
Shindou...
I saw a glimmer of Sai in him.
The other person that I see...
coming in and out of you.
That...
That shadow I've...
I've always been chasing after...
Shindou-kun?
Shindou?
Shindou? The kid who didn't
show up to his matches?
Do you mean him, Amano-san?
Yes. I believe he has just as much
potential as Touya-kun.
You think?
People like Touya Kouyou, Kuwabara
Honinbou, and Ogata Jyudan...
have been interested in him for some reason.
Are you talking about how Master
Touya requested to...
play Shindou-kun for the new
first-dan series game?
But the game itself was horrible.
Yes. But strangely, Master Kuwabara
and the others...
did not change their opinion of
Shindou-kun because of that.
And ever since I learned that Touya-kun
sees Shindou-kun as a rival,
I've become one of the people who
is counting on Shindou-kun.
Touya-kun does!? It would
be great if that were true.
Oh yes, I've heard of a rumor that Master
Kuwabara thinks highly of Shindou-kun.
Oh yes, Kurata-san said...
Oh! The match between Shindou
and Touya is this week!
...the other day. Maybe Kurata-san too?
What!? Even Kurata-kun thinks highly of him?
How has he done since he started
coming to his matches?
He played eight games and won them all.
That sounds great. I hope the young people
keep replacing the top players like this.
Nah, the old folks won't give up that easily.
But Master Ogata has already cut into them.
We have Kurata-kun, too!
No, it's about Touya-kun. He will surpass
Master Ogata and Master Kurata!
Oh, the match between Touya-kun and
Shindou-kun is going on today!
I get so excited thinking about the future.
Amano-san?
We have Touya-kun.
We have Shindou-kun.
And with Ochi-kun and Waya-kun and the
others thrown in, they form a new wave.
Yeah! The strength of youth! The
arrival of the next generation!
Yes, with Touya-kun in the lead.
And I hear Shindou-kun is just
as good as Touya-kun.
Then we can finally aim for the world! It'll be
a comeback for Japan! Right, Amano-san?
Sounds great. Our sales would improve
a lot if that were to happen.
But, we have no idea what will happen.
Let's put an end to our talk of dreams now.
Time for lunch!
This game's been moving really quickly.
There's a really complex battle going on.
But he's doing well against Touya despite the difficulty.
Saeki-kun! Wanna go eat together? Meals are no
good unless you have someone to eat with.
And Akira never eats during a game.
Come on, let's go. What do you want to eat?
A-Ashiwara-san! H-Hold on!
What do Touya's students think
of Morishita's students?
We stopped the clock after Touya's Katatsuki.
I should play on the lower left instead
of the conflict at the top right.
I'll play at the Keima to assault White's weakness.
Touya will definitely connect, so
I'll just get life on the side.
The lower left is still too small.
How should I attack the top?
I'm at a disadvantage?
No. It's close. I can still play.
Oh yeah, lunch!
Touya, what are you doing about lunch?
I'm gonna go before we run out of time.
Is he not going to eat?
Sai...
I thought of Sai from the Internet
when I was playing you.
Touya...
I'm not Sai, unfortunately.
It's you.
Touya?
It's the other you.
There's another one of you.
The Shindou Hikaru when we first met...
He is Sai!
T-Touya...
There's...
someone else inside you!
Ring
My
Bell
noizu darake no mune de
ノイズだらけの胸で
I listen to my fate through the din in my heart.
noizu darake no mune deunmei wo kikiwakeru
ノイズだらけの胸で運命を聴きわける
It occurs to me.
hirameku
閃く
hiramekuyume ha watashi no naka demezame o matteta
閃く夢は私の中で目覚めを待ってた
My dream was waiting for the time
to wake up within me.
mezame o matteta
閃く夢は私の中で目覚めを待ってた
Music
Is
My
Thing
I can be more like myself
jibun rashiku nareru
自分らしくなれる
Music
In
My
Heart
ときめきならして
Let the pounding of my heart be heard
tokimeki narashite
ときめきならして
Music
Is
My
Thing
karada wo ugokasu
体を動かす
I move my body
karada wo ugokasu
体を動かす
Music
In
My
Heart
Feel the light
hikari wo kanjite
光を感じて
Music
Is
My
Thing
shiro to kuro de egaku
白と黒で描く
I draw with black and white
shiro to kuro de egaku
白と黒で描く
Music
In
My
Heart
owaranai haamoni
The unending Harmony
終わらないハーモニー
owaranai haamoni
When White played here at this
point, that was a mistake.
Black could play here.
It's an Atari, so White has to connect.
Then Black moves here, and White loses its eyes.
So, White has to protect at this point.
I resign.
Yuuki-kun won by resignation.