kono me kimi no me ni
この瞳君の瞳に
On this eye, this eye on yours,
utsuru donna mono mo
映るどんなモノも
everything will appear,
mikiwamete miseru yo shinjitsu wo
見極めて見せるよ 真実を
I will tell apart the truth.
Elite-Fansubs
Presents
Hikaru
Elite-Fansubs
Presents
no Go
Hikaru no Go
bokutachi wa kono jidai ni
僕達はこの時代に
We had so many dreams
dore dake no yume kakaete
どれだけの夢抱えて
In this time we live in.
namida shite mayoi nagara
涙して迷いながら
We stare at it and run towards it,
sore ni kakete miteru no
それに賭けてみてるの
even as we wander about crying.
boku wa sore demo hito ni hiketoranu you na
僕は それでも 人にひけとらぬような
Even then, I will find a deciding move.
kimete mitsuke yume wo te ni suru darou
決め手見つけ夢を手にするだろう
just as good as anyone else's, and take hold of my dreams.
kono me kimi no me ni
この瞳君の瞳に
On this eye, this eye on yours,
utsuru donna mono mo
映るどんなモノも
everything will appear.
mikiwamete miseru yo shinjitsu dake
見極めて見せるよ 真実だけ
I'll tell apart, just the truth.
tatoe genjitsu ga
たとえ現実が
Even if the truth is
kitsuku umoresou demo
きつく埋もれそうでも
so harsh it's suffocating.
konna basho de owaru
こんな場所で終わる
I'm not going to end
boku janai
僕じゃない
in a place like this.
If you calm your emotions and
play normally, you win.
If you play with stirred emotions, you lose.
I calmed down with those 30 minutes.
While you probably became upset.
He's completely been overwhelmed.
There's no way he can win like this.
I win by four and a half moku!
Thanks for the game...
The Thirty-Second Match
The Last day of the Preliminaries
Japanese Go Institute
Second day of the Pro Exam Preliminaries
Please begin.
Good luck.
Hikaru... you're still not relaxed today...
If you lose the control of your mind, the thought
behind each of your moves begin to break apart.
Now that I think about it, you were like this during the Insei examination too.
You couldn't play the way you usually do.
And your moves become rushed, you went in too deep.
It's time for lunch,
so please halt your clocks.
Hey!
Let's go eat lunch! Lunch!
I bought lunch this morning!
What for!?
You're not going to finish it, Shindou-kun?
Just as I thought, Shindou isn't doing well.
If he loses today, he'll be at the
end of the rope with two losses.
Mind my own business.
Hikaru, umm, umm...
Shut up! I'm trying to think right now.
I resign...
How did you do!? I got my second win!
What? Looks like you got your second
loss. You're at the end of your rope!
Third day of the pro exam preliminaries.
Hikaru, is this okay?
What?
I mean, it's almost time for the pro exam.
You already have two losses.
Are you sure you should be here?
It's okay.
I'll go in as late as possible.
So that I don't meet Tsubaki.
In order to get a win!
My opponent today is Fuku.
I've only lost to Fuku twice out of
all the games we played for fun,
and all the games during the study sessions.
I should be able to beat Fuku if I play normally.
Fuku is probably desperate being one and one.
But if I play normally I won't lose!
Play normally... that becomes harder
the more desperate you become.
Okay!
Please begin.
Shindou-kun! What's wrong!?
That doesn't matter, go sit down already.
Okay.
You came in at the last minute.
Mmm, sorry.
The clock's already started.
Okay.
Good luck.
Don't let your feelings take control, Hikaru.
I don't understand it at all.
That's like speaking to someone who's asleep!
But, didn't he say something earlier about giving
him money so that he can take the pro exam?
The Inseis take it for free.
Ahh, I see.
He asked to take a day off of school awhile ago too.
He said he told his teacher already.
I thought he was too into it back then.
I thought I'd ask you dad, about
what it's like to be a pro player.
No, I don't know anything either,
though I do like Go.
What did Masao say?
He said, "It's hard to become a pro no
matter who it is. He'll probably drop the
exam. Let him do what he wants."
I agree with him. Just let Hikaru
do what he wants for now.
It feels like Hikaru's changing... I feel uncertain.
Why does Hikaru want to become
a pro all of a sudden?
He lost to a boy his age by a lot
at Go, and he was given up on.
He looked disappointed, and became pro.
So I want to make him look back at me.
Yeah! The eyes he had when he first came to me.
I'll make him turn those eyes to me!
How fortunate that the opponent is
someone you're used to playing.
You're back to your normal self.
It's time for lunch, so please halt your game.
You're already in the end game?
Do you want to play to the end?
Yes.
Ah, okay.
I was worried for Shindou-kun because he got two
straight losses, but he's playing the way he usually does.
I have 50 moku.
I have 59 moku.
I won...
Thanks for the game.
Yes! One win!
One win!? Shindou-kun you lost twice!?
Oh you didn't know? I would've been out if I lost.
I'm so glad I won. Oh yeah... now Fuku
you're one and two just like me.
Yeah.
Sorry. I'm going to go home. I don't want
to bump into that hairy godzilla.
Is that why you came at the
last minute this morning?
Yeah.
Are you going to come at the
last minute tomorrow too?
We're going to have drawings again tomorrow.
I know!
It makes sense for the winner to record the game.
I'd hate to mark down my own losses.
Fukui... Fukui... and then my win...
Three and a half moku...
and one more!
I'll grab a win again tomorrow!
Tomorrow... you have two losses still
tomorrow. That won't change.
I resign. This is it.
Jinryuji-san lost!
Who is this kid?
You're not going to tell me that you're a pro right?
No, I'm an Insei.
Playing at a Go Salon like this
occasionally is good practice.
Oh, an Insei, here to practice...
I have a friend who's a pro.
According to him, if the age limit for the
exam wasn't 30, I could take it too.
"You're strong enough!" He told me, but
seems like he was just being polite.
Sorry I didn't put up much of a fight.
No, thank you very much.
Over here mister, you played here.
If you had kosumi'd here, I would
have been in trouble.
I see...
Waya, are you done? Want to go?
Yeah.
Hold on a second.
Try going to this Go Salon. You want
to play good people right?
Thank you very much.
Playing at a Go salon is fun but the smoke is...
Want to play at my house, Waya?
Hey Isumi-san, let's stop by the Institute.
To see the pro exam preliminaries?
Today's the third day.
Let's go see if Shindou's risen
up with three straight wins.
Japanese Go Institute
Pro Exam Preliminaries Day 4
What!? Waya and Isumi-san dropped
by afterwards yesterday?
Yup. In the afternoon, to check the match records.
When I told them that Fuku and Shindou
finished in the morning and went home,
Waya said "Those two always play so quickly."
We used a lot of time that game for Fuku and I.
The people with three wins
and three losses are gone.
And all that's left are people who are 1-2 and 2-1.
Waya said "Shindou that idiot, what is he doing?"
It's not just you Shindou, I have two losses,
Fuku has two losses... it's really bad.
Morning!
To think, Iijima-kun got three wins.
Oh yeah! Where's Tsubaki!?
The beard guy got three wins and moved on.
Oh, so he's not here.
Well then, we'll begin the drawings.
Please come forward to draw a number
when your name is called.
If you've already played your opponent,
please say so, we'll redo it.
If two people with two losses play
each other, one of them will fail.
Let's begin now.
That move he played now, it seems
like a good move, but it's a failure.
If Hikaru responds correctly...
It ends here.
I resign.
Yes!
Like I said! If you had only played
like that on the first day!
But noooo you were afraid of the bearded
guy and you lost. I'm so angry!
Shut up already.
Fuku won too. Now Fuku and I are both 2-2.
Will you mark me down too?
Oh you won?
Yeah. By resignation. I'm so glad.
Nase is 2-2 too.
We might play each other tomorrow.
There will be less people too.
I'll go watch the other games.
It's finally the last day of the preliminaries...
I'll take... a win tomorrow too!
Japanese Go Institute
Pro Exam Preliminaries Day 5
Two boards... this decides everything...
Umm...
Morning.
Looks like everyone's here.
There are five people with 2-2. Two of us will...
We'll begin drawing for the pairings.
Fuku and Shindou-kun have played
each other on the third day.
Anyone else played someone here? No right?
Then if Fuku-kun is playing
Shindou-kun, we'll redo it.
Everyone please come forward and draw a number.
I'm B.
I'm B too.
Your name?
Hirabayashi.
Let's see, Hirabayashi and Fuku-kun.
I'm A.
Nase-kun and Matsui-kun.
Shindou-kun you don't have an opponent
and you win by default.
Win by... default...
Japanese Go Institute
YAHOO! I won without playing!
I'm so lucky!
It's the opposite! You're unlucky!
Hikaru, you need to play as
many games as you can!
Really?
You're going to play that bearded guy again!
I still have a month till the exam!
I'll train! I'll train!
Train? How?
Umm... I'll think about it when I get home.
Think about it now! Now!
Ahh you're so annoying.
Oh yeah, Morishita 9 dan's Study
Session is this afternoon...
I don't want to go home only to come back again.
Wanna play on a magnet Go board to kill time?
~Wai~ I'll play! I'll play!
Shindou and the other guys with two losses... if
they won yesterday, they should still be there.
If they have three losses, they would've failed
yesterday, and they wouldn't be here today.
If he failed... Shindou might not come
to the study session today.
Fuku and Nase and the outsiders are the
only ones playing. Did Shindou fail!?
Sh-Shindou!
Hairy Godzilla!? You lost because of that?
Y-Yeah.
Even if it was by default, you made
it to the exam, that's good.
But really, I thought you'd come
up with three straight wins.
I didn't think you'd get defeated by a hairy godzilla.
But... I just kind of got angry and...
Okay! You'd come with us, the next time
Isumi-san and I go to a Go Salon.
Go Salon?
You're going to play against people
like that hairy godzilla.
You've got to get used to it by the exams.
They should be done by now. Let's go check.
Yeah.
Hey mom? It's me. Yeah, it just ended.
Yeah, I won.
Thanks.
Yeah...
Waya-kun...
Fuku, how was it?
I won!
Yes!
Yes! All three of you made it to the exam!
Man, you really had me worried.
Who cares! We won!
What are you talking about? Just
yesterday you were going,
"where's the hairy godzilla? Where's
the hairy godzilla?" in fear.
You didn't have to say that!
Oh well, I'm just glad you won.
Tsutaetai omoi ga ima
伝えたい想いが今
These feelings I want to tell you
Afurete iru yo
溢れているよ
are spilling out right now
Kotoba ni dekinakute tomadotte iru
言葉にできなくて 戸惑っている
but I'm hesitating, not knowing how to put it into words
Deai kara kazoekirenu kisetsu ga meguri
出会いから　数えきれぬ 季節が巡り
so many seasons passed by since we met
Katari akashita yoru ga natsukashii yo ne
語りあかした夜が なつかしいよね
I miss that time we stayed up all night talking
Yume e chikazuku tabi ni
夢へ近づくたびに
As I walk towards my dreams
Hakanasa wo shitta yo
儚さを知ったよ
I learn what vain all my effort are
Sorezore no tabidachi
それぞれの旅立ち
Let's start each of
Koko kara hajimeyou
ここから始めよう
our departure here
Ima made no bokura to wa chigau
今までの僕達とは違う
I'm not like I was before
Mou makenai arukidashite iku yo
もう負けない 歩き出していくよ
I won't give up anymore, I'll keep on walking,
Donna mirai e demo
どんな未来へでも
no matter what the future holds.
Tsuyoku nareru you ni
強くなれるように...
So that I can become stronger.
Go
Igo!
Umezawa Yukari's
Teacher Yukari
Let's continue with Tesuji today.
It's white's turn. Right now, these three
white stones are about to get captured.
But there's a way to save them
by taking these black stones.
How would you save the white stones
by capturing the black stones?
What should you do?
Yuuki
Mai
Okay last move, do it with energy!
Yuuki is correct!!
Yes, you can take these black stones like this.
This is a technique called
"A Nesting Swan"
How about this time?
Mai is trying it this time!!
When the left and right are symmetric, the
center tends to become the critical spot.
Yes, you can take the stones by doing that.
If you get your Tesuji right
Go will become even more fun!!
If you play Tesuji like this successfully in a
real game, Go will become even more fun.
To be continued...
Just think of it as a team match!
Team match?
We have to be able to beat the old men at
a Go Salon with three stones at least.
Why you bastard! How dare you look
down on me like that you brat.
I can't just play like I normally do.
I have to find a key to the game.