Fujiwarano Sai, the Go player who
lived during the Heian period,
has revisited this world through Shindou Hikaru.
He returned to this world to make the move of God.
君が今僕を支えて
Kimi ga ima boku wo sasaete
Now you are,
holding me up strong!
僕が今君を支える
boku ga ima kimi wo sasaeru
Now I am,
holding you up as well!
だから迷いながらも共に生きていこうよ
Dakara Mayoi nagara mo tomo ni ikite ikou yo
So let us now, while wandering live together
未来へと
Mirai e to...
towards the future
Elite-Fansubs presents
Hikaru no Go
仲間と戯れ　それなりで居ても
Nakama to tawamaure sorenaride itemo
Even when I'm capricing with my friends,
もの足りなさを感じてしまう
mono tari na sa wo kanjite shimau
I feel an emptiness in my heart.
冷めた目で見られて
Sameta me de mirarete
Looked at with cold eyes,
乾いた時代の風に吹かれている
Kawaita jidai no kaze ni fukareteiru
I'm blown by the wind of a dry age
不安な 心と勇気が
Fuan na, kokoro to yuuki ga
Feelings of doubt and courage
背中合わせになっている
senaka awase ni natteiru
are back to back
だけど今なら夢をこの手で叶えてみせるよ
dakedo ima nara yume wo, kono te de kanaete miseru yo
but I'll make these dreams come true now with my own hands.
傷ついて壊れそうな日も
Kizutsuite koware sou na hi mo
The days where I'm hurt and about to break,
涙して困らせる日も
Namidashite komaraseru hi mo
the days where I cry and trouble you
あるけれど僕達はそれを
aru keredo bokura wa sore wo
They all exist, but we will
超えていくんだ誰より
koete ikunda dare yori...
get over it heading higher
上を目指して
ue wo mezashite!
than anyone else!
What? He lost?
Akira-kun lost, did you say?
The Second Match
The Weakpoint Revealed!!
Hello.
Hi, Akari-chan.
Is Hikaru-kun at home?
Well, he's started to go to Go class.
Go?
Yeah, I don't know why he suddenly started it.
Hikaru is playing Go?
Okay, let's start with this problem right here.
In this situation, black should
place a stone underneath this one.
Then, even if white holds the two black stones,
black tries to capture these two stones,
forcing white to capture his stones.
Then breaking the eye on the left would kill the white formation.
I don't get any of what they're talking about!
Well, that's because you are a beginner.
Now, let's see what happens
if we go to break the eye first.
19-16!
That's right.
If we place white here, then
the white formation would live.
Do you know how strong the person who's teaching is?
I know that he's a pro.
Pro?
That means he makes his living playing Go.
Let's cut the lecture off around
here and get to playing the game.
Good luck.
Um...
So, you are Shindou-kun, right?
Uh, yes.
Is it your first time?
I've played once before, but that doesn't count
because I was sort of watching the game.
Why don't we start with "capture" game then.
Oh, I know this!
If white goes here, black gets taken, right?
Yes, that's right.
When you only need one more move to capture a stone, we call it atari.
Ok, what about the next one?
Atari!
Ok, Shindou-kun, try playing black.
Um...
See, atari again.
Atari.
Atari again.
Ok, thanks for the meal!
Oh, hey!
This shape is called shichou, it's one of
the shapes that you can't get away from.
You will see this quite often when you are playing,
so why don't you watch others
while keeping this in mind.
Oh no...
Hikaru, are you going home already?
I need a break.
Oh!
What is this?
It's a vending machine. You can
get drinks by putting money into it.
Hmm... oh....
Oh no, I'm late again.
Oh, Hikaru-kun...
did you start playing Go, too?
Well, yeah, kind of.
I have a friend who plays Go.
I play with him sometime, but see, I don't know anything about Go...
so I came here to try to learn some of
the basics, but I still don't understand it!
And you're hanging around here.
Oh, hey, this is the TV
broadcast of the Tengen-match.
Hikaru, what is that? There
are people playing Go in a box?
Hmm... he's pausing to think...
What would he be thinking right here...
Um... what would that be?
Well, with Touya Meijin,
he's constantly thinking of ways to improve
the status-quo even during the opening game.
Some way that we can't see.
Yeah, that's right.
He's said to be the closest to
obtaining the hand of God!
Hand of god?
I'm kind of his fan.
This man... is not an ordinary player.
He's also like me, trying to make 'God's move'.
Oh, and it's known that Touya Meijin has
a son who is also trying to become a pro.
Yes, I heard that he's pretty good.
Oba-san, don't you need to go to the class?
Oh, yeah that's right!
Shirakawa-sensei is also cute!
Welcome.
Is Akira-sensei here?
I was wondering if I could play a match with him.
Well, he's here, but...
he hasn't played anyone since last week.
He's been looking over at the game
he lost last week over and over.
Oh, you mean the game where he lost
to another boy his age by 2 moku?
I'm going home.
Um... ok. Be careful on the way.
Hey, Akira-kun, you were still here?
You better go home before it's
late... your mother will worry...
What's wrong with him?
Well, he's a little...
That move, and that move...
it was a tutoring match.
If that's his real talent...
No, that can't be.
There can't possibly be a child like that.
I don't understand it...
Who the hell is he?
Ok, class is over.
Don't forget to do your homework!
Good bye.
Be careful on your way home, everyone.
Oh, Shindou-kun.
You've been phasing out a lot,
but your social studies grades have been very good.
Have you hired a tutor or something?
Well, something like that...
but he's a little annoying sometimes.
Well, keep it up!
Yeah, I will, bye.
Be careful on the way home.
I will!
Hikaru!
What's wrong with you these days?
You aren't doing well in PE class,
and you actually do your correction
for the social studies test.
Is there anything wrong with
me doing the corrections?
I don't mean that, but...
Hey do you want to go out tomorrow?
Tomorrow?
Well, I need to do something for a friend.
You mean Go class?
What, you know?
Y..yeah.
Do you wanna come, too?
Well... I'm a little...
Nice to meet you.
Sorry, she said she really
wanted to come and watch.
Oh, that's fine with me...
It's nice to know people are
getting interested in Go.
Recently it's been popular to place
the first move on the star point, but
komoku is probably still the safest.
[note: komoku is an opening move in GO where
you place your stone under a star point, it
captures less territory, but is a great deal safer]
If you follow it up with a keima, then it's like
you've captured an entire corner already.
[note: A keima is a move in GO similar to a knight's
move in chess. Where you go 2 units in one
direction, and another unit in a different direction]
Hikaru, do you get what he's talking about?
No way.
But in an actual game, it won't always
turn out the way you want it to.
Ok, now, let's say white places his next move here.
What should black do?
Oh, I know!
Shindou-kun?
Tell me where would you put black?
16 and 5.
16 and 5. Underneath the star point.
16 and 5. You mean right here?
Hmm...
I thought you were a beginner?
Oh, was I wrong? Sorry.
No...
it's a very good move!
Whoa?
Nowadays we don't see this as much, but in the
past it was quite popular to make this move.
Oh, ok.
Oh, you can sit down.
Yes.
Am... why isn't that move seen anymore?
It's because of the komi rule.
Komi?
Since black makes the first move,
he's got the advantage, so white
gets 5 and a half moku to start with.
In other words, if white has 50 moku on the board,
black has to have 56 moku all together to win.
I see... 5 and a half moku.
What do you mean "I see". Didn't you know?
There was no such rule during Shuusaku's time.
Didn't you think that black seemed
to have the advantage every time?
I've never lost before when I've taken black.
Hmm... this guy...
I see...
komi rule, with 5 and a half extra points...
After this rule was introduced, some people
said that this move was not as good...
so that's why not many people
make this move anymore.
But we cannot deny that it is a very good move.
If you think Shindou-kun has an odd number
of stones, then put one stone on the board,
but if you think he has an even number of
stones, then put two stones on the board.
Ok, how many have you got, Shindou-kun?
2, 4, 6, 8, 9, it's an odd number.
I got it right.
Ok, then you are black.
If you are playing against a person
at about the same level, we use this
method to decide who goes first.
Um...
There is a game played by pros in this book.
Why don't you recreate their game
and kinda get the hang of the game.
I'll be back later.
Hmm...
Hey, Hikaru, do you understand it?
I guess all we need to do is to put stones
on the board, following the numbers.
See, Akari, the first move is this one.
Where?
Here, this one.
Okay! There's six more stones I've captured!
I guess you like getting all your
stones taken or something!
Mr. Akoda is bullying those
who can't play well again!
How annoying!
Oh my, why do you make such stupid moves?
People who enjoy losing are rather rare you know.
A wig?
I can't stand him anymore! Hikaru,
play against him instead of that man!
That guy hasn't made a single correct move!
Sai...
Every move he's made is there to confuse
the weaker player! I can't stand it!
I will play instead of that man
who can't even fight back.
I will make him swallow the grief that
comes from making futile moves, and
say to him at the end of the game...
Oh, I'm sorry.
What do you think you're doing, you little brat?
You've ruined the whole game!
Sorry, my hands slipped.
Don't worry I'll take it off now!
What?
No, stop, stop it!
Shindou-kun, you may go home, now!
I came with you and THIS is what you do?!
I didn't ask you to!
Go to hell!
You've made the teacher
angry, now we can't play Go!!
19th National Children's Go Tournament.
Oh yeah, there's a tournament next week...
I will take you to this. Is that ok?
Hikaruu~~~~~
Japanese National Institute of Go
What's with this atmosphere?
Some of these kids are younger than me.
Are they parents and family?
Sai, it's amazing, isn't it?
Yes. It's amazing!
There are lots of kids.
Their passion towards the game is the
same as my passion from 1000 years ago.
They show me...
that it is the same even after 1000 years.
Oh, maybe that guy is here.
Akira-kun, Mr. Hirose is here to ask you whether
you can play a tutoring match with him.
I'm sorry, but...
Are you waiting for him?
It's difficult to find him with this crowd.
The battle on the upper left hand corner...
You mean this?
Black is going to lose, if he
doesn't make the right move.
Hm...
1-2 is the key point.
Oh, close! You should've gone above it!
What?
Ooops!!!
You!
What do you think you're doing?
You're disturbing the game!
I..I'm sorry.
No need to yell.
Mr. Ogata. Well, I will take him to the back.
Ok.
Here, come with me.
Ok, everyone, continue the game.
And... could you tell me what happened?
I put it at 1,3 and he said 'you
should have put it one above it.'
That...
Oh yeah, that's right!
I gave him the pamphlet on the
National Children's Go Tournament.
Oh, is it at the Kiin today?
Yes. He didn't seem too interested, but he might be...
Akira-kun.
If he comes here, could you
hold him until I come back?
He's changed...
Well... he didn't have any rivals.
See, what you did was serious. You
can't just say 'my tongue slipped'.
Y..yes.
And what happened?
Well, we decided to cancel the
match and have them replay.
Oh well, I guess that's the only way.
You can go home now.
I'm sorry for all the trouble.
Well... well... and what did the game look like?
Umm... your change!
I shouldn't have said anything... huh?
I feel sorry for them.
Be careful.
This man...
the one we saw last time on TV, the
one who's closest to the Hand of God.
I heard that there was trouble.
Oh, Mr. Touya.
Well, please look at this.
A mere child commented on this situation...
a situation that even us pros would
take a moment to think about.
I see.
He found the key point for black to live...
I didn't know a child other
than my son could do this.
And you didn't even ask for his name?
I'm sorry.
That's all right.
If he's really that strong, sooner
or later he will come before us.
Anyways, it's all your fault, Sai!
What you wanna fight? If you act
like that I won't play Go anymore!
Shindou!
Touya...
I found you...
I finally found you...
Shindou Hikaru.
どこにあるのかな
Dokoni aru no kana?
Where is it?
ボクだけの宝物
bokudakeno takaramono
The treasure that belongs to me
今　大きな冒険へ
ima ookina bouken e
Now with a great adventure...
やわらかな日差し
yawarakana hizashi
the gentle sunlight
旅立ちの予感
tabitachi no yokan
a feeling of departure
空も花も　ホラ 笑っている
sora mo hana mo hora waratte iru
The sky and the flower are both laughing!
この先には何が待つのだろう
kono saki ni wa nani ga matsu no darou?
I wonder what waits ahead for me.
深呼吸
shinkokyuu
take a deep breath...
夢の扉にそっと手をかけて　行こう
yume no tobira ni soutto te wo kakete... ikou!
place your hand gently on the door to your dreams... let's go!
風に吹かれながら
kaze ni fukare nagara
Because I was blown by the wind!
心揺らしながら
kokoro yurashi nagara
Because my heart was touched!
真っ白な地図を片手に持ちながら
masshiro na chizu wo katate ni mochinagara
holding my belongings in one hand
風に吹かれながら
kaze ni fukare nagara
Because I was blown by the wind!
明日を描きながら
asu wo kaki nagara
Because I can't cause strife!
遠くまで　何処まで
tooku made, doko made?
far away
たどり着けるまで
tadori tsukeru made
until I reach that place...
絶対負けないよ　絶対泣かないよ
zettai makenaiyo zettai nakanaiyo
I won't lose! I won't lose!
この夢を叶えるその日までは
kono yume wo kanaeru sono hi made wa
Until the day that I make this dream come true!
あの空は笑っていた
ano sora wa waratteita
That sky is fleeting!
あの花はも笑っていた
ano hana mo waratteita
That flower is fleeting!
ボクもいつか笑うから
boku mo itsuka warau kara
Some day I will laugh with you!
どんな壁も越えるから
donna kabe mo koeru kara
I will surpass any obstacle!
もう　何も何も　コワクナイ
mou nani mo... nani mo kowakunai
I'm not afraid of anything any more!
Umezawa Yukari's
Go Go Igo!
Go! Go! Igo!
What would Miss. Yukari teach us today?
Ok, then why don't we play the "capture" game?
Teacher Yukari
In order to take the opponent's stone...
In order to capture the opponent's stone.
What you need to do is surround it.
Yuuki
Mai
In Go, if you surround the opponent's stone, you capture it
Right, Mai-chan is going to surround
Yuuki-kun's and Yuuki-kun is going
to surround Mai-chan's stones.
Yes, well done, you two!
Well, actually, this one is the best choice.
A good choice.
The best choice.
See, you don't have to put these,
and you can get the white.
Because all you need to do is to surround
the opponent by blocking the four lines.
You only need to put stones on the lines
and you can get the opponent's stone.
See, we can get the white.
Ok, let's see who can get each of your
opponent's stone first. Start with Yuuki-kun.
To be continued...
The sound the stone makes is good.
I see. So you are the one who won against Akira.
Place three stones.
That's Akira's talent.
Me, pro? I never thought about it.
A person who plays Go wouldn't be so impudent!