kono me kimi no me ni
この瞳君の瞳に
On this eye, this eye on yours,
utsuru donna mono mo
映るどんなモノも
everything will appear.
mikiwamete miseru yo shinjitsu wo
見極めて見せるよ真実を
I will tell apart the truth.
------- -------- -- -- --- - --- --- ---- ---- ---
Real-Fansubbers
Presents
----- ----- ---- --- -- --
----- ---- ---- --- - - --
Hikaru
Hikaru no Go
bokutachi wa kono jidai ni
僕達はこの時代に
How many dreams did we carry with us,
dore dake no yume kakaete
どれだけの夢抱えて
through this day and age?
namida shite mayoi nagara
涙して迷いながら
We gave them all a try, even as we cried
sore ni kakete miteru no
それに賭けてみてるの
wandering around so very lost.
boku wa sore demo hito ni hiketoranu you na
僕はそれでも人にひけとらぬような
Even then, I will find a deciding move,
kimete mitsuke yume wo te ni suru darou
決め手見つけ夢を手にするだろう
just as good as anyone else's, and take hold of my dreams.
kono me kimi no me ni
この瞳君の瞳に
On this eye, this eye of yours,
utsuru donna mono mo
映るどんなモノも
everything will appear.
mikiwamete miseru yo shinjitsu dake
見極めて見せるよ真実だけ
I'll tell apart, just the truth.
tatoe genjitsu ga
たとえ現実が
Even if the truth is
kitsuku umoresou demo
きつく埋もれそうでも
so harsh it's suffocating.
konna basho de owaru
こんな場所で終わる
I'm not going to end
boku janai
僕じゃない
in a place like this.
So this is Sai...
The Fifty-Sixth Match
The Answer to His Millennium
This is...
Touya... Kouyou...
and... Sai...
Your important match is next week?
I don't mind you coming here to relax, but...
Why don't you try to enjoy it?
Don't you enjoy being with me?
There is nothing I enjoy more than Go.
What a boring man you are.
You're going to lose if you don't relax.
I'm cheering you on, so don't lose.
Like you even know what title I'm playing for.
I lost the Honinbou match against Master
Kuwabara in the last game, but...
This time...
Maybe I'll stop by the hospital on my way home,
and check up on my opponent
for the Jyudan match.
AISHINDOU
HOSPITAL
No visitors!?
Excuse me!
Did something happen to Master Touya?
Oh, the sign?
Don't worry about it.
It's only up there because Touya-san
asked us to put it up yesterday.
He asked you to?
He said that he doesn't want
anybody bothering him today.
He's really focused on playing Go on the Internet.
Internet Go!?
Yes.
I just went in to pick up the plates from his
lunch, but he hasn't touched any of it.
Are all Go players like that?
Just who is he playing? Someone he
needs to turn away visitors for?
And he requested that he have no visitors ahead of time.
Then... this match was scheduled ahead of time.
When did he schedule it?
And with who!?
This is it!
WHITE
Sai!?
Master Touya is thinking.
Why!? They're already near the end.
Wouldn't expanding from there let him win?
Yeah, I agree.
Then why?
Is there something we're not seeing?
Hey, let's try playing it out.
Okay.
Mother, aren't you going to the hospital?
Your father told me not to come today.
He told you not to come?
He said he wants to play Go on the Internet
without getting interrupted.
He knew about this match before today.
Father scheduled this ahead of time with Sai...
Master Touya played a Nozoki!
Nozoki!? From there!?
Here?
Doesn't that seem too small to you?
Not at all, he's going to play there after
he gains territory on the side.
That may be so, but...
Perhaps he wants to get Sente there
and then go to the right side.
I think expanding there is fine though.
Wouldn't that result in a Miai?
No... Touya-kun may be right.
But wouldn't Black win by just defending?
Though Black has the advantage,
it's incredibly small.
The Meijin must have decided that he can't
beat this opponent by just defending.
He probably decided on solidly taking territory
while eliminating the white territory on the top.
Yes.
Sai can read incredibly deep
and calculate very well.
He comes up with a move to
take control of the game,
after reading all of his opponent’s moves.
I know that...
he won't let my father keep his
lead without putting up a fight.
Sai won't...
Sai definitely won't.
Touya-kun...
You know Sai?
I played him once during the
summer two years ago.
Sai disappeared from the Internet
after that match against me.
And the same Sai is now playing
Go on the Internet.
And against Master Touya of all people...
My father... arranged this match
against Sai ahead of time.
Father knows who Sai is!?
But... the only time Father left the hospital was
for the fourth game of the Jyudan match...
Did he arrange to play Sai then?
If not...
Then with someone who visited him at the hospital...
Could... one of them have been Sai?
Say, Akira-kun.
He's such a nice boy.
He came to visit the Master at the hospital today.
Shindou-kun came to see him!
Shindou came to see him!
It can't be...
I still...
can't forget about Shindou and Sai...
If the Master were to have arranged this match...
He must have met him face to face.
The Master doesn't know how to use e-mail...
Then it must have been someone...
who was around during the fourth
game of the Jyudan match...
Or...
someone who came to see him at the hospital...
No. Shindou is not Sai.
The 9th Annual Wakajishisen
His game during the Wakajishisen was not
a game that Sai would have played.
Besides, if he was Sai,
he would have become well-known
even when he was an Insei.
But... even if Shindou isn't Sai...
He might know who Sai is.
But even if Shindou doesn't...
Someone around me is connected to Sai.
Even though he can play this
well against Touya Kouyou...
We don't know anything about him...
Sai...
Just who is he!?
Do you have any ideas, Touya-kun...
as to who Sai is?
Shindou!
Are you Sai!?
I don't...
have any ideas...
But... he's playing this well against Master Touya,
the number one Go player, with five titles.
He has to be a well-known pro.
He might be a pro from China or Korea.
Can't you find out where he's
accessing the net from?
No... I'm not sure...
I might be able to trace him...
if I knew more about the Internet.
Sai is not Shindou.
Sai is...
Sai is as strong as the most experienced
players imaginable.
I remember... the match we played
on the Internet, two years ago.
My opponent, shrouded in darkness...
Yes! You!
You can't be Shindou!
Who are you?
If you're not Shindou...
Why?
Why...?
Why do I see the old Shindou in you?
The old Shindou...
Back when we first met...
Black is leading.
Ooyose is about to end as well.
But...
I can't feel any doubt coming out of him.
From this opponent...
I feel spirit.
I can feel it because I'm playing him.
This feeling...
I've felt it before...
Yes!
This atmosphere...
This pressure...
I've felt it all before.
This is!
WHITE
Captured:
Rem.Time:
BLACK
Captured:
Rem.Time:
GAME INFO
Komi: 5.5 M
Move:
Chat
Stop Obse
A good move...
He can't capture this white stone...
The black territory there... just disappeared.
It was close to begin with...
But now... Black's lost out...
It's a battle of spirit.
When it's played against you, you realize that it's
the best move you can make in this situation.
But... how many people are
able to notice this move?
How many people can make this move!?
Master Touya's moves...
None of them looks like a bad move, but...
Captured:
Rem.Time:
BLACK
Captured:
Rem.Time:
GAME INFO
Komi: 5.5 M
Move:
Chat
Stop Obse
Somehow the two sides are...
even!
This... this can't...
Even?
No.
It's just by a little, but...
The Meijin is...
losing.
Only Yose is left...
When I read the game out to the end...
I see...
myself losing by a half moku.
Unlike all the other conflicts on the board, there
is only one path you can take for Yose.
Though it's difficult to play right,
and easy to stray away from...
there is only one correct path to take.
He won't make a mistake.
He probably sees the final board just like I do.
WHITE
Captured:
Rem.Time: 1
BLACK
Captured:
Rem.Time: 1
GAME INFO
Komi: 5.5 M
Move:
Chat
Stop Obse
RESIGNS
BLACK
Captured:
Rem.Time: 1
GAME INFO
Komi: 5.5 M
Move:
RESIGNS
He resigned!?
Master Touya resigned here!?
Sai...
Sai has...
won!
Why resign!?
It's still close!
There's only Yose left, but it's very close!
I have no idea.
He read the game till the end already!?
But they still have to fight over kos...
Is he serious!?
Master Touya resigned here...?
It can't be...
Although the Meijin has played
calmly and rationally...
Sai still played above him.
That move he made...
and the moves that followed it...
Is there... no way for the Meijin
to turn the game around!?
No... there is.
There has to be!
Sai...
Who are you!?
Sai!
He's the old...
Shindou...
I've come upon an answer...
The old Shindou is the person I see inside Sai!
This doesn't...
This doesn't answer any questions though...
It's over...
Touya Kouyou...
You responded to me exceedingly well.
Each of your brilliant moves...
made my body shiver in excitement
more than ever before.
And I feel proud...
that I could respond to you beyond
the best of my own abilities.
Thank you... Touya Kouyou.
Thank you... Hikaru.
Hikaru?
Over here...
Master Touya prevented himself
from being cut here...
You would think that he needs to make that move...
But if...
before that...
he placed this stone in the corner...
See? White has to respond.
So he'll have gained more territory
than he did during the match.
Note from translator: By placing the move in the corner, Black can kill White
unless White responds. Even if White responds, it leads to Seki, in which
case White loses several stones worth of territory in the corner.
In other words, if Black had played in
the corner instead of connecting...
He would've won!
Sai, you would have lost!
Hikaru is...
absolutely right...
How's that, Sai?
Hikaru...
I finally understand...
God has...
given me a millennium of time,
simply to...
show Hikaru this match!
tsurai omoide toka ikutsu atta no kana?
つらい想い出とかいくつあったのかな？
How many sad memories did we have?
donna tanoshii hi wo
どんな楽しい日を
What kind of happy days are we going to
kore kara wa taisetsu ni shite iku no kana?
これからは大切にしていくのかな？
hold onto preciously from now?
chikaku no kouen de atsumatta ne itsumo
近くの公園で集まったねいつも
We always gathered at the nearby park
yonaka made ookina koe dashite waratteta ne
夜中まで大きな声出して笑ってたね
and laughed out loud into the middle of the night,
zutto... zutto...
ずっと...ずっと...
always... always...
onaji toki wo ima ikiteru kiseki ga
同じ時代を今生きてる奇跡が
Because I'm really happy for the miracle
sugoku ureshii kara ne
すごくうれしいからね
of being here when you are
tsugi au hi mo kitto ne
次あう日もきっとねぇ
Let's laugh together again,
issho ni waratte iyou yo
一緒に笑っていようよ
the next time we meet.
kondo wa donna yume wo
今度はどんな夢を
What kind of dreams
issho ni katariau no kana?
一緒に語りあうのかな？
are we going to talk about then?
Teacher Yukari
Yuuki
Mai
Let's do another Fuseki problem today.
Let's do another Fuseki problem today
Yuuki
Teacher Yukari
Mai
Let's do another Fuseki problem today
The problem arises when White moves here.
Should black play here...
or here? Which is better?
If he plays here...
White responds like this,
It's easier for white to make eyes...
and he can almost immediately get two eyes.
White has plenty of space.
If he plays here...
It may proceed like this,
and White won't be able to readily make two eyes.
It's tougher on white...
White has very little space.
If White comes into a place Black is strong in,
respond aggressively so that White can't live easily.
To be continued...
Sai, you say?
So you do know Sai after all!
Mr. Ogata...
Did you arrange that match...
between Sai and Master Touya!?
No! It wasn't me!
Let me play him, too!