kono me kimi no me ni
この瞳君の瞳に
On this eye, this eye on yours,
utsuru donna mono mo
映るどんなモノも
everything will appear.
mikiwamete miseru yo shinjitsu wo
見極めて見せるよ真実を
I will tell apart the truth.
------- -------- -- -- --- - --- --- ---- ---- ---
Real-Fansubbers
Presents
----- ----- ---- --- -- --
----- ---- ---- --- - - --
Hikaru
Hikaru no Go
bokutachi wa kono jidai ni
僕達はこの時代に
How many dreams did we carry with us,
dore dake no yume kakaete
どれだけの夢抱えて
through this day and age?
namida shite mayoi nagara
涙して迷いながら
We gave them all a try, even as we cried
sore ni kakete miteru no
それに賭けてみてるの
wandering around so very lost.
boku wa sore demo hito ni hiketoranu you na
僕はそれでも人にひけとらぬような
Even then, I will find a deciding move,
kimete mitsuke yume wo te ni suru darou
決め手見つけ夢を手にするだろう
just as good as anyone else's, and take hold of my dreams.
kono me kimi no me ni
この瞳君の瞳に
On this eye, this eye of yours,
utsuru donna mono mo
映るどんなモノも
everything will appear.
mikiwamete miseru yo shinjitsu dake
見極めて見せるよ真実だけ
I'll tell apart, just the truth.
tatoe genjitsu ga
たとえ現実が
Even if the truth is
kitsuku umoresou demo
きつく埋もれそうでも
so harsh it's suffocating.
konna basho de owaru
こんな場所で終わる
I'm not going to end
boku janai
僕じゃない
in a place like this.
I'm sure you want to play him in an even game.
Yes.
I wonder if I can make it happen...
'I wonder'!?
But Hikaru!
I'll make it happen someday. Be patient.
When is this 'someday'?
'Someday' is 'someday'.
Besides, it was an important match for me, too!
And I couldn't play it because of
your selfishness, don't you get that?
Umm...
I'm sorry...
Man,
it was your fault for coming to me.
Torajirou...
He was a very clever...
and truly kind person.
So what you're saying is
that I'm stupid and unkind.
Hikaru...
The Fiftieth Match
Sai of the Fujiwara
Why did God...
revive me in Hikaru's mind?
It's true that
Hikaru is growing very quickly,
and it brings me both
pride and joy in teaching him...
But,
what about...
what about my Go?
I hate this existence.
The chance to play him finally came...
the game against him when I was
supposed to master the divine move...
But...
I couldn't do it.
In a game that I couldn't play as myself,
I couldn't head for that divine height with him.
If I cannot master the divine move...
why am I here?
How long am I supposed to wait?
A thousand years ago...
Everything began from there.
Every day...
I played Go within the palace.
But...
when I played the other tutor that His Majesty had,
in a match to decide who would
become the only tutor for His Majesty...
he placed a white stone that
was hidden among his stones,
in his Agehama during a moment
when everyone else was distracted.
When I tried to raise my voice...
You...
just...
Hey!
You! You just placed a black stone
from your Goke into your Agehama!
W-What?
That is what you just did!
What a stupid excuse that is.
You just placed a black stone that was
hidden in your Goke into your Agehama
when everyone's attention was on the board!
You are the one making excuses!
Stop it. Quiet.
I do not wish to even consider that such
a dishonest act has occurred before me.
Continue.
I lost.
I could not contain my anger.
I was charged with cheating during the game
and driven out of the capital.
I no longer had a reason to live.
Two days after the match...
I drowned myself.
But...
I wanted to play Go a lot more.
My soul, unable to find peace,
possessed a Go board,
and after a long period of time
heard a voice of a young boy
on Innoshima, within the sea of Seto.
He was...
Torajirou.
Young boy,
if you can see the tears of grief that I shed,
let me dwell in a corner of your mind.
I was able to play Go as much
as I wished, together with him.
He changed his name to Shuusaku, and
became the successor to the Honinbou.
I believed that I would be able to
master the divine move together with him.
But...
he could not defeat disease and...
Torajirou...
Honinbou Shuusaku...
I will never forget the time that I spent with him...
Never...
Sai...
So that's how you want to play it...
Yes...
and then you appeared before me.
This stain just won't come off.
There's no stain. It's clean.
This.
Where?
Here!
There's nothing. Where!?
Can you see it?
That's what I've been saying...
Can you hear my voice!?
You can hear my voice, can't you?
There's nothing...
Who are you!?
The gods before me...
I thank you.
Now I can...
I can...
I can return to the present world,
once more.
But...
I was concerned at first.
After all, Hikaru, you had never played Go before.
You like Go that much?
Yes!
You still want to play Go?
Too bad, I have no intentions of playing Go.
Hikaru!
Shindou-kun!
Say, can't you possess someone other than me?
Probably not...
Fine, I guess it would be
okay to play once in a while.
And!? And!?
Where are we playing?
In a Go Salon.
Domestic and international
travel
Sky Blue
Travel
Tours of various locales -- Rental
Go
Salon
Weekdays
1PM~10PM
Weekends 12PM~9PM
Hair
Studio
JOY
Wow, it's filled with old men.
Oh there's another kid.
Can I play him?
Umm, yeah... but he's...
Looking for someone to play?
This was how I met Touya Akira.
Yeah.
Okay, I'll play you.
I believed that this was
the destiny that God gave me.
Yes...
The wheels of destiny began to turn.
Okay!
17-4 Komoku on the upper right-hand corner.
17 and...
one...
one... two...
one... two... three...
one... two... three... four...
He holds the stone like a beginner.
I think I played him around three times,
through Hikaru's body.
16-17 Komoku on the lower right-hand corner.
16-17... here it is.
3-16.
3-16...
8-5.
Let's see... 8... There it is!
This...
This isn't the best move...
nor is it the strongest move.
He made this move to see how I would respond.
He's testing to see how strong I am...
from far above me...
Touya Akira had great potential,
despite the fact that he
was the same age as Hikaru.
So...
Go on.
Y-Yeah...
Wow, he doesn't even notice the crowd.
That's why I...
He's waiting for my Kosumi isn't he?
I suppose there's nothing wrong with that.
15-16
Kosumi!
Come, let's see what you have in mind!
I resign!
Sai...
He resigned.
He declared his own defeat.
He faced up to me despite his fear.
Our third match was a match over the 'internet'.
He's strong.
I feel a wall higher than when Shindou defeated me.
He's...
He's... not Shindou?
Could it be!?
The black in the center has...
no chance of living.
He resigned...
Sai, how was it? Was it Touya?
Without a doubt.
Oh.
And? What did you think?
Sai?
Yes...
he was very strong.
He had great instincts.
He thought during all the important moves.
And? Did Touya get any stronger?
I was the one that became stronger.
And Hikaru, you, too.
Me?
You watched dozens of my games, after all.
Yes.
Together with Hikaru,
I learned modern Go.
Through playing Touya Akira,
Touya Akira began to chase after me,
and Hikaru began to chase after Touya.
Oh yes, I forgot about that match.
When I was playing Touya Akira during
Hikaru's match in the Go tournament...
Touya...
how far...
have I caught up to you?
I want to play...
Touya...
Just like you're chasing after Sai, I'm chasing after you.
I'll catch up to you some day.
13-4
I'll go to 11-8, and then...
Hikaru. 13...
I want to find out.
Sorry, Sai...
I can't tell without playing him myself.
I want to find out the gap between him and me.
11-8!?
I'm playing!
Now that I think about it,
that was when I first realized
how interesting Hikaru's ideas were.
You must have been mortified then.
Stop messing around!
T-Touya...
I'm going to catch up to you
someday, if you keep chasing after my illusion!
You?
Would you like to play now instead of 'someday'?
Ever since then, Hikaru has...
run straight towards Touya Akira.
He became an Insei to chase after Touya,
and he passed the pro exam.
He really has become strong.
Hikaru...
Your name!
Your name! I said I'd remember it.
Shindou Hikaru!
My name is...
But...
now that I think about it,
that was around when I stopped
playing Go against people other than Hikaru.
And to think, I have more
opportunities to play stronger players now.
Hikaru...
Hikaru, do you not intend to let me play anymore?
Even though I'm closest to
mastering the divine move?
Oh, God! Why did I come
back in the mind of Hikaru!?
God...
So there is no answer after all...
Hikaru!
Wake up!
Hurry and wake up!
What is it? Why are you being
so loud this early in the morning?
Wake up and play me!
I haven't even eaten breakfast yet,
I don't want to.
No 'I don't want to's.
We have to play to come
closer to mastering the divine move.
Hikaru you're the only person I can play.
What's wrong Sai?
You're acting weird.
Not at all. It's just the conclusion I came to.
Come on, hurry! hurry!
Let me sleep for just another half hour.
No!
Hikaru! Hey! Hikaru! Wake up!
Good night.
Let's play, Hikaru!
Hikaru!
tsurai omoide toka ikutsu atta no kana?
つらい想い出とかいくつあったのかな？
How many sad memories did we have?
donna tanoshii hi wo
どんな楽しい日を
What kind of happy days are we going to
kore kara wa taisetsu ni shite iku no kana?
これからは大切にしていくのかな？
hold onto preciously from now on?
chikaku no kouen de atsumatta ne itsumo
近くの公園で集まったねいつも
We always gathered at the nearby park
yonaka made ookina koe dashite waratteta ne
夜中まで大きな声出して笑ってたね
and laughed out loud into the middle of the night,
zutto... zutto...
ずっと...ずっと...
always... always...
onaji toki wo ima ikiteru kiseki ga
同じ時代を今生きてる奇跡が
Because I'm really happy for the miracle
sugoku ureshii kara ne
すごくうれしいからね
of being here when you are
tsugi au hi mo kitto ne
次あう日もきっとねぇ
Let's laugh together again,
issho ni waratte iyou yo
一緒に笑っていようよ
the next time we meet.
kondo wa donna yume wo
今度はどんな夢を
What kind of dreams
issho ni katariau no kana?
一緒に語りあうのかな？
are we going to talk about then?
Yuuki
Teacher Yukari
Mai
It's "Yose" again (Sente, Gote)
We're continuing with Yose today.
There are two "Yose" spots, but...
When there are two Yose spots
left, how would you play, Yuuki-kun?
Here.
Well done!!
You got to play both spots.
If you play here first...
But, if you play the top first...
You can only get one of the spots.
Black lost out on 3 moku.
You lost three moku compared to earlier.
We call places like this,
A place where the opponent will respond to
where white has to respond to black, Sente.
Sente
And, we call a place where your
opponent doesn't have to respond to, Gote.
A place where your opponent won't respond
Gote
The key to "Yose" is to play the Sente spots first.
The key to "Yose" is to play the Sente spots first!!
To be continued...
How dare you slander
Torajirou's name with a fake signature!
You said all that, why don't you try?
It's impossible to turn a game around
once you're at a disadvantage to a pro.
Atsushi
Kurata
Meijin
Most of the way
Atsushi
Kurata
Meijin
Most of the way
Atsushi
Kurata
Meijin
Most of the way
Atsushi
Kurata
Meijin
Most of the way
14-4, approach by one space.