kono me kimi no me ni
この瞳君の瞳に
On this eye, this eye on yours,
utsuru donna mono mo
映るどんなモノも
everything will appear.
mikiwamete miseru yo shinjitsu wo
見極めて見せるよ真実を
I will tell apart the truth.
------- -------- -- -- --- - --- --- ---- ---- ---
Real-Fansubbers
Presents
----- ----- ---- --- -- --
----- ---- ---- --- - - --
Hikaru
Hikaru no Go
bokutachi wa kono jidai ni
僕達はこの時代に
How many dreams did we carry with us,
dore dake no yume kakaete
どれだけの夢抱えて
through this day and age?
namida shite mayoi nagara
涙して迷いながら
We gave them all a try, even as we cried
sore ni kakete miteru no
それに賭けてみてるの
wandering around so very lost.
boku wa sore demo hito ni hiketoranu you na
僕はそれでも人にひけとらぬような
Even then, I will find a deciding move,
kimete mitsuke yume wo te ni suru darou
決め手見つけ夢を手にするだろう
just as good as anyone else's, and take hold of my dreams.
kono me kimi no me ni
この瞳君の瞳に
On this eye, this eye on yours,
utsuru donna mono mo
映るどんなモノも
everything will appear.
mikiwamete miseru yo shinjitsu dake
見極めて見せるよ真実だけ
I'll tell apart, just the truth.
tatoe genjitsu ga
たとえ現実が
Even if the truth is
kitsuku umoresou demo
きつく埋もれそうでも
so harsh it's suffocating.
konna basho de owaru
こんな場所で終わる
I'm not going to end
boku janai
僕じゃない
in a place like this.
Are you... Sai?
No! No! I'm not!
Why do you think I'm him?
He reminded me of you during the match.
He would have gotten an advantage if he played
in the corner instead of connecting.
See? Black's winning by a little this way.
You're right.
Everyone around us is starting
to notice Hikaru's strength.
I can see it.
The brilliant future that...
Hikaru has, shining above him...
The future I lack...
The Fifty-Eighth Match
One-Color Go
Japanese Go Institute
Ouza Match Finals Game 1
Kurata Atsushi 6-Dan
Kamaishi Yoshirou 9-Dan
I resign.
Thanks for the game.
Kurata-kun!
Are you done?
Judging from the smile, I'm guessing you won.
I'm going to blast through this year.
I'm seriously aiming for a title now.
Sounds like you're doing well.
I guess even Kamaishi 9-dan is no
match for Kurata-kun anymore.
Hey, what's going on over there?
Over in Nagano.
The fifth game of the Jyudan match?
So that's why you stopped by.
Curious?
Of course!
Let's see, the fax did arrive...
Oh, here it is.
This is the latest one.
It's from half an hour ago.
The game's still pretty even, after all this time.
So I think Master Touya's going to end up
winning, since he is more experienced.
Mr. Ogata just isn't as good as Master
Touya with the finishing blow.
He was defeated in the seventh and
final game of the Honinbou match,
and he may lose today in the fifth and
final game of the Jyudan match.
I'm sure he'll toughen up once
he gets used to title matches.
His game is starting to get solid and professional.
Now that you mention it...
But more importantly, what's
wrong with Touya Kouyou?
Did something happen to him?
But Ogata-san is playing it rationally.
What!? The Meijin is still playing moves like that!?
That's unlike him.
Unlike him?
Master Touya... lost...
He lost?
Ogata takes the Jyudan title
In the fifth game of the 39th Jyu-
dan match where Ogata 9-dan
was challenging Touya Kouyou
Jyudan (Meijin, Tengen, Ouza
and Kisei) started at 9am on the
19th, and ended about 8:55pm.
Ogata won by resignation after
move 231, and captured the ti-
tle with 3 wins and 2 losses.
This is the first title for Ogata,
and Touya Kouyou now has
four titles left to defend.
With formulas like these, what
you want to be solving for is...
Listen up, this part is going to be on the test.
Why did Master Touya lose?
Was it because he played Go against Sai on the Internet?
I wonder if he lost because he was tired
from it, or if it threw him off rhythm...
I hope that's not it...
What do you think, Sai?
I doubt that would be the reason.
But I would have to look at the Kifu.
Kifu?
Yes.
I can tell what he felt during the
match if I look at the Kifu.
Really?
Yes.
Seems like you're finally back to normal, Sai.
Well, you've been acting strangely lately.
You looked really sad all the time.
You're not Touya, but you looked just
as inconfident and worried as him.
I was worried.
D-Did I say something wrong?
N-No, not at all.
Not at all...
I guess Master Touya is really going to retire.
He's not the type of person who changes his
mind after he's decided on something.
He isn't...
Yeah...
This is bad...
RAMEN
Yamanishi
I want to look at the Kifu, but I'm not sure
if I can get it at the Institute or not.
Weekly Go won't come out until next week...
RAMEN
I'm getting hungry.
Welcome!
Kurata-san!
Shindou?
What are you doing at a place like this?
Idiot? Shindou, are you an idiot?
I'm hear to eat noodles of course.
Not that!
I'm asking why you're in this area.
I'm not going to treat you just
because you sat down there.
I can pay for it myself!
What would you like?
Ramen.
Oh. Me, too.
Y-You, too!?
Two Ramens!
Did you have an appointment for
a tutoring game around here?
Did you have one?
Yeah.
On my way home.
Oh yeah, Kurata-san...
Can I see the Kifu from the Jyudan game
yesterday if I go to the Go Institute?
I saw it.
You did!?
I was at the Go Institute yesterday.
So the publishing division showed it to me.
They send you updates on the
game live over the fax.
Here you go.
I know that Master Touya lost... I
read about it in the newspaper.
What... kind of a game was it?
A game you wouldn't expect from Touya Kouyou.
Wouldn't expect!?
Don't you think he plays a well-balanced game?
He attacks when he should but
holds back when he needs to.
But...
It was as if he was off balance.
It was like...
Was it... poorly played?
Bad?
It was a great game.
He played interesting moves one after another,
even though it was the last game of a title match.
His game has become more youthful!
He ended up losing, but I'm impressed.
I mean, he can still change
his game despite his age!
Touya Kouyou is incredible.
He's still at his prime.
That's my impression of the game.
Are you going to eat, Shindou?
O-Of course.
So it was a good game...
I'm glad.
Then he might not retire.
That makes defeating him all the more
worthy a goal. I'm getting excited.
His son put up a great fight, too.
Kurata-san, you've played Touya Akira before!?
I beat him last month in the second
preliminaries for the Meijin match.
But he's made it to the third preliminaries
for the Honinbou match.
A mere 2-dan is in the third preliminaries!
He has no rivals amongst the lower dan players.
He might really become threatening by summer.
It's faster than I could've imagined.
Touya...
So you've already made it that far...
Can I not even catch up to him? Let alone surpass him...
Thank you, come again.
That was a great meal.
See ya.
Okay.
Kurata-san!
Are you busy right now?
Do you have some time?
What if I have time?
Please play a game against me.
No way.
What'll I do...
I wonder if he's bitter about my saying
that I didn't want his autograph...
Well then...
I want Kurata-san's autograph!
Kurata-san, will you give me your autograph
as a reward if I beat you?
Kurata Atsushi
Well, I doubt someone like me could win,
but I can't ask for Kurata-san's autograph for free!
It's something I have to work hard for.
Reeeaally?
You want it that badly?
I guess I have no choice.
Well, let's go to a Go salon somewhere then.
Score!
He's really easy to manipulate!
Okay!
We'll test my strength out, by seeing how
well I can play against Kurata-san!
GO
Beginners
Welcome
You pay the entrance fee, okay?
For both of us.
Okay.
Welcome!
K-Kurata the pro!
Kurata!?
Oh! It's Kurata! Kurata 6-dan!
It really is him! I'm a fan!
Can we play?
O-Of course! This way, please.
Kurata-san! We'll be cheering you on
for the Honinbou match next month.
We were all just talking about how Kurata-san's
Honinbou title will follow Ogata-san's Jyudan title.
Thanks much.
Mr. Kurata, who is your companion here?
Him? His name is Shindou.
He just became a pro.
He asked me to give him my
autograph if he beats me!
So he's Kurata-san's fan! How cute!
May I have your autograph later as well?
Did we have any autograph paper?
An even match is too much,
so Shindou you can play first with no Komi.
Okay.
But, I won't give you my autograph for nothing!
Okay!
I don't want it!
Okay, let's play!
Huh?
They're both white.
Here are some Black stones.
Nah, let's play like this.
One-Color Go.
One-Color Go!?
Yeah, it's played with White
or Black, just one color.
Shindou, yours is Black, okay?
Okay, good luck!
Huh!? These white stones are black?
Come on, say 'good luck'!
G-Good luck!
This stone is...
Black!?
Looks like this is Shindou's first
time playing One-Color Go.
It's just starting to get interesting.
Playing with just white stones?
In other words...
If all of the stones in this game we're playing,
are replaced by white stones...
Can you do it?
No way.
Wow, they can both play with only white.
Was the kid white or black?
He's black!
Keep quiet, I'm going to lose track here.
He's better than I thought.
I can still kind of keep track...
Me, too.
You can see more than you
thought you could, right?
You remember it by the shape.
The shape of the stones.
Shape, huh...
Oh yeah...
Didn't he teach Mr. Gokiso a lesson
during that convention?
Shape? But to us...
I've lost track.
I stopped focusing for a second, and I've lost track.
Me, too.
I'm completely confused.
Done already?
We've still got a ways to go.
Right, Shindou?
Mr. Gokiso isn't a match for him.
Wow Muranishi-san, you still
know what's going on!?
I lost track a long time ago.
It's just determination now. I'm
determined to keep track of it.
That's impressive.
Oh, someone can still see it?
Okay, we're going to ditch you now.
Okay!
A furious battle's started in the corner!
...or that's what it looks like.
Yeah, we have no idea what's going on...
It just looks like this clump of white stones
that keeps getting bigger and bigger.
We've still got a ways to go!
And? Who's winning?
Don't ask me.
Who's winning?
Shindou is!
U-Umm... Mr. Kurata...
Who's winning right now?
He's working very hard to stay ahead right now.
He must really want my autograph.
He won't give me a chance.
He's tough.
There!
I misread it!
I'm saved!
Shindou just made a big mistake.
... I'm saved?
I'm not playing Touya Kouyou or
old man Kuwabara right now.
He's a kid that just became pro.
Wait! Isn't this...
Shindou's first time playing One-Color Go?
It isn't just Touya Akira...
who's going to be threatening me from below...
There's another one!
Crap! I lost track of the stones!
Around there... it's around there...
Umm... Umm...
Will Black die if I move here?
I resign.
Ahh! Crap!
I totally misread this part.
It was complicated, but I'm sure I could have won!
I totally messed up by making a ko here.
I should have moved cautiously here.
I should have replied on the right side, right?
Right? Kurata-san?
He...
He has realized it, too.
He's seen Hikaru's hidden strength.
Do you have autograph paper? Extra ones?
Ohh! Of course, here you go.
Here.
Huh? Weren't you going to give him
an autograph only if he won?
I don't want it...
Huh? What is this?
Kura
It's just 'Kura'?
I'll sign the rest of it when you
beat me in a formal match.
Kurata-san...
Mr. Kurata, may I have an autograph as well?
One for me, too, please.
Of course! Of course!
Line up if you want one!
Kurata-san's... recognized me...
What!?
What's wrong?
Did something happen?
Turn the volume up!
O-Okay...
In an earlier press conference, the top Go player,
Touya Kouyou, with four titles,
has announced his retirement!
What!?
Master...
Touya's...
tsurai omoide toka ikutsu atta no kana?
つらい想い出とかいくつあったのかな？
How many sad memories did we have?
donna tanoshii hi wo
どんな楽しい日を
What kind of happy days are we going to
kore kara wa taisetsu ni shite iku no kana?
これからは大切にしていくのかな？
hold onto preciously from now?
chikaku no kouen de atsumatta ne itsumo
近くの公園で集まったねいつも
We always gathered at the nearby park
yonaka made ookina koe dashite waratteta ne
夜中まで大きな声出して笑ってたね
and laughed out loud into the middle of the night,
zutto... zutto...
ずっと...ずっと...
always... always...
onaji toki wo ima ikiteru kiseki ga
同じ時代を今生きてる奇跡が
Because I'm really happy for the miracle
sugoku ureshii kara ne
すごくうれしいからね
of being here when you are
tsugi au hi mo kitto ne
次あう日もきっとねぇ
Let's laugh together again,
issho ni waratte iyou yo
一緒に笑っていようよ
the next time we meet.
kondo wa donna yume wo
今度はどんな夢を
What kind of dreams
issho ni katariau no kana?
一緒に語りあうのかな？
are we going to talk about then?
Let's cover 'Seki' today.
Teacher Yukari
Mai
Mai-chan, have you heard of Seki before?
Nope!
Seki... when neither side can capture the other
Seki is a situation when you are both close to capturing,
but can't capture the opponent.
Don't both White and Black have a shape
where they're close to capturing
and close to getting captured?
If it's Black's turn...
If Black goes to capture
If you try to capture, you get captured instead!
and Black plays here...
White plays here, and five stones get captured.
If you try to capture, you get captured instead!
If White goes to capture
It's the same with White.
If you try to capture, you get captured instead!
If White goes to capture
They will both get captured if they move.
You won't get captured, if you don't try to capture!
But if they don't move, then they don't get captured.
If you have a Seki, leave it be until the end of the game.
If a Seki forms, the game ends with the seki.
Neither side can count the Seki as their own territory
It's not counted for either side as a territory.
Seki seems difficult, but it's a way to avoid
getting captured when you're about to die.
To be continued...
Touya Meijin's retiring!?
What are you talking about? I can't believe it.
Why did he retire?
Why!?
No fair! It's too early!
I haven't taken a title from Touya Meijin yet!
What a self-centered man you are, Touya Kouyou.