Fujiwarano Sai, a go player from the Heian period...
has passed through time and returned to
the world in the mind of Shindou Hikaru,
in order to obtain the Hand of God.
Kimi ga ima boku wo sasaete
君が今僕を支えて
Now you are,
holding me up strong!
boku ga ima kimi wo sasaeru
僕が今君を支える
Now I am,
holding you up as well!
Dakara Mayoi nagara mo tomo ni ikite ikou yo
だから迷いながらも共に生きていこうよ
So let us now, while wandering live together
Mirai e to...
未来へと
towards the future
Elite-Fansubs presents
Hikaru no Go
Nakama to tawamaure sorenaride itemo
仲間と戯れ　それなりで居ても
Even when I'm capricing with my friends,
mono tari na sa wo kanjite shimau
もの足りなさを感じてしまう
I feel an emptiness in my heart.
Sameta me de mirarete
冷めた目で見られて
Looked at with cold eyes,
Kawaita jidai no kaze ni fukareteiru
乾いた時代の風に吹かれている
I'm blown by the wind of a dry age
Fuan na, kokoro to yuuki ga
不安な 心と勇気が
Feelings of doubt and courage
senaka awase ni natteiru
背中合わせになっている
are back to back
dakedo ima nara yume wo, kono te de kanaete miseru yo
だけど今なら夢をこの手で叶えてみせるよ
but I'll make these dreams come true now with my own hands.
Kizutsuite koware sou na hi mo
傷ついて壊れそうな日も
The days where I'm hurt and about to break,
Namidashite komaraseru hi mo
涙して困らせる日も
the days where I cry and trouble you
aru keredo bokura wa sore wo
あるけれど僕達はそれを
They all exist, but we will
koete ikunda dare yori...
超えていくんだ誰より
get over it heading higher
ue wo mezashite!
上を目指して
than anyone else!
The Twenty-Seventh Match
A Place to Go Back To
Japanese
Go
Institute
Winning every game is hard.
Of course it is. You are playing
against those who are well aware of
their goals and walking towards it.
Shindou!
Waya!
The next study session with
my master is on Tuesday.
Shindou, you went to Mr. Morishita's study session?
Yeah.
What was it like?
Of course it helped him a lot, right?
Yeah.
K-Kinda.
Maybe I should join a study session too.
But playing go all day long and all night long?
You're right, we need to let lose sometimes.
Hey! Wanna, go do karaoke
on our way home tonight?
Yeah! Let's! Wanna go bowling afterwards too?
Okay.
Let's ask Isumi-kun too!
Okay, I'll call home then.
Okay, then I'll...
Haze Public Junior High School
I...
I don't want to do Karaoke or go bowling,
I just want to play at the Go club sometimes...
What will you do after I go here?
Here?
Yup, that's right.
Yes!
Hikaru!?
What's up?
You always go home right after class.
You study Go at home everyday, right?
Yup! I teach him!
What are you talking about?
You don't teach me anything.
Don't worry about me. What
about the tournament?
You girls are going, right? It's almost time, right?
Yeah.
What's wrong with that response?
What about Mitani? Did he quit?
I tried calling him a few times...
I barely even talk to him now
because I'm in a separate class.
I can't bring up the Go club anymore...
I hope he comes back someday too...
Seems like it's become lonely here at the Go club.
Hey! Want me to play you guys for a bit?
He's gotta be bored playing you
two crappy girls all the time.
I'll play all three of you at
the same time! Okay? Okay?
Hikaru...
Please don't come anymore.
Ouch...
Natsume-kun and I were just talking about
it... Mitani-kun might come back eventually...
And when he comes to take a look...
if Hikaru was having fun here...
Mitani-kun wouldn't like it...
He wouldn't come anymore...
Hikaru...
Then just this once!
Just once won't matter!
Get another Go board, I'll play you guys.
Hikaru!
Wasabi.
Really...
You two place all the stones you want!
You think that little of us!? I'm really
going to place all the stones I want!
Okay!
How's this!
Just that? Are you sure it's enough?
Just this!? But there's so many.
Heh, just you wait.
Ahh! I'm getting nervous!
Good luck.
Chemistry Lab
Ahhh... Hikaru wins...
Ahh! I'm so angry! I placed so many stones too!
He just keeps taking them!
Hikaru, you're not holding back at all.
You're always doing that to me. I've
got to let the stress out somehow.
Mitani-kun!
Mi-Mitani!?
Mitani-kun.
Hikaru just dropped by today.
I don't care whether Shindou's here or not.
I forgot my chemistry book,
so I came to get it, that's all.
I'll just get it tomorrow.
You must be happy, getting
lessons from the spectacular Insei.
About you forgetting your
chemistry book... is that true?
The rearmost desk by the windows.
Akari...
Chemistry
Mitani Yuuki
It's here...
Akari... I...
It was nothing. Mitani-kun forgot his
Chemistry book, so he came to get it, that's all.
I don't think he had Chemistry today.
Oh no.
Tamako-sensei wasn't here today.
Hikaru, you idiot!
Stop it Akari!
Now Mitani-kun's never going to come back!
Clean up the stones already and go home!
I'm sorry! I won't come anymore!
I get it! Stop it!
Come on to the Basketball Club!!
We're at the Chemistry Lab afterschool.
It was exactly a year ago wasn't it?
When Shindou pulled me into the Go club.
We put up a poster...
But no one's coming... not even one.
Mitani-kun won't come back either...
This sucks.
Let's make another poster!
Mitani-kun came last year
when we made a new poster!
Anyways, you girls have to practice
for the tournament next month.
What!? Are we really going?
We're going. I already asked the
girl from the Volleyball club. So we
have three including you, Kumiko.
Good luck!
I wish I could go too, but I'm the only guy.
There's nothing I can do.
Umm... ahh... I came to join the Go club... may I?
I heard we're having a quiz today.
Oh no!
Umm... is Mitani-kun here?
Hey! Mitani!
Mitani-kun.
Oh, it's you Natsume. What is it?
It's about the Go club...
Go club?
You're still in that?
Against those two girls that
don't know how to play.
They know how to play now! They're
starting to learn how to play a good game.
But that's not what I'm here
for. We got a new member.
And?
That seventh grader isn't strong or
anything, but he's about as good as I am.
Well, we have two male members now!
So?
So if you come back we can go to the tournament!
This again?
Mitani-kun...
Won't you play first board, Mitani-kun!?
You there. The bell's rung,
go back to your own class.
Wait for me after school. I'll come again.
Natsume!
Don't bother.
I'm not going back.
You there!
Well, to begin with, in yesterday's homework...
Chemistry Lab
Okay! We're doing the lab
on page 47 of your textbook,
so each group is to get whatever you need for it.
Be careful.
It wasn't me! He was...
I'll clean that up so.
Fujisaki
Akari
What is this?
Match records? They keep this crap?
Man they play a lot...
Five books in total?
Oh so they have five whole members.
The girls that don't know how to play and Natsume and...
Koike Hitoshi?
And?
Mitani Yuuki
Mitani!
Hey Mitani!
What are you doing! Help out!
What!? Natsume-kun you gave up after that!?
But...
Fine, I'll try asking him again tomorrow.
I'll go again too.
I'm sure something good'll happen
if we just keep on trying, Senpai.
Yup, Koike-kun's in the Go club now too so...
Oh! Is that the new poster?
You're done already?
Is this okay?
I thought about putting a Tsumego in but...
Nah, it's great! It's very well done.
Thanks.
Ah! Mitani-kun!
You're going with us to the tournament!?
You're going to play first board for us!?
No!
Why!? Why not!?
If you're not going to the tournament...
then, you came here...
to play us every now and then?
[loae666: MWAHAHAHAHA You have fallen into
their trap! You have taken a step down a very
slippery slope! Within the next 25 episodes, you WILL
be playing in the tournament! MWAHAHAHAHA]
That's all.
Ahhh! That's fine!
We've got to get another board!
Umm, can you play both Natsume-kun
and Koishi-kun to begin with?
I'm Koike from the seventh
grade. Nice to meet you.
Play us after that!
We have to show him how much better we are now.
Waaasssuuuppp?
Kaneko-san!
I came to get some practice and drink some
buds. We are going to a tournament after all.
I thought I should come here as much
as possible and get some practice.
And? Who's the best player here?
I see.
Let's play then.
I'm going to Nigiri.
You're really confident. You're
going to play me evenly?
It's our first match. We have to play evenly to
see how strong we are relative to each other.
But go ahead and put some
stones down if you want.
What? Me? Play with a handicap?
Oh so you are confident. Then let's play.
Come on.
Oh, I'm first, You're at a disadvantage,
so wanna tack on 10.5 moku komi?
[note: Komi is usually 5.5, she's making fun of Mitani here]
Why you!
Oh god please! Don't let Mitani-kun leave!
It's been awhile, I'm a little rusty.
I'm not trying either.
Oh! Kaneko-san's stones connected.
No. Mitani-kun knows that he's at an
advantage, so he didn't try to forcefully
kill them, and let them connect, that's all.
But Kaneko-san is a lot stronger than either I
or Koike-kun. No wonder she was so confident.
About time you resigned, isn't it?
Yeah... you're rather strong.
What about the "I resign?" the "I resign?".
Well, there are opponents that
you really don't want to resign to.
But that won't work. "I resign"
How about a 3 stone handicap from now on?
If you think you can win at 3 stones, just try it.
Oh, those words are going to hurt when you lose.
Oh yeah! We've got to record this!
We're finally starting to fill in Mitani-kun's book.
It was always blank.
Don't record a game like this.
Why not?
We've got to make a book for Kaneko-san too.
Make it! Make it! Please!
I have to record my increasing wins and
decreasing handicap against this guy.
Thanks Kaneko-san! It was fun today.
Hey Kaneko-san, you're in the
same class as Hikaru, right?
Shindou?
Yup. Could you tell him?
That Mitani-kun's started
to show up at the Go club?
To stop worrying?
Okay. But Shindou's going to be absent
tomorrow, so I'll tell him on Monday.
Absent?
Yeah, he told the teacher something about
going to a Wakajishisen or something.
Wakajishisen?
I'm sure he has his own
tournaments. Leave him alone.
Cya.
Good bye.
G..Good bye.
Mitani.
We're playing at three stones tomorrow too!
Who said I was coming tomorrow?
Then I'll make sure to mark
down your loss by default.
But why is it three stones!?
You lost every game today at three stones!
I'll make it four stones if I lose
every game tomorrow too.
Like I said! Who said I was coming tomorrow!
Yume ni miteita shiawase nara
夢に見ていたシアワセなら
I thought that someone would bring me,
Dareka ga hakonde kureru to omotteta
誰かが運んでくれると思ってた
the happiness that I dreamed of.
Isogi ashi no machi de
急ぎ足の街で
In a quick paced city,
iiwake bakari...
言い訳ばかり
all I'm doing is listing off excuses,
Minna mo onaji to usobuiteta
みんなも同じとうそ ぶいてた
and lying to myself, that everyone was doing the same.
hontou ni kimi wa ima manzokushiteru no?
本当にキミはいま　満足してるの？
Are you really satisfied right now?
kokoro no mannaka minukaretayoude
心の真ん中 見抜かれたようで
It feels as if you've straight through my heart.
Anata to deaenakattara
あなたと出会えなかったら
If i had not met you,
Itsuwatta egao no mama!
偽った笑顔のまま
I would still only have a false smile!
Uwabe no taido ya kotoba wo
うわべの態度や言葉を
My words and disagreements
kurikaeshita ne
繰り返したね
would only have been superficial.
anata no hitomi no chikara de
あなたの瞳の力で
With the power of your gaze,
watashi wa kawatte yukou
私は変わってゆこう
I am starting to change!
Kinou no yuraida kimochi wo
昨日の揺らいだ気持ちを
In order to cast off
nugisuteru tame ni
脱ぎ捨てるために...
the swaying feelings of yesterday.
Go
Igo!
Umezawa Yukari's
Let's do "Fuseki" today.
Teacher Yukari
Fuseki is the first stage of a game of Go.
[Fuseki] is
the placement of the first stones, and is important!!
[note: Loae is horrible at this >_< I'm maybe about 10k
in strength in the early game. I make up for it in the mid
game though, and I'm horrible at the end game >_<]
Yuuki
Mai
This is my territory
over here!
You start declaring which areas you
want to make your own territory.
This side is
my territory!
If you move on further...
In this were to happen, this area
might become black's territory.
This area here may become white's territory.
Black's territory looks larger, so
let's say that white moves in.
When this happens, the Fuseki
is over and a fight begins.
[Fuseki] has no set rules
So think about different ways of playing!!
It's important to play the "Fuseki" portion while
trying to maintain a balance with your opponent.
To be continued...
Yup!
The Ninth Wakajishisen
I thought Mashiba-san would be a little better than that.
I wonder which one's the pro.
Heh! Beating me at a place like this is meaningless.
You're worthless unless you pass the pro exam.
Why you! Mashiba!