胸の鼓動　熱くゆるがす
mune no kodou atsuku yurugasu
My heart walks, searching for something exciting
刺激求めて歩く My Heart
shigeki motomete aruku MY HEART
That will passionately sway the beating in my chest.
時間だけが過ぎる毎日じゃ
jikan dake ga sugiru mainichi jya
If I just wait for the time to pass everyday.
変化はない
henka ha nai
nothing's going to change.
Woo Wooo
止まらない　信じたい　進みたい
tomaranai shinjitai susumitai
I won't stop. I want to believe. I want to move forward.
自分の力試す My Life
jibun no chikara tamesu MY LIFE
I will test my strength during my life.
でも早歩きしたって見落とすだけ
demo hayaaruki shitatte miotosudake
But even if I walk faster.
I will definitely lose track of
そう確実に
sou kakujitsu ni
the important things.
Baby for you...
明日は明日の風が吹く
ashita ha ashita no kaze ga fuku
Tomorrow's wind will blow tomorrow.
それでも　今この瞬間を強く生きたい
soredemo
but I want to make the most out of this moment now.
ima kono shunkan wo tsuyoku ikitai
It's fantasy
さまよったとしても
samayotta to shitemo
Even if I'm wandering,
見たことない世界でも
mitakotonai sekai demo
even if I'm in a strange new world,
何よりも 自分を信じ立ち向かおう
nani yori mo jibun wo shinji tachimukaou
I'll stand up to it,
believing in myself more than anything else.
It's destiny
どんな場所にいても
donna basho ni itemo
No matter where I am,
つつむ空は一つだから
tsutsumu sora ha hitotsu dakara
I'm surrounded by the same sky.
ねぇ　もっと 翼広げて
nee motto tsubasa hirogete
so I'll be able to fly
羽ばたけるよね
habatakeruyone
with my wings spread out.
Have you seen Isumi-kun?
He looks much more confident than last year.
He not only beat Murakami-kun,
but Tsujioka as well...
We can't let these young ones take the world yet.
Excuse me Master Kuwabara, but Master
Ogata already has two titles.
It's incredible. Touya-kun was
a new first dan not long ago,
and he's already in the Honinbou league.
Master Touya has signed a contract
with the Bei'jing team of China!
Doesn't it feel like the Go world is moving?
The whole Go world.
The new wave may be coming...
With Touya Akira in the lead.
The Seventy-Third Match
Shindou vs Touya
Hey, Shindou. What are you doing at the Institute
when you don't even have a match?
Kurata-san!
What am I doing? Master Morishita's
study session is today.
I looked at the tournament pairings for the
first preliminaries for the Meijin match.
You're playing Touya Akira in the first round!
Yeah, it's all thanks to you Kurata-san!
Thanks to me?
The reason Touya's still in the
first preliminaries this year is
because you beat him last year, Kurata-san.
He's moved on in the preliminaries for
every other title, I can't reach him.
Well he is Touya Akira!
And since he's so busy, our match
still hasn't been scheduled.
Well, bye.
Hey, Shindou. Bring the half-finished
autograph that I gave you.
Autograph?
Remember, I only wrote half my name?
I'll write the rest of it if you beat Touya.
Kura
Oh! That!
Where did I put that!?
It's a favor. Isn't that encouraging?
I don't... umm... need encouragement?
Oh! Don't need encouragement? That's
some confidence against Touya.
Confidence?
I hope your match gets scheduled soon.
I look forward to the result.
Bye.
'I hope it gets scheduled soon.' He said.
I wonder when we'll actually get to play.
Oh! The study session! Study session!
Shindou-kun's grown a lot since he came back.
I don't know what happened while he was gone.
But he's settled something inside.
I resign.
He's good. Without a doubt.
Shindou-kun has become really strong.
This move here beat me.
Have you read through it all?
He cut my shape apart early in the
game, and I couldn't do anything.
Shindou! That's the spirit! Keep going!
Okay!
Saeki! You won't even be able to beat that
Ashiwara who studies under Touya at that pace!
Sorry.
And Waya!
Don't take it out on us!
What am I taking out on you?
But if you don't hurry up, Shindou's
going to pass you by.
I know that...
Shindou-kun, want to play me next?
Yes, please!
Touya...
I'll play you any time!
I'm home.
Welcome home, Hikaru.
The Go Institute sent you a notice for a match.
A notice?
It's been decided!
It's in two weeks... Touya...
A record of Touya's Honinbou match...
Our match is just starting.
Touya... let's play. We can't start until we play.
The Sai that you wanted to play is gone, but...
Sai is in my Go, so...
I don't know if you'll notice him but...
I'll get to be as strong as you are
and play you from now on.
Is that enough for you?
My rank on the midterm exam dropped.
You got the ranking already? We
haven't gotten it yet in our class.
The teacher must have forgotten about it!
Akari, bye-bye.
Bye-bye.
Hikaru!
Oh, Akari.
You're playing Touya-kun tomorrow, right?
How do you know about it?
I looked at Weekly Go.
Remember, it has a section
on this week's matches?
Do you always get nervous
on the day before a match?
Why do you ask?
Well... You had such a stern face, Hikaru...
A match against Touya is special.
Akari, do you have some time?
Hmm? What?
Want to play a game?
Playing you may calm my nerves a little.
I-I'd be happy if you'd play me, Hikaru.
Okay, let's go to my place then!
Hmm? What's wrong?
Hikaru... you've changed...
Really?
Yeah... you've changed.
Maybe you've gotten used to being
a pro... you've grown up.
You've changed, too.
Really!?
How? How did I change?
Hmm.. You've gotten smaller.
You got taller!
Hikaru you're such a tease.
Have a safe trip.
I'll be going.
I'll be going now.
Japanese Go Institute
You've got a big match today, Saeki-san.
Yeah... Ashiwara, who studies
under Touya, is my opponent.
I'm sure Master Morishita will be
furious if you lose this game...
Stop pressuring me!
Good morning, Saeki-kun!
Ashiwara-san...
Hello to you too, Waya-kun!
Hi...
Good mor...
Saeki-kun, good luck today! Let's both do our best.
Hey, Saeki-san...
What is it?
I've been thinking...
Maybe we Morishita students are the only ones
who feel a rivalry towards the Touya students...
That's taboo, Waya.
Waya! Saeki-san!
Shindou!
Good morning.
Morning.
Isumi-san called last night.
He passed the pro exam!
Really!?
But there's a few games left in the exam still!
He's undefeated, he won again
yesterday and passed.
Yes!
Isumi-san said to me, 'Look after me, senpai'!
I'd better work hard then.
Isumi-san passed...
Mashiba-san...
But he was muddling around for so long.
Mashiba!
I'm sure he'll climb up really fast once he's a pro...
He has the skill...
Every year, new guys keep coming. It's so stupid.
I'm not going to lose to you today, Waya!
You're playing Mashiba-san, Waya?
Yeah.
You're playing Touya, right?
... until I play him.
Touya...
Ochi, what were you talking
to Touya about just now?
Touya said 'looks like you're
on a winning streak' to me.
Is that it?
And I replied 'it's nothing compared to you,
who's already in the Honinbou league'.
And then I asked Touya 'you've got an easy
win today against Shindou, right?'
He said 'of course' or something, right?
I doubt he has anyone other than the
top pros in his sight right now.
What did Touya say?
'I won't know until I play him.'
Wasn't there a rumor that Shindou was Touya's
rival when he first became an Insei?
Everyone thought it was false,
but I guess it was true.
We've got to start working harder.
Yeah, I'm only just starting.
Waya, you're playing me next week, right?
I look forward to it.
You little brat! I do, too!
I guess I should give it my best, too.
Yeah! Let's do our best, Saeki-san.
Touya.
We're finally playing.
I haven't played you since the third
board match in the Go club.
It's been two years and four months.
It's been that long?
Yeah, it was long.
I looked at your match against Master
Zama on Weekly Go. It was close.
It was a good game, but he kept the lead from
the early game all the way to the end.
He is the former Ouza,
I didn't expect to beat him on my first try.
But next time, I'll have improved, too.
I saw how good you are from your matches
against Master Zama and Mr. Hagiwara.
Today, it's my turn to show you how good I am.
I didn't waste the last two years
and four months, either.
Good luck.
Let's play, Touya!
Komuko on the upper right corner!
That was fast...
This isn't how someone plays
with five hours on the clock!
It's speed Go!
As if he couldn't wait to play this game.
He didn't respond to my kakari,
and he responded with a kakari.
So he's not willing to wait for the action.
Fine!
We'll start a fight in the corner.
I couldn't wait to play this game either!
Ring
My
Bell
noizu darake no mune de
ノイズだらけの胸で
I listen to my fate through the din in my heart.
noizu darake no mune deunmei wo kikiwakeru
ノイズだらけの胸で運命を聴きわける
It occurs to me.
hirameku
閃く
hiramekuyume ha watashi no naka demezame o matteta
閃く夢は私の中で目覚めを待ってた
My dream was waiting for the time
to wake up within me.
mezame o matteta
閃く夢は私の中で目覚めを待ってた
Music
Is
My
Thing
I can be more like myself
jibun rashiku nareru
自分らしくなれる
Music
In
My
Heart
ときめきならして
Let the pounding of my heart be heard
tokimeki narashite
ときめきならして
Music
Is
My
Thing
karada wo ugokasu
体を動かす
I move my body
karada wo ugokasu
体を動かす
Music
In
My
Heart
Feel the light
hikari wo kanjite
光を感じて
Music
Is
My
Thing
shiro to kuro de egaku
白と黒で描く
I draw with black and white
shiro to kuro de egaku
白と黒で描く
Music
In
My
Heart
owaranai haamoni
The unending Harmony
終わらないハーモニー
owaranai haamoni
We'll have a serious match between
Mai-chan and Yuuki-kun today.
Good luck.
This move by white was too aggressive.
This move in the game was rather
good, but there is a better move.
Here.
It's an Atari, so White runs.
You extend here, and then...
Black can either play here to
capture these two stones,
or play here to get this stone in a net.
White is stuck in a Miai.
I saw...
a shadow of Sai in Shindou!
That shadow that I... I've always been chasing after.
I'm not Sai.
Unfortunately...
It's you...
Touya...
There's...
someone else inside you.