kono me kimi no me ni
この瞳君の瞳に
On this eye, this eye on yours,
utsuru donna mono mo
映るどんなモノも
everything will appear.
mikiwamete miseru yo shinjitsu wo
見極めて見せるよ真実を
I will tell apart the truth.
------- -------- -- -- --- - --- --- ---- ---- ---
Real-Fansubbers
Presents
----- ----- ---- --- -- --
----- ---- ---- --- - - --
Hikaru
Hikaru no Go
bokutachi wa kono jidai ni
僕達はこの時代に
How many dreams did we carry with us,
dore dake no yume kakaete
どれだけの夢抱えて
through this day and age?
namida shite mayoi nagara
涙して迷いながら
We gave them all a try, even as we cried
sore ni kakete miteru no
それに賭けてみてるの
wandering around so very lost.
boku wa sore demo hito ni hiketoranu you na
僕はそれでも人にひけとらぬような
Even then, I will find a deciding move,
kimete mitsuke yume wo te ni suru darou
決め手見つけ夢を手にするだろう
just as good as anyone else's, and take hold of my dreams.
kono me kimi no me ni
この瞳君の瞳に
On this eye, this eye of yours,
utsuru donna mono mo
映るどんなモノも
everything will appear.
mikiwamete miseru yo shinjitsu dake
見極めて見せるよ真実だけ
I'll tell apart, just the truth.
tatoe genjitsu ga
たとえ現実が
Even if the truth is
kitsuku umoresou demo
きつく埋もれそうでも
so harsh it's suffocating.
konna basho de owaru
こんな場所で終わる
I'm not going to end
boku janai
僕じゃない
in a place like this.
Let me...
Please let me play, Hikaru.
You've got to be kidding!
If I let you play, you're going to win for sure...
Shindou, you've finally come all this way.
I've been waiting for this.
A handicap...
He'll have to play differently if he has a handicap.
I'll play with one!
The Forty-Ninth Match
A Painful Match
Twenty minutes for him to play the first move...
What an unexpected beginning.
Let's see how the Meijin responds to this move.
Hoshi on the lower right corner.
It's so stuffy in there.
I'm so tired.
It's the first time that
something like this has happened.
He didn't look nervous though.
Touya-kun was here, wasn't he?
Let's ask him his thoughts about the
long time he spent on the first move.
Mr. Ogata...
Even Master Kuwabara!?
That took some time. The match
did start on time... Right, Amano-san?
Yes. Shindou-kun surprised me.
He spent twenty minutes on the first move.
On that note, Master Kuwabara,
are you here for Shindou-kun today?
Yes. I think highly of that boy.
I had a feeling when I passed by him.
Passed by? Are you basing
your opinion of him only on that?
Only that.
He says it's his intuition.
Intuition?
You'll never beat me, Ogata-kun,
if you think so little of my intuition.
Even if it is just intuition, it's impressive
that he has Master Kuwabara's attention.
Not just Master Kuwabara...
He has Mr. Ogata's too, and, Touya
Meijin requested to play him for this match.
Oh! He requested the game!?
Requested?
Waya, Shindou...
He's our...
No...
Don't say anymore...
Meijin is probably interested
because Akira-kun thinks of him as a rival.
Is he your rival, Touya-kun?
Well... umm...
No.
The Meijin has to be interested
in the boy regardless of his son.
Master Touya is...?
That man has good intuition, just like me.
13-14. Boushi.
Boushi is when you limit a stone's ability to expand into the center.
Uh... Boushi?
Shindou just...!
Started a fight!
This early in the game!
What is Shindou thinking?
13-17. Hai.
I won't stand a chance unless I fight early on.
I'll bring him into a difficult battle.
Whoever can read further will win.
I have to create a weak
point that he'll want to attack.
When my opponent comes to end the game...
That is when black's path to victory will appear.
18-16. Suberi.
But... he isn't playing what I want him to.
He's being careful.
If the game goes any further...
It's only going to get more difficult.
Then...
18-9. Osae!
What is Shindou-kun doing?
He's being way too aggressive.
All of his moves look hopeless.
He went too far here, too, right?
Black has a bad shape.
Touya-kun, Shindou-kun
is far from being your rival.
Black's done for if he
loses these stones here, right?
It's the kind of shape one would want to attack.
But... my father didn't attack it.
I'm sure it's because he didn't
want the game to end too quickly.
What do you think, Ogata-kun?
I believe that black is at a disadvantage. I
wonder what Master Touya thinks about it.
He has good intuition, after all.
Black looks like it's about to die here.
But it looks dangerous when I read far ahead.
It would probably be best if I
don't get lured in right away.
This match... it looks poorly played.
But it is rather deep.
That's not all.
Why?
He's a new first dan.
A fourteen year old child, but...
What is this atmosphere around him?
What is this pressure I feel?
The battle that started in the
corner has spread across the board.
Shindou probably wanted to
spread the battle across the board
in the hopes of a mistake by his opponent. But...
It didn't work out.
The result is crystal clear!
Black's been wiped out! Wiped out.
What was he thinking?
But Master Touya sure is being careful.
It may be a good thing for young
people to take risks, but he went too far here.
There was no way it would work against the Meijin.
Shindou...
See, he resigned.
It ended just as I expected.
I'm sure Shindou-kun is disappointed.
Waya...
Yeah, they're going to
start the discussion over there.
Looks like I win the bet.
But... it doesn't affect my opinion of Shindou.
It was an interesting match.
Ogata-kun, I'm going to bet on the
boy again, if this ever happens again.
Akira-kun.
I-I'll be right there.
Master Kuwabara...
The match just now...?
Yes.
It makes sense if the boy put a
large handicap on himself for the game.
Shindou!? Put a handicap on himself!?
Against my father, the Meijin!? It can't be!
I don't know why he did that,
but isn't he an interesting boy?
This is it...
I would have liked to have
played without any handicap.
I don't know why you played the way you did.
But you still couldn't hide that something you have.
He didn't just find out that I
placed a handicap on myself...
Touya Meijin's also gotten an idea of Sai's strength.
I felt a pressure from you similar to
that of an extremely experienced player.
Next time we play, let it be an even match.
Yes, let it.
Thanks for your work.
Let's start from the first move.
To put a handicap on himself...
Why would he do that?
What an interesting boy he is.
I don't understand him.
I played him two years ago.
It was... as if I was playing my
father. He seemed that strong.
But... when I played him again six months later,
he was so weak he seemed like someone else.
Stop messing around!
T-Touya...
Someone else?
That sounds strange...
'I didn't chase after someone that weak as a rival.'
I thought to myself... I got very angry over it.
But... one day he said to me...
I'm going to pass you by someday,
if you keep chasing after my illusion.
The next time I saw him, he was an Insei.
And now... he's facing my father
in the Room of Deep Contemplation.
So you're the one that pulled
him into the world of the pros.
Touya... what was your name?
Akira.
Touya Akira, I see. I'll remember that.
Touya-kun.
How is it going over there?
I wonder what's wrong with Shindou-kun.
He won't say anything, no
matter what anyone else asks.
Oh yes, the record keeper said something strange.
Strange?
Master Touya supposedly said that he wanted
to play Shindou-kun in an even match next time.
My father...
Really!?
Yup. Though, Touya
Meijin didn't say so straight out,
so Amano-san can't put it into the article.
My father, the Meijin, said he
wanted to play Shindou in an even game?
Hey, you're not getting on!? Touya-kun!
Touya-kun!
I don't think he saw through all your strength.
But Touya's dad sure is incredible. He
realized that it wasn't just a poorly played game.
Next time, let it be an even match.
Yes, let it.
I'm sure you want to play an even game.
Yes.
I wonder if I can make it happen.
I wonder!? But, Hikaru!
I'll make it happen someday. Be patient.
When is this 'someday'?
'Someday' is 'someday'.
Besides, it was an important match for me, too!
And I couldn't play it because of
your selfishness, don't you get that!?
Umm...
Sorry...
Man, it was your fault for coming to me.
Wasn't Shuusaku better, Sai?
Unlike me, Shuusaku let
you play all the games, right?
Oh wait, you called him Torajirou, right?
The
Hint
to Tsumego
The
Hint
to Tsumego
The
Hint
to Tsumego
The
Hint
to Tsumego
The
Hint
to Tsumego
The
Hint
to Tsumego
I wonder why Torajirou didn't want to play.
The
Hint
to Tsumego
The
Hint
to Tsumego
Didn't he want to become a Go player?
What a boring guy.
That's... that's my... my fault!
I was impatient when I returned to the real world,
and I didn't know that I
would get to meet you, Hikaru.
So I demanded a lot of Torajirou,
because I didn't want to lose this opportunity.
Then what... did Torajirou die
an early death because of you?
N-No! Torajirou was a good person!
When there was an epidemic, and
people around him began to get sick,
he watched over them at
the risk of getting sick himself.
And...
Torajirou...
He was a very clever...
and truly kind person.
So what you're saying is
that I'm stupid and unkind.
Hikaru...
Father...
After your game today,
did you say to Shindou Hikaru that you
wished to play him in an even match next time?
Yes.
Shindou Hikaru made my father, the Meijin, say that...
Just who is Shindou?
tsurai omoide toka ikutsu atta no kana?
つらい想い出とかいくつあったのかな？
How many sad memories did we have?
donna tanoshii hi wo
どんな楽しい日を
What kind of happy days are we going to
kore kara wa taisetsu ni shite iku no kana?
これからは大切にしていくのかな？
hold onto preciously from now?
chikaku no kouen de atsumatta ne itsumo
近くの公園で集まったねいつも
We always gathered at the nearby park
yonaka made ookina koe dashite waratteta ne
夜中まで大きな声出して笑ってたね
and laughed out loud into the middle of the night,
zutto... zutto...
ずっと...ずっと...
always... always...
onaji toki wo ima ikiteru kiseki ga
同じ時代を今生きてる奇跡が
Because I'm really happy for the miracle
sugoku ureshii kara ne
すごくうれしいからね
of being here when you are
tsugi au hi mo kitto ne
次あう日もきっとねぇ
Let's laugh together again,
issho ni waratte iyou yo
一緒に笑っていようよ
the next time we meet.
kondo wa donna yume wo
今度はどんな夢を
What kind of dreams
issho ni katariau no kana?
一緒に語りあうのかな？
are we going to talk about then?
This time it's "Yose"
We'll be doing Yose today.
Yuuki
Teacher Yukari
Mai
Yose is the last step in Igo.
"Yose" is when you make the borders between your territories
clear at the very end of the game.
It's when you make the borders between
your territories clear at the end of the game.
Let's take a look at this.
The border between black and
white isn't completely set here.
Once you get good at "Yose" you can increase your territory
or reduce your opponent's territory!!
What should White do to reduce
Black's territory as much as possible?
Then Mai-chan you start.
Here.
If I go here?
There's a cut point here, so black connects.
The border becomes clear
Black's territory became 10 moku!!
This makes black's territory ten moku.
But if white plays like this, Black plays
here, and Black's territory is twelve moku.
But, if you make a mistake...
Black gained 2 moku!!
Black gained two whole moku.
Next time is "Yose" too!!
I am Sai of the Fujiwara.
The reason I have been in the world for a
thousand years, is just to master the divine move.
That's what I thought, but...
But why!?
God! Why did I come to Hikaru!?