kono me kimi no me ni
この瞳君の瞳に
On this eye, this eye on yours,
utsuru donna mono mo
映るどんなモノも
everything will appear.
mikiwamete miseru yo shinjitsu wo
見極めて見せるよ真実を
I will tell apart the truth.
------- -------- -- -- --- - --- --- ---- ---- ---
Real-Fansubbers
Presents
----- ----- ---- --- -- --
----- ---- ---- --- - - --
Hikaru
Hikaru no Go
bokutachi wa kono jidai ni
僕達はこの時代に
How many dreams did we carry with us,
dore dake no yume kakaete
どれだけの夢抱えて
through this day and age?
namida shite mayoi nagara
涙して迷いながら
We gave them all a try, even as we cried
sore ni kakete miteru no
それに賭けてみてるの
wandering around so very lost.
boku wa sore demo hito ni hiketoranu you na
僕はそれでも人にひけとらぬような
Even then, I will find a deciding move,
kimete mitsuke yume wo te ni suru darou
決め手見つけ夢を手にするだろう
just as good as anyone else's, and take hold of my dreams.
kono me kimi no me ni
この瞳君の瞳に
On this eye, this eye of yours,
utsuru donna mono mo
映るどんなモノも
everything will appear.
mikiwamete miseru yo shinjitsu dake
見極めて見せるよ真実だけ
I'll tell apart, just the truth.
tatoe genjitsu ga
たとえ現実が
Even if the truth is
kitsuku umoresou demo
きつく埋もれそうでも
so harsh it's suffocating.
konna basho de owaru
こんな場所で終わる
I'm not going to end
boku janai
僕じゃない
in a place like this.
The Fifty-First Match
Kurata 6-dan
Hikaru...
They're not all playing games either.
There are tutoring games and lectures, too!
But... wow, there are a lot of people here.
Hikaru, Hikaru! Over there!
Net Go Corner
I guess this'll cheer Sai up a bit. I'm glad we came.
I wanted to play you with no handicap.
Next time, let us play an even game.
Yes, let us.
It did turn out to be an unsatisfying game for Sai.
I feel sorry for him.
Hikaru, let's go watch a game!
Yeah. And let's go watch Ochi's
new first dan match next week.
That jerk was dissing my game
with Waya. I've got to get him back.
Hikaru's trying to be nice to me.
When I took an important game
away from him by being selfish...
I'm the one that's at fault.
I won't...
I won't ask him to play someone else...
too often.
Vendor's Corner
That'll be 1,500 yen.
Thank you very much.
You've got to stop selling those cheap
fans, and start selling the expensive Go boards.
Oh, Mr. Gokiso!
THAT treasure of a board hasn't sold yet,
but I've already sold three of the other ones.
Which ones have you sold?
This one! The Kaya Go board! Special, 200,000 yen!
This is Kaya? Well I guess you can fool most
people with it. But it's probably only worth 80,000.
Sir!
Just hand the pen over. You
can't just put 'special' on it.
Kaya Go Board
Kaya Go Board
Kaya Go Board
Kaya Go Board
Kaya Go Board
Kaya Go Board
Kaya Go Board
This is much more useful.
You seem like you're better at business than Go.
You've got to be kidding, I'm a pro.
Remember, I'm the reason
you got into this convention.
Work hard at getting their money.
FREE PLAY AREA
Oh.
That large cluster is about to get taken. It's in atari.
You're right. This is no time to
be thinking, he's got to protect it.
He didn't notice!
It'll get taken this turn, and the game'll end.
AHH! He hasn't noticed either!
T-This is much more exciting than a pro match.
Would you like to play?
We're still registering players.
Play? No thanks.
I'll play if you don't want to, Hikaru...
I just told myself not to ask. I'm so stupid.
A Go board, they're so nice.
I'd like to buy one some day.
Why not buy it now?
I'm sure you'd improve
quicker if you played on a good board.
Oh, they're just selling boards and stuff.
What were you expecting?
There's a special on this one today, just 25,000!
Kaya Go Board
That one's on special for just 200,000!
It's made out of the best
domestic grown Kaya there is!
Kaya!? This is Kaya!?
This isn't Kaya. It looks like it, but it's not.
Sai, what's Kaya?
It's a wood used to make Go boards.
Your grandfather's board is made of Kaya.
All good boards are made of Kaya.
What about mine?
That's Katsura.
Then...
This isn't Kaya!?
Hey! Stop making up stuff to ruin my business!
Who's causing the trouble over here?
Don't get in the way of his business.
I'm not!
Hikaru, try placing a stone on it.
AHH! What are you doing!?
The sound is too dull to be Kaya.
Then...
Ahh! He played a stone on something we're selling!
You worthless brat!
What's going on?
Is there a problem?
Not at all. A little child played a
stone on a board we're selling, that's all.
But it's...!
Hey.
We're going to make you pay for the Go
board you scratched if you say anymore.
U-Umm... I think I'll wait until I
get a little better before I buy a board.
O-Oh wait!
Hey. Go boards are made of wood, so it's
going to get dented if you play a stone on it.
It's really valuable, so please don't do it again.
Okay. I'm sorry.
But...
A Go board that Honinbou Shuusaku used?
You're selling this, too?
1,000... 10,000... 6,000,000!?
That's a treasure that we got from
an antique shop just the other day.
Master Shuusaku used this board
when he went to Takamatsu to tutor Go.
You went to Takamatsu?
I went to all sorts of places with Torajirou.
This is something that got stored
there after Master Shuusaku signed it.
Gokiso the pro!?
Signed? In Takamatsu? Torajirou?
Honinbou Shuusaku
Hikaru! That's not Torajirou's writing.
Then...
It's a fake!?
You again!? It's the real thing! Go away!
S-Sir!
How dare you lie like that!?
That's not Shuusaku's writing!
This is the real thing. There's no doubt about it.
See! Even a pro says so!
Why is a pro saying such a lie!?
Oh! You must be the one
that wrote this on the board!
H-How dare you say that to Mr. Gokiso!
What's the problem this time?
How dare you slander
Torajirou's name with a fake signature!
How dare... umm... what?
So what is it?
What is it?
Mr. Gokiso, your tutoring game is
about to start, please come this way.
Like anyone's going to pay
attention to what a kid says.
Wh!?
Honinbou Shuusaku
Fake... you can tell?
Yup. They're both lying.
Those other boards aren't Kaya either.
I knew it.
What?
I thought that might be the case.
That's not Kaya, that's new Kaya.
Well, I don't know too much about it either,
but the vendor who came until
last year was a very nice person.
He taught me a lot of things.
New Kaya is similar to Kaya, but its real
name is Spruce, and it's a foreign species of wood.
The board surface is smooth, so it's
a great material for making boards.
But Kaya is more expensive than new Kaya,
so I hear that some immoral vendors
sell Spruce under the pretense of Kaya.
But...
Why did you change vendors?
Mr. Gokiso... the pro you
met earlier, recommended him.
I couldn't refuse.
Why not?
Events like this can't be held
without the help of the pros.
I'll keep an eye on that vendor.
Sorry about all that.
Oh well. We came all this way to enjoy
ourselves. and this happens. Doesn't it suck, Sai?
Wanna go watch another game?
Oh, he's angry. He's angry.
Sai?
Hikaru, over there.
Tutor Go Corner
The man from earlier is playing a tutoring game.
Oh, he's playing the person who
ran away without buying the board!
Look, look. You're falling apart everywhere.
The upper-left's died too...
I guess you just can't improve
without playing on a good board.
What a horrible game.
Yes. The stronger player is
just picking on the weaker.
This is not a tutoring game.
I suppose I can't do any more.
You still have a chance!
You still have a chance, mister. Good luck.
What can you do at this point?
It's fine with me, would you like to continue?
I've had enough. No thanks.
The child behind you says you can come back.
Then why don't you play?
You did say all that, why don't you play?
Hikaru, sit down.
Do you realize that he's a pro?
I can do it.
Tell him to take Torajirou's
board off the display if you win.
Okay.
Hey, you're really going to play?
If I win this game, take
Shuusaku's board off the display.
Give it your best shot.
It's a promise.
But won't he raise a fuss later if I let Sai play?
He thinks you're just a child.
If he is to lose to you, he'll be
too ashamed to tell anyone about it.
If that's the case...
Go, Sai!
Okay!
14-4 approach by one space!
Are there any questions?
Mr. Kurata, it's almost time.
Well then, I guess this is a
good place to end the lecture.
Thank you, thank you.
Mr. Kurata, may I have your autograph?
Sure thing!
I hope you get a title this year.
Yeah, I'd like a title.
Meijin might be nice.
Might as well write it.
Meijin, most of the way.
Kurata
Atsushi
Meijin
Most of the way
Atsushi
Kurata
Meijin
Most of the way
Atsushi
Kurata
Meijin
Most of the way
Atsushi
Kurata
Meijin
Most of the way
Atsushi
Kurata
Meijin
Most of the way
Can't show this to Touya Meijin.
Sir, may I have an autograph, too?
Okay, let's do Kisei for this one.
Soon to be Kisei, Kurata Atsushi.
Then I'll take one with Honinbou, please!
Sure thing!
Eventually Honinbou, Kurata Atsushi.
Sounds nice. I wouldn't be
surprised if it really happened.
I'm scheduled for a tutoring game
with you after this. Take it easy on me.
Of course.
I should have taken Mr. Kurata, too.
Did something happen?
I just had a tutoring game with Mr. Gokiso.
And what did Mr. Gokiso do?
It was horrible.
Horrible?
All his moves seemed to be
traps, and he just pummeled me.
That's horrible. I wonder if
something bad had happened to him.
From what I hear, Mr. Gokiso's stocks
went down and he's in a bit of trouble.
He shouldn't be taking his anger
out us over something like that.
I resigned quickly, and left.
Though the child behind me
said I could still make a come back.
It's impossible to make a come
back against a pro after you fall behind.
That's what I thought.
If he could do that, it would
mean that he's stronger than a pro.
Oh, hey you!
The tutoring game from earlier.
That child continued
playing, and it's turned around!
What!?
It's over. This is the end.
Sai is incredible.
He plays moves that I would never have imagined.
How... how can it be... it's got to be
because I underestimated him. It has to be.
Let's see.
Is this it?
Kurata-kun!
Hey! What are you doing!?
Oh, I played an embarrassing game.
You'd laugh over it.
What? It was funny? I
would've liked to have seen it.
Excuse me.
The promise.
Hey! Don't forget about your promise!
Hey, hey.
Did you win?
Y-Yeah.
It was Sai who won, not me.
From what I hear, you
managed to come back from behind.
Is it true? It can't be. Is it?
He was a pro. If you could do that...
Hey, have I seen you before?
Are you a pro?
I'm Shindou. I just became a pro this year.
Oh I know! I saw you on Weekly Go!
Now I get it! You're a new first dan!
What's with this guy?
Say, what was that promise you mentioned earlier?
That's...
Welcome!... Oh! Mr. Kurata!
Sir, we don't have any goods worthy of you, today.
Kaya, 200,000. What's this price tag?
T-This is... umm... ahh...
I mean... this is...
You mean this is?
I misplaced the tag! This is the real one.
Thank you for taking the time to tell me!
Sir, is there anything else?
Haven't you sold a few already?
U-Umm ahh...
Please show me a list of
people who have bought from you.
Yes, please.
A list?
And...
is this it?
But I know nothing about Shuusaku's writing.
This is?
A fake!
For sure?
For sure!
Yes, I said it's for sure, so it's for sure!
Because you said so?
Yes!
Hey, can you do something about this?
Please take Shuusaku's board off display.
I'd like to talk to you in private.
Because you said so, huh?
Just so that you know, don't be
too proud of beating Mr. Gokiso.
It would be incredible if you beat
me, but he's a pro who's over the hill.
Who is he?
Umm, who are you?
Register
What!? You don't know me!?
I'm Kurata! The pro player, Kurata!
Most of the way Meijin or Honinbou!
You're that strong, Mr. Kurata?
Register
Yeah. But it's not that hard
to beat the people above you.
Everyone above me is desperate.
Touya Meijin is at his peak right now.
Old man Kuwabara seems like he's got
it easy, but he's actually quite desperate.
He's just barely protecting the title of
Honinbou by using bluffs and mental traps.
He'll fall down soon enough.
By either myself, or maybe
Ogata-san'll do it before me.
The really scary people are coming from below me.
That's why I'm more scared of
Touya Akira than Touya Kouyou.
The fights against the
people below me will be tough.
Though it's far in the future.
First I have to bring down the top.
He's really confident, isn't he?
What was your name again?
It's Shindou, Shindou Hikaru.
Not many people don't know me.
Register
Hey, can I have that fan?
Kurata Atsushi
You want it right, here you can have it.
Sir, that's store merchandise, so...
umm... could you pay?
Don't you want it? You can have it.
Want it?
No.
You don't want it!?
You've got to be kidding. But
everyone wants it. Why not?
I'm a pro already, so...!
Shindou Hikaru
Kurata Atsushi
Ahhh! You ruined my autograph!
Idiot! Idiot! Idiot!
How can you write such
ugly letters next to my name!?
K-Kurata-san, your writing is just as bad.
It really is poorly written,
Torajirou's was so much better.
Who would want this?
Thanks.
You're peculiar.
So are you.
Ahh! My tutoring games are about to start.
I'll remember your name. As
Honinbou Shuusaku's Writing Authenticator.
Writing Authenticator?
You'll regret turning my autograph down.
Sai, are you satisfied now?
Satisfied! Satisfied!
He knows a lot about Shuusaku's writing?
What a strange child.
tsurai omoide toka ikutsu atta no kana?
つらい想い出とかいくつあったのかな？
How many sad memories did we have?
donna tanoshii hi wo
どんな楽しい日を
What kind of happy days are we going to
kore kara wa taisetsu ni shite iku no kana?
これからは大切にしていくのかな？
hold onto preciously from now?
chikaku no kouen de atsumatta ne itsumo
近くの公園で集まったねいつも
We always gathered at the nearby park
yonaka made ookina koe dashite waratteta ne
夜中まで大きな声出して笑ってたね
and laughed out loud into the middle of the night,
zutto... zutto...
ずっと...ずっと...
always... always...
onaji toki wo ima ikiteru kiseki ga
同じ時代を今生きてる奇跡が
Because I'm really happy for the miracle
sugoku ureshii kara ne
すごくうれしいからね
of being here when you are
tsugi au hi mo kitto ne
次あう日もきっとねぇ
Let's laugh together again,
issho ni waratte iyou yo
一緒に笑っていようよ
the next time we meet.
kondo wa donna yume wo
今度はどんな夢を
What kind of dreams
issho ni katariau no kana?
一緒に語りあうのかな？
are we going to talk about then?
Have you guys seen things like this before?
Something that records the moves
that were played in a game.
Kifu
Yup.
This is called Kifu. If you place stones on the board
following these numbers,
you can replay an old game.
Teacher Yukari
You can replay a match from the past with a Kifu!!
Mai
Yuuki
Teacher Yukari
Mai
Yuuki
You can replay a match from the past with a Kifu!!
Want to give it a try?
Sure.
If you replay a Kifu, you can learn all sorts of things, like the flow of a game, attacking, and defending.
Even a match from hundreds of years
ago can be replayed with just one Kifu.
To be continued...
My first opponent is...
Touya!
He's already declared hostilities against you.
Touya-kun.
Shindou-kun's opponent for the first round is...
I know.
I'll catch up to Akira... I'll surpass him!