胸の鼓動　熱くゆるがす
mune no kodou atsuku yurugasu
My heart walks, searching for something exciting
刺激求めて歩く My Heart
shigeki motomete aruku MY HEART
That will passionately sway the beating in my chest.
時間だけが過ぎる毎日じゃ
jikan dake ga sugiru mainichi jya
If I just wait for the time to pass everyday.
変化はない
henka ha nai
nothing's going to change.
Woo Wooo
止まらない　信じたい　進みたい
tomaranai shinjitai susumitai
I won't stop. I want to believe. I want to move forward.
自分の力試す My Life
jibun no chikara tamesu MY LIFE
I will test my strength during my life.
でも早歩きしたって見落とすだけ
demo hayaaruki shitatte miotosudake
But even if I walk faster.
I will definitely lose track of
そう確実に
sou kakujitsu ni
the important things.
Baby for you...
明日は明日の風が吹く
ashita ha ashita no kaze ga fuku
Tomorrow's wind will blow tomorrow.
それでも　今この瞬間を強く生きたい
soredemo
but I want to make the most out of this moment now.
ima kono shunkan wo tsuyoku ikitai
It's fantasy
さまよったとしても
samayotta to shitemo
Even if I'm wandering,
見たことない世界でも
mitakotonai sekai demo
even if I'm in a strange new world,
何よりも 自分を信じ立ち向かおう
nani yori mo jibun wo shinji tachimukaou
I'll stand up to it,
believing in myself more than anything else.
It's destiny
どんな場所にいても
donna basho ni itemo
No matter where I am,
つつむ空は一つだから
tsutsumu sora ha hitotsu dakara
I'm surrounded by the same sky.
ねぇ　もっと 翼広げて
nee motto tsubasa hirogete
so I'll be able to fly
羽ばたけるよね
habatakeruyone
with my wings spread out.
That's not the only forfeit Shindou has, Isumi-san.
I don't know why, but it seems like he
doesn't want to play Go anymore.
Sai...
There's a lot of dust on it...
He really hasn't played in a long time.
Shindou...
Shindou.
Let's play a game.
I'm not saying this because I'm worried about you.
Play... play a game for me.
That's what I came here for today.
I...sumi-san...
Shindou, do you remember the game between
us in the pro exam last year?
The Seventieth Match
Sai was here...
Shindou.
Shindou, please.
Just one match.
Sai, I... I...
I went to China,
and my desire to become a pro strengthened there.
Watching all those young players surrounding
themselves with Go everyday,
it made me want to follow their
path all that much more.
The pro exam is an objective, but not a goal.
The road goes on forever. Everyone's fighting
each other, while walking the same way.
Whether it be a top pro, or you guys.
Me, too?
Is that not true? Are you quitting?
It would be a shame for you to leave.
I...
I'm not playing! I'm not playing!
Sorry...
I....
Shindou...
Shindou.
It's your life, so you're free to
quit playing Go if you want to.
But will you play this one game with me?
For my sake?
For your sake, Isumi-san?
Yeah. I'll leave if you do that.
Okay.
Sai...
This is for Isumi-san...
It's not because I want to play...
You have to understand how Isumi-san feels. He
wants to walk straight down the path of Go.
Good luck.
Sai... I'm playing, reluctantly, for Isumi-san.
So you'll forgive me for this game, right?
Sai! Answer me!
Where are you!?
Whoever wins will enter the Honinbou league...
The one who loses has to play through
the tournament again next year.
Both of us want to win.
He has his first league entrance at stake, I have my
second league entrance in seven years at stake.
Come, Shindou!
I'm right here!
I can't...
I can't... I can't get excited!
But...
But...!
He got the upper-right, but I have strength.
Shindou won't give in, and he can read far ahead.
But I trained in China, I can read just as far!
Now!
I'm not going to let you push me around the whole game.
He's retaliating.
He's brought it into a Sabaki.
He's clustered me up, I can't have that.
I can cut him here, so it won't matter.
He moved down again. I can't respond to that right now.
I can't afford to be short on territory.
Isumi-san's shape is sparse, if I encroach
on his territory while attacking this...
If I connect here!
I'm ahead on territory!
Damn, it's going back and forth.
The game is even now.
It's not over yet!
Isumi-san...
Shindou...
He's gotten better.
If I reduce White's influence on the right side now...
Sai?
Shindou?
That move...
He...
He played... just like this...
He's here... I couldn't find Sai anywhere...
and he was here all along...
Shindou?
Sai was here...
Sai, who I couldn't find anywhere...
was hiding in the board I face,
in the way I play.
The only way I could find you... was by playing!
Sai!
I...
Can I play?
Shindou...
Isumi-san... I... I...
Maybe I'm allowed to play... Go...
It seems...
like you've been struggling with
something all this time.
I'm going to play.
Dozens of games, hundreds of games,
thousands of games from now on.
With Isumi-san, with Waya,
with Ochi, with everyone!
Yeah...
I want to walk down the same path.
Thank you, Isumi-san.
I can restart from here, too.
Touya!
U-Umm... the game...
Shindou-kun! What's wrong with you!
Huh? I...
You've been skipping all of your matches, what is...
It doesn't matter.
It doesn't matter? But Master Kuwabara, he's!
Hey, kid.
Your rival is on the fifth floor.
Yes!
Master Kuwabara, what...
You can tell from the look in his
eyes. He's back on his feet.
Sakamaki-san, did you know that Go is a two player game?
Of course I know that.
No, you don't.
Just you wait, Touya! There's something
I want to say to you!
Thank you both for the game.
Thank you.
Touya-kun. Can I interview you for a bit upstairs?
Of course.
Hagiwara-san doesn't make it back
into the league after seven years.
But to enter the league as a Junior High student.
What do you expect from Master Touya's son?
You.
What you just said was rude to Touya-kun.
'What do you expect from Touya Akira.'
Master Touya has nothing to do with it.
Touya-kun, congratulations on
entering the Honinbou league.
Thank you very much.
Thank you for the game.
Shindou!
Shindou-kun, what have you
been doing all this time!?
Is this the Kifu?
You won!?
Why are you here?
Touya... I...
You can't play Go by yourself.
I'm not giving up on Go.
I said, I know that.
You need two people.
A masterful game cannot happen
with just one genius.
I'll keep walking down this path!
That's what I came to tell you.
Right, Sakamaki-san?
You need two people with equal genius. Two.
When you have two, you can finally....
Come after me!
Yes.
take a step towards...
Take a step towards...!?
The divine move.
What a far-off dream.
It seems like he's finally determined,
to walk down this endless path.
But, I won't let you have your way
while I'm still around, brats.
Ring
My
Bell
noizu darake no mune de
ノイズだらけの胸で
I listen to my fate through the din in my heart.
noizu darake no mune deunmei wo kikiwakeru
ノイズだらけの胸で運命を聴きわける
It occurs to me.
hirameku
閃く
hiramekuyume ha watashi no naka demezame o matteta
閃く夢は私の中で目覚めを待ってた
My dream was waiting for the time
to wake up within me.
mezame o matteta
閃く夢は私の中で目覚めを待ってた
Music
Is
My
Thing
I can be more like myself
jibun rashiku nareru
自分らしくなれる
Music
In
My
Heart
ときめきならして
Let the pounding of my heart be heard
tokimeki narashite
ときめきならして
Music
Is
My
Thing
karada wo ugokasu
体を動かす
I move my body
karada wo ugokasu
体を動かす
Music
In
My
Heart
Feel the light
hikari wo kanjite
光を感じて
Music
Is
My
Thing
shiro to kuro de egaku
白と黒で描く
I draw with black and white
shiro to kuro de egaku
白と黒で描く
Music
In
My
Heart
owaranai haamoni
The unending Harmony
終わらないハーモニー
owaranai haamoni