Real Fansubbers presents
Hikaru no Go
Original Creator
Yumi Hotta
Takeshi Obata
Technical Director
Yukari Umezawa (Japanese Go Institute)
(Shueisha Weekly Shounen Jump Series)
mune no kodou atsuku yurugasu
胸の鼓動　熱くゆるがす
My heart walks, searching for something exciting
shigeki motomete aruku
刺激求めて　歩く
that will passionately sway the beating in my chest.
Planning
Keisuke Iwata
Takashi Harada
Yuuji Fugawa
My heart
jikan dakega sugiru mainichi jya
時間だけが過ぎる毎日じゃ
If I just wait for time to pass every day,
Animation Character Design
Kanami Sekiguchi
Miyuki Ueda
henka ha nai
変化はない
nothing's going to change.
Woo Wooo
tomaranai shinjitai susumitai
止まらない　信じたい　進みたい
I won't stop. I want to believe. I want to move forward.
jibun no chikara tamesu
自分の力試す
I will test my strength during my life.
My life
demo hayaaruki shitatte miotosudake
でも早歩きしたって見落とすだけ
But even if I walk faster,
I will definitely lose track of
sou kakujitsu ni
そう確実に
the important things.
Baby for you...
ashita ha ashita no kaze ga fuku
明日は明日の風が吹く
Tomorrow's wind will blow tomorrow,
Music Producer
Takashi Nagasawa
Music
Kei Wakakusa
soredemo
それでも　今この瞬間を強く生きたい
but I want to make the most out of this moment now.
Opening Song
Karaoke     llbx
LYRICS
Nana Katase
MUSIC
ARRANGE
Seikou Nagaoka
Nana Katase
ima kono shunkan wo tsuyoku ikitai
It's
It's fantasy.  even if I'm wandering,
fantasy
samayotta to shitemo
さまよったとしても
Program Manager
Tetsuya Watanabe
mitakotonai sekai demo
見たことない世界でも
even if I'm in a strange new world,
nani yori mo jibun wo shinji tachimukaou
何よりも　自分を信じ立ち向かおう
I'll stand up to it,
believing in myself more than anything else.
It's
It's destiny.  No matter where I am,
destiny
donna basho ni itemo
どんな場所にいても
tsutsumu sora ha hitotsu dakara
つつむ空は一つだから
I'm surrounded by the same sky,
Director
Tetsuya Endou
nee motto tsubasa hirogete
ねぇ　もっと　翼ひろげて
so I'll be able to fly
habatakeruyone
羽ばたけるよね
with my wings spread out.
I played against him in the Wakajishisen last year.
He scared me during the game with a few good moves,
but he was bad at Yose and I
won by six and a half moku.
But, Touya persistently asked me about how he played.
I was pissed off back then because he
kept asking about the guy who lost,
But I guess Touya really did think of him as a rival.
Okay.
I can win!
Only I can measure Shindou's strength now.
I knew the moment he appeared
in front of me that night.
I just need to wait..
They've already prepared a match between us.
The Seventy-Second Match
And so they began to run
It may look like he's foiling Shindou-kun's
attack on White in the center,
but Shindou-kun's planned for this to happen.
Murakami-san thought he was
foiling Shindou-kun's advance,
but instead he wasted many moves,
and let Shindou-kun gain territory.
I resign.
He's lost all will to fight...
Thank you for the game.
He is Touya-kun's rival.
Shindou-kun.
Have a minute?
So you will be coming to your
matches from now on?
I will! I will! I won't be absent anymore.
The pairings for the first preliminaries of the Meijin
title match should have been sent out...
Yes, I got it yesterday.
Your opponent for the first round
was Touya 3-dan, wasn't it?
Yes!
Touya-kun has a full match schedule, so
I don't know when your match will be,
but good luck. There are some people
who expect great things from you.
Yes. I'm sorry. Good bye.
Who's expecting great things from Shindou-kun?
Amano-san...
It's Master Kuwabara.
He speaks of him as if he's Touya Akira's equal.
It's incredible.
Oh.
'Oh'? You knew about it, Amano-san?
Yeah.
Shindou-kun looks like nothing more
than just another impolite kid to me,
just like any other kid these days.
Touya?
Of course I'd be happy if many more kids
like Touya-kun, with real skill, appeared.
The pro exam starts this week...
I wonder who will pass this year.
I hope whoever passes doesn't ditch
their matches like Shindou-kun.
Shindou-kun...
Amano-san, should we be hopeful
about the future of the Go world?
Japanese Go Institute
TODAY'S PROGRAMS
Public Match Room
Day of the Kyu-players
Training Course Dan-players
Onagai Classroom
Tutor Go with Sasaki Masashi 8-dan
Basics of Go Course
Katsuragi Classroom
Pro examination
6th Floor
3rd Floor
2nd Floor
Basics of Go Course    3rd Floor
Katsuragi Classroom   3rd Floor
Pro examination           6th Floor
Please start your clocks
Good luck.
Mr. Shinoda.
This year's pro exam's started.
Yes. The preliminaries are going on right
now, and the finals will be in a month.
Are Kadowaki-kun and Isumi-kun the favorites?
Have you seen Isumi-kun?
He looks much more confident. He's
nothing like he was last year.
That sounds hopeful. He had a fragileness
about him last year.
Amano-san, people speak as if you need
to bloom early in the Go world.
But I've always believed that everyone
has their own pace for growth.
Taking the long way isn't always bad in life.
Mr. Shinoda, do you mind...
if I use those words in an article
if Isumi-kun passes?
Ochi-kun and Waya-kun, who passed
last year... they're working hard.
Shindou-kun seems to have won
his first comeback game, too.
I'd like those who pass this
year to be just like them.
Black won't let me off that easily...
White will have a tough time here.
Oh no...
I didn't expect him to strike back then.
It's over if I let Black eliminate
all of my Aji with one Tsuke.
Now black has nothing to worry about, the
game's going to become one-sided...
By Resignation
Shindou
Tsujioka
Bye.
Oh, good-bye.
He won against not only Murakami-kun,
but Tsujioka-kun as well...
Is the new wave really coming?
Is Shindou-Kun's strength the real thing?
Second match of the Second preliminaries for the Ouza Match
Touya Akira 3-dan
Matsunaga Toshiyuki 6-dan
I resign.
First round of the second preliminaries for the Tengen match
Touya Akira 3-dan
Kamimaezu Hiroshi 7-dan
I resign
He's defeating high dan players...
one after another...
The new wave may really be coming.
With Touya Akira in the lead!
Fifth Game of the Gosei Match
I resign
Congratulations, Master Ogata.
Not only Jyudan, but a second title as well!
Thank you.
Mr. Nogi, looking back on the game
just now, how do you feel about it?
He stuck in and pushed me past the edge.
I lost.
How disappointing.
To think that you defended the Meijin title three
consecutive times ten years ago, Nogi-san.
But now you're getting defeated
by the likes of Ogata-kun.
Master Kuwabara...
I watched your game in another room.
Nogi-san, we veterans have to stick in there.
Master Kuwabara, you defended your Honinbou
title successfully against Kurata-kun didn't you?
I hear Ichiryuu-san and Hatanaka-kun will be
competing in the Meijin match next month.
I'm sure Ichiryuu-san will cut apart
that young Hatanaka boy.
We can't let these young ones take the world yet.
Excuse me Master Kuwabara, but Master
Ogata already has two titles.
I was satisfied with just Honinbou...
but I may have to seriously try to get the Gosei
and Jyudan titles if Ogata-kun holds them.
I've had pretty good luck against Ogata-kun...
Right, Ogata-kun?
I'll be waiting for you in the defender's chair.
Oh no... he's gaining confidence...
Master Ogata...
Japanese Go Institute
Good morning.
Impressive.
It's been less than two years since I played
you in the new first dan series.
Back then, I defeated you even with a reverse
komi handicap of five and a half moku.
I was that much better than you.
We're playing an even game today.
Show me how much you've improved.
I recorded that new first dan series game, too.
It's incredible.
Touya-kun was a new first dan just awhile ago,
and he's already in the Honinbou league.
Good luck.
Yes, publishing section.
Hello, Miyake-san.
What!?
Really!?
Okay... I understand.
Miyake? Miyake-san from Maichou
newspaper? What was it about?
Master T-Touya Kouyou has signed a contract
with the Bei'jing team of China!
Bei'jing team?
The Bei'jing team in China's team league?
Team league?
Translator's Note: J-league is a Japanese soccer thing. I don't
play soccer. I don't play baseball either. I won't comment any
more on J-league in fear of pulling another carps fiasco.
China has something similar
to Japan's J-league for Go.
I heard that there were teams who had contracts
with top Korean players, but...
I see!
What is it?
Now that Master Touya has retired, he's
free from Japan's match schedule!
China's contracts don't pay
very much for a Japanese,
but for Master Touya,
the benefit of getting to play against the best
players in the world must be enough.
Yoshikawa-kun!
Yes!
Call Master Touya now! Get his comments on it.
China Go Institute
Yang Hai!
Did you hear?
Master Touya from Japan just
joined the Bei'jing team!
I know. There's already a commotion
about it on the net.
This makes the Bei'jing team a lot stronger.
The team league is going to
get a lot more interesting.
Now the Shang'hai team, that Wang Xing
and I are in, is going to be in trouble.
You seem happy. Aren't you a Touya Kouyou fan?
Yeah! He's closest to mastering the divine move!
The divine move, huh?
The divine move will be born in this.
The computer?
Yeah.
Didn't they say it'll take a century before
computers can beat people at Go?
I won't need a century.
I found a sponsor for the project. I can start now.
We've already started inputting
the data somewhere else.
I see!
Your Bei'jing team is weak because
you're always doing crap like that!
Hey! This has nothing to do with it!
At least my own win rate is...
Worse than mine.
I can't get through. No one's picking
up at Master Touya's house.
I checked a few Chinese websites. It's for real.
I saw Akira-kun this morning, but he didn't say anything.
I wonder if he knows anything about this.
Since he joined the Bei'jing team...
this means that Master Touya will be going
to China regularly from now on, right?
I wonder how many games he has every
year... I should check up on it.
Weekly Go's going to have to follow
up on that from now on.
It's going to get busy.
Right, Amano-san?
Amano-san?
Yoshikawa-kun.
Yes?
Doesn't it feel like the Go world is...
moving?
The whole Go world.
Touya.
I want to play you.
As soon as possible.
Against you. As soon as possible.
Ring
Hikaru Shindou
Tomoko Kawakami
Akira Touya
Sanae Kobayashi
Honinbou Kuwabara
Rokurou Naya
Ogata 10-dan
Keiji Fujiwara
Insei Teacher Shinoda
Naoki Bandou
My
Bell
noizu darake no mune de
ノイズだらけの胸で
I listen to my fate through the din in my heart.
noizu darake no mune deunmei wo kikiwakeru
ノイズだらけの胸で運命を聴きわける
Zama
Akihiko Ishizumi
Amano
Yoshito Ishinami
Sakamaki
Shouto Kashii
Hai Yang
Kenichi Sakaguchi
Furukawa
Takao Ishii
Murakami 2-dan
Toshiaki Kuwahara
Tsujioka 2-dan
Mizuki Saitou
Noji
Masayuki Nakada
Pro
Youji Ueda
Record Keeper
Tomo Shigematsu
ノイズだらけの胸で運命を聴きわける
It occurs to me.
hirameku
閃く
hiramekuyume ha watashi no naka demezame o matteta
閃く夢は私の中で目覚めを待ってた
My dream was waiting for the time
to wake up within me.
mezame o matteta
閃く夢は私の中で目覚めを待ってた
Music
Is
My
Thing
I can be more like myself
jibun rashiku nareru
自分らしくなれる
Music
In
My
Heart
ときめきならして
Let the pounding of my heart be heard
tokimeki narashite
ときめきならして
Music
Is
My
Thing
karada wo ugokasu
体を動かす
I move my body
karada wo ugokasu
体を動かす
Music
In
My
Heart
Feel the light
hikari wo kanjite
光を感じて
Ending Song
Karaoke: llbx
LYRICS
TUNE
JAPANESE LYRICS
YUUKO EBINE
EDITING
TATSUHIKO
SONG
Music
Is
My
Thing
shiro to kuro de egaku
白と黒で描く
I draw with black and white
shiro to kuro de egaku
白と黒で描く
Music
In
My
Heart
owaranai haamoni
The unending Harmony
終わらないハーモニー
owaranai haamoni
February 26th 2003, Japanese Go Institute
Hello, this is Yuuki. I'm at
the Japanese Go Institute.
Y
U
K
I
I came to watch because I hear that
Teacher Yukari has a match today.
We're looking at a pro match today.
Mai isn't here because she's studying for exams
Meijin Match   First preliminaries
Umezawa Yukari
vs
Chinen Kaori
Teacher Yukari appears!!
Her opponent is Women's Kisei Chinen Kaori!!
Help from :  Asahi Newspaper Co.
Meijin Match
First and Second preliminaries
Kurotaki Masaki 5-dan
Matsumoto Takehisa 5-dan
Nagahara Yoshiaki 6-dan
Yoshida Youichi 5-dan
It made me want to become a pro.
Pro player!!
Head for it!!
To be continued...
Pro player!!
Head for it!!
To be continued...
Touya...
Let's play. We can't start until we do.
The Sai that you wanted to play is no longer here, but...
Sai is in my Go.
Good luck.