胸の鼓動　熱くゆるがす
mune no kodou atsuku yurugasu
My heart walks, searching for something exciting
刺激求めて歩く My Heart
shigeki motomete aruku MY HEART
That will passionately sway the beating in my chest.
時間だけが過ぎる毎日じゃ
jikan dake ga sugiru mainichi jya
If I just wait for the time to pass everyday.
変化はない
henka ha nai
nothing's going to change.
Woo Wooo
止まらない　信じたい　進みたい
tomaranai shinjitai susumitai
I won't stop. I want to believe. I want to move forward.
自分の力試す My Life
jibun no chikara tamesu MY LIFE
I will test my strength during my life.
でも早歩きしたって見落とすだけ
demo hayaaruki shitatte miotosudake
But even if I walk faster.
I will definitely lose track of
そう確実に
sou kakujitsu ni
the important things.
Baby for you...
明日は明日の風が吹く
ashita ha ashita no kaze ga fuku
Tomorrow's wind will blow tomorrow.
それでも　今この瞬間を強く生きたい
soredemo
but I want to make the most out of this moment now.
ima kono shunkan wo tsuyoku ikitai
It's fantasy
さまよったとしても
samayotta to shitemo
Even if I'm wandering,
見たことない世界でも
mitakotonai sekai demo
even if I'm in a strange new world,
何よりも 自分を信じ立ち向かおう
nani yori mo jibun wo shinji tachimukaou
I'll stand up to it,
believing in myself more than anything else.
It's destiny
どんな場所にいても
donna basho ni itemo
No matter where I am,
つつむ空は一つだから
tsutsumu sora ha hitotsu dakara
I'm surrounded by the same sky.
ねぇ　もっと 翼広げて
nee motto tsubasa hirogete
so I'll be able to fly
羽ばたけるよね
habatakeruyone
with my wings spread out.
I'm starting at the preliminaries for
the pro exam again next year.
Iijima-kun quit the Insei program already,
maybe I'm at my limit, too
Oh yeah, have you heard, Waya?
A few players from the Kyuuseikai have gone
to China to study and to further relations.
And?
It seems Isumi-kun went with them.
Isumi-san did!?
The Sixty-Fifth Match
Isumi no Go
It only takes four hours to go from Tokyo to Bei'jing!
Are we taking a taxi the rest of the way?
How long does it take to get
to the Go Institute of China?
Half an hour I think.
What? Sakurano and Isumi, is this the
first time in China for both of you?
But Isumi, when you quit the Kyuuseikai last year...
I thought you were giving up on becoming a pro.
Why would he give it up!?
Shin-chan would play evenly with your average pro.
I never said he wasn't good enough.
I thought you had gotten depressed
and given it up.
I wanted to be alone for a bit
to organize my emotions.
I'm sorry for making you worry.
The fact that Master Narusara invited
you to this Shizen match,
shows that he thinks highly of your abilities.
Yes.
I have to pass this year, in order to
thank the teacher for his kindness.
You really do! You're already nineteen, you know.
I didn't become a pro until I was over twenty.
Sakurano is Sakurano, Isumi is Isumi.
What do you mean?
How many games are we playing?
Three games or so over three days and two nights.
I've done everything I can so far.
The pro exam preliminaries will start in two months.
I'll pretend that the Shinzen match is the pro exam.
I resign.
This move you made was rather peculiar.
You lost all the stones you played.
I couldn't turn the game around after all...
He's good...
It wasn't a bad game. Don't feel bad about it.
Come on, let's cheer up with a nice lunch.
It wasn't bad?
I am dissatisfied with that game I just played.
I'm not depressed at all.
I'm just angry at myself for playing too
aggressively, because I thought I couldn't lose...
For not being able to play my best...
Do you think you could have won if you had?
Well, good luck on your afternoon match.
Shin-chan, hurry up!
I once pretended to
play a Go stone in this park...
Sai found a rock that looked like a Go stone...
Yup something just like this.
And he told me to try playing this stone...
The rock flew out of my hand
when I tried to play it.
Sai...
Shindou!
Waya!
What are you doing?
Huh?
What are you doing here, Waya?
I was on my way to your house.
Master Morishita is furious.
You don't come to the study sessions, and
you've been ditching the matches.
You haven't said anything to
the Go Institute have you!?
Are you in a slump? Or are you
just tired of it all already?
Say something!
How can I know what you're thinking
if you don't say anything!?
How can I tell him that I don't care about Go anymore...
I want to see Sai again...
Say...
I started living on my own
All our Insei friends come to visit me.
You should come, too
That's all right.
Shindou...
You're the only one that's standing still.
I played three Ooteai matches,
and I'm two and one...
But Ochi has already played four games
and has four straight wins!
Honda-san, Komiya, and everyone else are working
hard for this year's pro exams, too.
From what I hear, Isumi-san went
to play Go against Chinese pros.
Isumi-san is in China?
Yeah.
Shindou...
We just barely passed last year, even though
Isumi-san was taking the test.
Isumi-san will definitely pass this year!
Are you going to tell Isumi-san that you've been
ditching all the matches when he becomes a pro!?
Don't you feel ashamed!?
You want to play Go, right!?
You want to play!
I'm going first, you ready?
16-4,
Star!
You just though about where to play.
Tell me about the response that you came up with!
Shindou!
You idiot!
Three days and two nights passes by like a flash.
All that's left is to say goodbye to
Liu Xian Sheng and go home.
Do you have time? Let's go see Tien an men.
I'd rather go shopping.
No way I'm going to come all the way to China
just to look around stores, right Isumi?
What's wrong, Shin-chan?
I'm sorry for brining this up at the last minute...
But I'm going to stay another day
I want to play him one more time.
Isumi...
No way! I'm going shopping!
So I'll stay behind by myself.
Him... You mean Zhao-kun?
Zhao-kun...
I managed to beat him, but
it was a very close game.
To be able to play that well at his age...
He really showed me how strong
the Go Institute of China is.
I'm not surprised.
Isumi, haven't you heard?
All the pros here were chosen out of the pros.
'Zhong Guo Go Institute'
China has pro players in every Sheng...
in Japanese that means "prefecture".
Anyone that is thought to have potential out of all of them,
is gathered here in Bei'jing to get daily training.
They live here, too.
What!? They live here!?
Yeah.
Well, people who make a lot,
or people who get married,
seem to rent apartments nearby.
There are only thirty or so young pros
who are in their teens and twenties.
So he is one of the chosen pros.
He's living here, far away from
his parents, at that age...
He's an exceptional child.
What about school?
I don't think he goes to one.
They have enough time for
a normal education, but...
Well, they're already pros.
Is something wrong?
Oh, Li Xian Sheng. Hello.
Well, he said that he'd like
to play Zhao-kun again...
Play Zhao again?
He can't accept the fact that
he lost to Zhao yesterday.
Please.
Isumi-kun played well...
But Zhao neutralized his attack very effectively.
I understand how Isumi-kun feels.
I don't care how good he is.
I don't want to go back to Japan while I'm
still angry at myself for losing a game
that I did not do my best on.
I can't, if I want to be confident
during the pro exams this year.
I see.
But Zhao is going to be gone starting today.
There is a match in a rural
area, so he headed there.
He should be back in a few days.
Isumi-kun, why don't you study here
for a few days until he comes back?
Liu-san!
Here?
The playing room here is a place
for pros to train themselves.
Everyone gathers there everyday.
You can play however much you want.
You're angry at yourself for losing
to Zhao. I understand that.
But there's no need to be in such a hurry.
How about it, Li Xian Sheng?
Anyone willing to work hard is welcome.
Get a room in a nearby hotel, and come study here.
Shin-chan...
So, Isumi. What are you going to do?
I didn't expect this, but...
It might be a good opportunity!
Okay! Thank you for letting me stay here.
'Zhong Guo Go Institute'
How much do you know about this place?
It's a place where all the best pros gather.
But it is a very strict place.
You're sent back to the rural provinces
if you don't do well in your matches.
There are people who don't improve as much as
expected, even if they have a lot of potential.
Li Xian Sheng manages both the studying of
Go and the lifestyles of the players here.
This is the playing room.
You research new moves here, replay
old games, play practice games...
It's a place of learning for the chosen pros.
They're all young.
A study session for Chinese pros...
Don't feel out of place! I studied
with pros at Kyuuseikai, too.
They study here starting from
8:15 in the morning...
Le Ping!
Were you playing hooky again!?
Why do you always do that when I'm not around!
I wasn't playing hooky. I just
went to the bathroom.
Don't lie to me!
Waya!
S-Sorry.
Waya?
It's the name of a friend of mine in Japan.
He looks just like him...
Li Xian Sheng? What's "Waya"?
Is he talking about me?
Let me introduce him.
This is Isumi-kun from Japan. He's
going to be studying here for a bit.
Isumi-kun?
A Japanese pro?
Nope. He is someone who is just starting out.
N-Nice to meet.... you all...
Isumi-kun! Isumi-kun!
Does Waya have an outtie just like me!?
Le Ping!
Oh! It's already lunchtime!
Wait!
Le Ping!
What a problem child...
Le Ping isn't very motivated to study Go.
Li Xian Sheng must be annoyed with him.
He's always yelling at him.
He looked very young.
He's a pro too, right?
Of course!
He came here last year at the age of eleven.
It's time for lunch.
Why don't we eat, too?
Okay.
Eat here on the first floor while you are here.
Everyone eats here.
You should go and get a hotel room
as soon as you finish eating.
You have two hours for lunch. That's plenty of time.
Okay.
Good luck.
It may not be a long time, but if you work
hard, you will learn something valuable.
Okay...
Le Ping...
Oh no, I can't be relaxing just because
I met a small version of Waya.
You're going to play a game with one and
a half hours each in the afternoon.
We're playing in leagues right now
to test out everyone's strength.
I'll write your name in, too.
They are the members of the lower
dan group, first dan through 3-dan.
You should play anyone who's free.
Li Xian Sheng,
I'll play Isumi-kun.
Le Ping?
How about it, Isumi-kun?
Le Ping...
I can't be losing to a child like him
Please.
I underestimated him!
I belittled him too much in my mind.
Le Ping is one of the chosen pros, too!
Isumi-kun, you were too forceful.
This move was a mistake.
It looked like Black avoided White's attack well,
But it lost out during the fight.
Did you really think that this would work?
You underestimated me
I can't lose, not to the likes of you, Isumi-kun.
Good luck studying!
Le Ping!
He laughed...! At me!
How was he?
He sucks.
Really?
This is a situation where you should move
to the sides instead of towards the center.
Yeah. Black has strength on the
top side and the right side.
Everything they say is brilliant and well thought out...
I can't join the conversation.
Everyone's been working here for months... no, years!
In a place where everyone around them is the
elite of the pros... from dawn until dusk...
I thought it would be a good opportunity
for me to learn here...
But... if this place just serves to make
me lose confidence in myself...
No. It's still all right when I'm angry at myself.
If my self-anger were to turn into self-pity...
The best of the pros in their teens and twenties...
The elite of the pros who are stronger
than players who are older than them.
What can I accomplish here?
Isumi-kun.
Y-Yes?
Want to play a game of speed Go?
With ten seconds per move?
Okay...
I played ten second Go a lot in my free time at
both Kyuuseikai and the Insei study sessions.
It depends on the instinct and ideas,
rather than reading ahead.
Good luck.
He's around my age...
But he's as strong as...
a 9-dan pro from Japan!
I resign...
Huh? You resign?
It's too early.
White can pull back if Black plays a hane,
but that would kill his cluster.
So White can only cut and play elsewhere.
Black loses the initiative, but he has no
weaknesses, so he has the advantage.
I thought he'd simply pull back,
but he has to play elsewhere...
I resigned too early...
Let's clean up.
I'll do it.
Okay, let's play again sometime.
I hear you came from Japan?
I was in my room all day today,
so I just heard about you.
Nice to meet you. I'm Yang Hai.
I'm Isumi.
What's wrong?
You seem tired.
Where are you staying?
A nearby hotel?
Yes.
I'm in a double, so there's an empty bed.
Wanna stay there? Room 303.
I thought foreigners were not allowed to stay here.
Who cares? Who would know?
Li Xian Sheng always leaves by five.
I'm not going to make you pay rent.
It's all right.
Why not?
I want to spend sometime alone at the hotel...
Besides, I'm not staying long...
Oh? That's too bad.
I was hoping you could tell me about
the entertainment industry in Japan.
But I guess someone who's here to study
Go wouldn't know anything about that.
Wanna play?
No... I'm done for today...
Oh? Okay.
I guess you're tired.
In the pro exam last year,
I was able to recover after losing three games in a row...
to Shindou, Waya, and Fuku only because
of my determination to beat Ochi.
My Go supports me.
I'll believe in my own capabilities.
I was able to tell myself that...
back then...
But... will I be able to tell myself
the same thing here in China?
Will my Go support me here?
Ring
My
Bell
noizu darake no mune de
ノイズだらけの胸で
I listen to my fate through the din in my heart.
noizu darake no mune deunmei wo kikiwakeru
ノイズだらけの胸で運命を聴きわける
It occurs to me.
hirameku
閃く
hiramekuyume ha watashi no naka demezame o matteta
閃く夢は私の中で目覚めを待ってた
My dream was waiting for the time
to wake up within me.
mezame o matteta
閃く夢は私の中で目覚めを待ってた
Music
Is
My
Thing
I can be more like myself
jibun rashiku nareru
自分らしくなれる
Music
In
My
Heart
ときめきならして
Let the pounding of my heart be heard
tokimeki narashite
ときめきならして
Music
Is
My
Thing
karada wo ugokasu
体を動かす
I move my body
karada wo ugokasu
体を動かす
Music
In
My
Heart
Feel the light
hikari wo kanjite
光を感じて
Music
Is
My
Thing
shiro to kuro de egaku
白と黒で描く
I draw with black and white
shiro to kuro de egaku
白と黒で描く
Music
In
My
Heart
owaranai haamoni
The unending Harmony
終わらないハーモニー
owaranai haamoni
A pair Go tournament between
the top pros in Japan was held.
I participated in it as a pair
with Ishisa Yoshio 9-dan.
25 seconds.
This wasn't very good.
I'm a little disappointed that
I lost, but I learned a lot.
The final round is on January 26th.
Isn't he the strongest grade-school
player right now?
Yeah, Touya Akira.
He's Touya Meijin's son, and he doesn't
play in Amateur tournaments.
I heard that Touya Akira is good, is that true?
Why don't you play a game with Akira-kun then?
Yeah. That's what I'm here for.