Fujiwarano Sai, a Go player from the Heian period
has passed through time and returned to
the world in the mind of Shindou Hikaru...
in order to obtain the Hand of God.
Kimi ga ima boku wo sasaete!
君が今僕を支えて
Now you are,
holding me up strong!
Boku ga ima kimi wo sasaeru!
僕が今君を支える
Now I am,
holding you as well!
Dakara Mayoi nagara mo tomo ni ikite ikou yo
だから迷いながらも共に生きていこうよ
So let us now while wandering,
live together
mirai e to...
未来へと
towards the future
Elite-Fansubs presents
Hikaru no Go
Nakama to tawamaure sorenaride itemo
仲間と戯れそれなりで居ても
Even when I'm capricing with my friends,
mono tari na sa wo kanjite shimau
もの足りなさを感じてしまう
I feel an emptiness in my heart.
Sameta me de mirarete
冷めた目で見られて
Looked at with cold eyes,
Kawaita jidai no kaze ni fukareteiru
乾いた時代の風に吹かれている
I'm blown by the winds of a dry age
Fuan na, kokoro to yuuki ga
不安な心と勇気が
Feelings of doubt and courage
senaka awase ni natteiru
背中合わせになっている
are back to back
dakedo ima nara yume wo, kono
te de kanaete miseru yo
だけど今なら夢をこの手で叶えてみせるよ
but I'll make these dreams come true now with my own hands.
Kizutsuite koware sou na hi mo
傷ついて壊れそうな日も
The days where I'm hurt and about to break,
namida shite komaraseru hi mo
涙して困らせる日も
the days where I cry and trouble you
aru keredo, bokura wa sore wo
あるけれど僕達はそれを
They all exist, but we will
koete ikunda dare yori...
超えていくんだ誰より
get over it heading higher
ue wo mezashite!
上を目指して
than anyone else!
Why don't we tie his arms and legs
behind his back and make him play?
That's a good idea...
The Ninth Match
An Irritating Presence
Hmm?
Where's Itou and Kojima?
They came today right?
They're not here?
They took Okumura-kun, a freshman, and
the three of them sneaked off earlier.
Sneaked off?
Yes...
[note: Wakajishisen is a fictional tournament that appears in Hikaru no Go.
It is based on a real tournament where new pros play Insei in a
tournament style match.]
[note: Insei are children who go to the Japanese Go Center to learn Go. They all
aim to become pros some day, and they're all frighteningly good at the game]
[note: Shuusaku is the person that Sai inhabited 100 years ago. He actually
did exist, and is considered one of the greatest players of all time]
A
Hundred
Different
Tsumego
The Key
to
Solving
Tsumego
Collection
of
Shuusaku's
Matches
Famous
Pro
Matches
Waka-
jishisen
Ouza
Matches
As you can see, it's a mess.
When we didn't have very many
members, this was the club room.
But now... it's just storage for the club.
At the next tournament, we're going to use this
place as a preparation room for the women...
So Mr. Yun told us to clean it up.
Anyways, chores like this are work for the freshmen,
and you looked bored Touya, so if you don't mind...
I understand.
Oh wow, it's Kifu...
and an old Go magazine.
Wow!
[note: The Japanese Calendar doesn't work on the same system as the
Western calendar. They have periods that begin and end with the government.
Currently they are in the Heisei period which started about 15 years ago. The
Shouwa period was before the Heisei period, and lasted more than 60 years.]
There are things here from the
beginning of the Shouwa Period.
Learning
Joseki
Wow, this book is old too!
Old Joseki...
I've felt it since I first met Shindou Hikaru.
For example, black's next move....
These days we would hane the white stone.
It's considered to be the best move.
But, you used... a nobi.
That's an old joseki.
Sometimes, things like that happen.
It may look like a weakness to attack...
but you crushed me with your
strength before I got a chance.
Just improving slightly won't surpass him.
Surpassing him...
Master
of
Tesuji
will require a strength great
enough to... create new Joseki...
Could you play a game against me while you're at it?
Oh wait...
You just keep cleaning up like I told you to.
Don't you dare look at the board
in the middle of the game.
Not... look at the board?
You're telling me to play blind folded?
No, not at all.
It's just that if you're a member of the Kaiou Go club...
You have to do the chores, and you
also have to obey your sempai.
Go is different from Shougi.
A Go board is a lot larger.
Are you aware that blind Go is difficult even for pros?
You can do it right?
You are the future meijin after all.
Why did a guy like you have to join the Go club?
No one in any tournament will be able to beat you.
Why don't you just go pro and take 4 or 5 titles?
Or what?
Did you want to show off your strength to others
and make sure everyone knows that you're the best?
The best?
What? Are you saying you're not?
If I'm the best...
You're saying I should be able to play blind Go easily?
Please make your first move.
16-4... Star
4-16 Star
4-16 Star...
16-17 Komoku
4-4 Hoshi
4-4 Hoshi...
If I beat you at this, it would be great.
After all, it is an even match.
Beating the great Touya Akira at an even match...
Hmm!
It won't be interesting if you kill yourself off
too quickly, so try to hold back on mistakes.
I don't care if you show off,
but do it after you beat me.
You sure do talk a lot!
You just said that it's hard even for pros.
This will be an interesting match.
6-4 kakari!
3-6 !
6-6 !
4-14
Touya should be struggling by now.
Blind Go has to be tough, even for Touya.
So this is what he meant by tying
his arms and legs behind his back.
I understand.
Well, I'm next.
Isn't it still a little early?
I wanna see Touya's desperate face.
Hey Touya!
Will you play a game...
Itou...
T-This is...
a resignation from too great a gap?
But you've only gone through half a game!
I didn't think there was another person.
If you wish to play me, go ahead.
Oh...
he was beat easily since it was a match without any handicap...
with so little moves, blind Go is not impossible.
Like this, I would also get defeated.
Hey Itou!
Okumura!
Come here Okumura!
Huh?
You're gonna play him too!
But... he can't play against 2 people at the same time!
It won't even be a close game.
It didn't work out as we
planned with only one person.
Really?!
Two... opponents?
What?
You're going to quit now?
Then why don't you quit the Kaiou Go club too?!
If you can't play us, then why
don't you leave the Go club?
You're irritating.
Make your first move.
But...
I won't give up so easily.
What's the matter?
The future Meijin wishes to play you.
Then...
16-4 Star!
4-16 Star
4-16... Star
17-4... Komoku
4-3 komoku
16-17 komoku
4-4 Star
16-17 Komoku
4-16
6-17... kakari
16-15
15-3
13-17
17-17
17-15
17-14
17-18
17-16
3-3
5-3
5-17
4...-17
6-6
7-5
Damn...
Kojima's not as strong as I am...
and the freshman's even worse!
5-8
If it continues like this, they'll lose
with even fewer moves than me.
Hurry up and move!
4...
4-18...
Osae
[note: Kaketsugi, Hiraki, Ate, Osae are all names for moves that have a
specific purpose. Hiraki is there to capture more territory, Ate is a move
that places one of your stones next to an opponent stone, Osae is a
move made to limit the mobility of your opponent's stones, Kaketsugi is
a move to move your stones out of your opponent's containment.]
Man...
2-5 Kaketsugi
10-4 Hiraki
6-18 Ate
What a stupid...!
Hmm...?
Hey! Why are you so slow whenever
you're moving against me!
Touya is struggling?
It can't be, they haven't made very many moves yet...
and it's stupid Okumura, not Kojima...
Oh!
Touya's going to lose without holding out even 5 minutes...
Against Okumura.
Touya! Hurry up and move!
Touya! Hurry up and move! It's your turn.
Oh... Okumura's stupid moves are
throwing Touya's rhythm off...
memorizing each move can only happen when those moves have meaning.
But... Okumura's moves are so meaningless
that Touya's having trouble understanding
why he's making those moves...
and that's throwing his memory off!
10...
17...
10-17...
Touya, one of my stones is there.
Dammit!
4-9 Hiraki!
4-9 huh?
He's finally starting to collapse!
Wait, can't let my guard down, I'm playing Touya.
You can just keep acting stupid.
3-14 kakari
4-11
10-4... Hiraki
17-...
...6
Keep moving Touya!
Upon this battlefield which you can't see,
you shall wander around blindly and die!
Touya are you here?
Hitaka... sempai!
Itou... kojima too?
Oh hey, Touya...
you said you'd play a tutoring game with me earlier...
Huh?
You're a freshman, right?
What are you guys doing?
Umm... ahh... this is...
Eh, Umm... Mr. Yun...
Said to clean up this room, so we asked Touya...
We wanted Touya to play a
tutoring match with us too...
but Touya had to work so...
So?!
So...
Umm... we played a little...
Blind Go.
Moron!
Touya had to work?
Then why didn't you help him?!
Itou... you're behind this aren't you?!
Umm... well...
You too Touya, what do you think you're doing?!
I'll clean this up, so you go ahead and clean them up.
Hitaka sempai...
I took this match...
I'll continue it like this.
Shut up!
They're bullying you, I won't let this continue.
But this is something I...
If you weren't here...
Then they wouldn't be doing something like this!
And you even accepted their challenge!
You're the one that made the bullying worse!
If only you weren't here!
But...
what I'm trying to say is...
you're a student of Kaiou, so
be in the Go club with pride...
So... don't accept challenges like
this, play them fairly and crush them.
Yes!
Thank you very much!
Hitaka-sempai...
It should end in about 5 minutes, so
please, allow me to play you afterwards.
I'm sorry for all the trouble.
Let's...
finish this!
Tsutsui-san!
I found a member!
Someone who can play Go!
Really?
Now we can go to the tournament!
You... can play Go?
Yeah I can.
You don't have to know, the Go club here is...
Are you stupid?!
Of course it's better that they know how!
Either way, Shindou-kun..
team matches are segregated by
gender, so she can't be on our team.
I know!
Let's have her dress up as a guy!
She'll fit the role perfect...!
I don't mind entering if it's just for the tournament.
I'm busy with the volleyball club.
Hikaru, you said something unnecessary again.
So a team match in Go work on a 3 player team?
Damn, a guy!
We have to find a guy!
I guess we want a guy who can play...
and someone as strong as possible...
Isn't there anyone like that Sai?
The only strong person I know is that person...
We can't have Touya's Dad dress
up as a Junior High student!
Hey, let's put a new poster!
One that attracts more attention.
We can put a difficult tsumego (Go problem)
on it and have anyone who can solve it come!
That again?
I don't really care if they're strong anymore!
Doesn't Kaiou Junior High have dozens of members?
Yup, the grass is definitely greener on their side.
Man I'm jealous...
Come on, it's your turn Shindou-kun,
Kaiou is Kaiou and we're us.
hmm...
Touya...
Itou of the second year just quit the club.
Why did you enter the Go club, Touya?
Because of you, all of our members are nervous.
I, the president, am as well.
To be honest...
I want to play you, and learn from you...
But...
everyone around me is talking...
they don't want to see the president
lose to Touya in an instant.
Although...
I want to challenge you like Aoki did, I can't.
Touya...
I heard the rumor that you entered the Kaiou Go
club to fight Shindou Hikaru of Haze Junior High.
But why a tournament?
Why did you have to enter the Go club?
Your existence in the club causes a hundred
problems for us, without a single benefit.
He refused my challenge.
I don't know why, but if he refuses...
then I have to enter the tournament no matter what.
You said earlier that "I cause a hundred problems
without a single benefit for the Kaiou Go Club."
But Shindou Hikaru will come to the next tournament!
It's not ego or selfishness!
I'm the only one who can play him evenly!
Dokoni aru no kana?
どこにあるのかな
Where is it?
bokudakeno takaramono
ボクだけの宝物
The treasure that belongs to me
ima ookina bouken e...
今大きな冒険へ
Now towards a great adventure...
yawarakana hizashi
やわらかな日差し
the gentle sunlight
tabitachi no yokan
旅立ちの予感
a feeling of departure
sora mo hana mo hora waratte iru!
空も花もホラ笑っている
The sky and the flower are both laughing!
kono saki ni wa nani ga matsu no darou?
この先には何が待つのだろう
I wonder what waits ahead for me.
shinkokyuu...
深呼吸
take a deep breath...
yume no tobira ni soutto te wo kakete... ikou!
夢の扉にそっと手をかけて行こう
place your hand gently on the door to your dreams... and let's go!
kaze ni fukare nagara!
風に吹かれながら
While blown by the wind!
kokoro yurashi nagara!
心揺らしながら
While rocking your heart!
masshiro na chizu wo katate ni mochinagara
真っ白な地図を片手に持ちながら
holding a blank map in one hand
kaze ni fukare nagara!
風に吹かれながら
While blown by the wind!
asu wo kaki nagara!
明日を描きながら
While drawing in tomorrow!
tooku made, doko made?
遠くまで何処まで
far away
tadori tsukeru made
たどり着けるまで
until I reach that place
zettai makenaiyo zettai nakanaiyo
絶対負けないよ絶対泣かないよ
I won't lose! I won't cry!
kono yume wo kanaeru sono hi made wa!
この夢を叶えるその日までは
Until the day that I make this dream come true!
ano sora wa waratteita!
あの空は笑っていた
That sky was laughing!
ano hana mo waratteita!
あの花はも笑っていた
That flower was laughing too!
boku mo itsuka warau kara!
ボクもいつか笑うから
Some day I will laugh with you!
donna kabe mo koeru kara!
どんな壁も越えるから
I will surpass any obstacle!
mou nani mo nani mo kowakunai!
もう何も何もコワクナイ
I'm not afraid of anything any more!
Umezawa Yukari's
Go Go Igo!
Go! Go! Igo!
West Tokyo Private, Hoya Junior High School
Today we have come to Hoya Junior
High School of West Tokyo for fun.
Teacher Yukari
Mai
Teacher Umezawa Yukari
Please give her a big welcome!
Both I and teacher Yukari were overwhelmed by the
welcome we received from everyone in the Go club.
Everyone in the Go club
Formed in April 2001, 33 Members. *4th place in the Eastern Beginners Tournament Goal: To Enter the City tournament, and to enter the Eastern Champion Matches.
But once the matches begin, everyone was serious.
Mai challenges a female student!
I played a game while I was
there, but I didn't stand a chance.
but lost miserably~~
I still need a lot of practice.
Teacher Yukari played 5 people simultaneously!!
Teacher Yukari played 5 people simultaneously.
Teacher Yukari is incredible!
Teacher Yukari, Thank you very much.
Club President
Thank you very much!
Go club huh? Not too exciting...
Hey, umm, there's a tournament soon.
A Go tournament, for Junior High Schools.
This child has quite a bit of potential.
He makes honest and good moves.
Hikaru! That child is cheating in the Seichi!
[Translators note: Seichi to be explained in next episode]