Real Fansubbers presents
Hikaru no Go
胸の鼓動　熱くゆるがす
mune no kodou atsuku yurugasu
My heart walks, searching for something exciting
刺激求めて歩く My Heart
shigeki motomete aruku MY HEART
That will passionately sway the beating in my chest.
時間だけが過ぎる毎日じゃ
jikan dake ga sugiru mainichi jya
If I just wait for the time to pass everyday.
変化はない
henka ha nai
nothing's going to change.
Woo Wooo
止まらない　信じたい　進みたい
tomaranai shinjitai susumitai
I won't stop. I want to believe. I want to move forward.
自分の力試す My Life
jibun no chikara tamesu MY LIFE
I will test my strength during my life.
でも早歩きしたって見落とすだけ
demo hayaaruki shitatte miotosudake
But even if I walk faster.
I will definitely lose track of
そう確実に
sou kakujitsu ni
the important things.
Baby for you...
明日は明日の風が吹く
ashita ha ashita no kaze ga fuku
Tomorrow's wind will blow tomorrow.
それでも　今この瞬間を強く生きたい
soredemo
but I want to make the most out of this moment now.
ima kono shunkan wo tsuyoku ikitai
It's fantasy
さまよったとしても
samayotta to shitemo
Even if I'm wandering,
見たことない世界でも
mitakotonai sekai demo
even if I'm in a strange new world,
何よりも 自分を信じ立ち向かおう
nani yori mo jibun wo shinji tachimukaou
I'll stand up to it,
believing in myself more than anything else.
It's destiny
どんな場所にいても
donna basho ni itemo
No matter where I am,
つつむ空は一つだから
tsutsumu sora ha hitotsu dakara
I'm surrounded by the same sky.
ねぇ　もっと 翼広げて
nee motto tsubasa hirogete
so I'll be able to fly
羽ばたけるよね
habatakeruyone
with my wings spread out.
Shindou?
Nase!
I heard you haven't been going to your
matches? Waya was worried that...
Shindou!
Shindou...
The Sixty-Eighth Match
Forfeits
He's going to quit being a pro!?
Yes.
Shindou-kun?
I can't believe that he would quit...
I heard from his teacher that he became
a pro by passing a very difficult test...
Did Shindou-kun say he was going to quit?
Not at all, but he hasn't gone to any of his matches.
He hasn't gone?
No.
He went to two of them in April.
But even though we've received
match schedules in the mail...
he hasn't gone to one since then.
He took a break immediately
after Golden Week didn't he?
I heard he had to go to Hiroshima
for something Go related.
That wasn't a match then?
No.
He hasn't had an absence since then.
Does that mean that he has been absent
from his matches to come to school?
I'm sorry, I don't know very
much about the Go world,
so it didn't bother me that Shindou-kun
came to school every day.
Has he said anything?
Nothing.
He wouldn't tell me anything even when I asked.
He suddenly changed.
He used to be so cheery that it was annoying.
I'm sure he has his reasons!
He did become a pro, he's made
himself a path in the world.
So both my husband and I have decided
to just watch over him for a while...
but I just can't help but be worried.
I understand.
I'll look into it, too.
Hikaru!
What is it, Akari?
Can you explain this to me?
Weekly Go? Where did you get it?
From Koike-kun. But more importantly,
explain this to me.
They list the records for all the pros in the scores
section, but yours is filled with forfeits.
I told you, I'm not playing anymore.
Huh? Weren't you talking about me?
I thought you weren't going to play
with me anymore because I suck.
So what do you mean you're
not going to play anymore?
Are you going to quit being a pro?
If Sai doesn't come back...
Maybe. I might quit.
What a jerk.
Mitani-kun.
I don't know what happened,
but you quit the Go club to become a pro.
But Hikaru... What are you going to do?
I probably need to study for
high school entrance exams.
Akari, stay after school and study with me.
Fujisaki doesn't have time! We
have a tournament coming up!
Tournament, huh?
What do you mean by 'Tournament, huh?'!
Don't you dare look down on us!
You were much more passionate when
you were striving to beat Kaiou!
Mitani...
I'm going to be in this next tournament.
Natsume, Koike, and I, the three of us,
we're going to challenge Kaiou again!
What? Mitani-kun, you're going to be in it?
You're going to go!?
Shindou, are you jealous?
We're never going to let you
back in again, you idiot!
Fujisaki! Leave him alone. Let's go!
Mitani-kun...
I was absorbed in Go...
I'm going to work hard here in the Go club
with Tsutsui-san. Right, Tsutsui-san?
Tsutsui-san! I brought Mitani!
It's a team tournament, three people
per team. We win if two of us win.
So?
So...
For the tournament...
Sorry, Sai. I can't tell unless I play.
To beat Kaiou...
Why don't you play when you haunt the third guy?
Ahhh! This pisses me off! What happened to him!?
Tsubaki-san said the same thing the other day.
Is a player he likes on a losing streak?
Another forfeit?
How long are you going to do this?
Tsubaki-san, are you done eating? The
company president wants to play you.
It's a waste of my free time...
So what? It's a chance for you to get some points.
Not only does he suck, he hates losing.
I can't stand it.
What? Is he good at Go or something?
I hear he took the pro exam last year.
Wow.
I know a guy like that, maybe
I should learn a bit, too.
Oh man, it's all crumpled up.
What is that crumpled up newspaper?
Did Kawai-san do it again?
Kawai-san, the newspapers are for everyone.
Please don't crumple them just because
Shindou-kun has another forfeit.
But I wonder what's wrong.
Why does he have forfeits?
How are we supposed to cheer him on like this?
I'm sure he has his reasons.
Can't you be a little more patient?
Really, you men!
Our patience set aside, can pros get
fired for not going to the matches?
Yeah. Can they?
How am I supposed to know.
Master?
I have no idea.
Fired!? You've got to be kidding!
I went all the way to Hiroshima with
him! And spent a night there, too!
That brat!
Kawai-san...
Japanese Go Institute
I just barely managed to win.
Ochi.
Are you done, too?
Judging by the fact that you were in
the bathroom, you must have lost.
You have this habit of going to the
bathroom whenever you lose.
It was just a biological function.
I'm still continuing my winning
streak, unlike you, Waya.
You little brat.
Waya have you heard? The head of the pros
committee, Murota 9-dan called Shindou.
And?
He asked whether Shindou was sick,
or if he needed to file for a leave,
but he couldn't get a clear-cut answer.
That idiot.
I wonder if he's going to quit being a pro.
I dunno.
And to think people thought
he could be Touya's rival.
Genius is meaningless if you don't play.
A tournament... what fond memories.
Mitani was first board, Tsutsui-san
was second, and I was third...
I was the worst player back then...
We won against Iwata Jr. High in the first round 3-0.
I even remember what the guy I played looked like.
Sai.
Shindou, going home?
What is it?
You've got nothing better to do
right? Can I ask for a favor?
What do you mean I have nothing better to do?
I heard you aren't going to any of the pro matches.
Play Mitani a little.
Play Mitani?
He's working hard to prepare for the tournament,
but there's no one he can practice with.
I'm not good enough.
Sorry...
Why not!?
Kaneko!
Mind your own business. I don't
want a guy like him coming.
I'm not asking just for you!
If Shindou can play you, then I'm
free to teach Natsume or Koike.
What's going on? Kaneko-san. Mitani-kun. Hikaru?
We're all working hard... that's what I thought. But
I guess it can't be helped if Mitani's like this.
The Go club will take care of it by
itself. Sorry for bothering you.
Hikaru!
The tournament is next Sunday.
Come watch at least!
Fujisaki!
Hikaru...
Our dream of participating in the
tournament is coming true.
I can't drag everyone down.
Ahh it's over! That was just horrible!
Akari, another game!
Huh? Sure.
Everyone's so passionate.
Especially the guys.
Hikaru was like this too when he was in the Go club.
I wonder what's wrong with him now.
Did he forget what he was like back then?
It's the last tournament in Jr. High for us
third year students, so let's do our best.
Yeah!
Okay. Let's go, Kumiko!
Okay. I'm going first!
Okay!
Kaiou Private Junior High School
It probably started already.
I won't be playing...
Sai...
I'm only watching.
IGO TOURNA-
MENT HALL
The Sixth Annual Summer Go Tournament Match Hall
The Sixth Annual North District Summer Junior High Go Tournament
It's Akari!
She's sitting in the middle.
So she's second board...
What is she thinking about?
It's an easy life and death problem. Don't
panic. Think carefully about it.
Yup.
Mitani...
I can't want it...
I can't want to play...
Shindou-kun?
If I were to want to play...
If I were to play Go again...
Sai... would be gone forever...
I...
I know it...
Ring
My
Bell
noizu darake no mune de
ノイズだらけの胸で
I listen to my fate through the din in my heart.
noizu darake no mune deunmei wo kikiwakeru
ノイズだらけの胸で運命を聴きわける
It occurs to me.
hirameku
閃く
hiramekuyume ha watashi no naka demezame o matteta
閃く夢は私の中で目覚めを待ってた
My dream was waiting for the time
to wake up within me.
mezame o matteta
閃く夢は私の中で目覚めを待ってた
Music
Is
My
Thing
I can be more like myself
jibun rashiku nareru
自分らしくなれる
Music
In
My
Heart
ときめきならして
Let the pounding of my heart be heard
tokimeki narashite
ときめきならして
Music
Is
My
Thing
karada wo ugokasu
体を動かす
I move my body
karada wo ugokasu
体を動かす
Music
In
My
Heart
Feel the light
hikari wo kanjite
光を感じて
Music
Is
My
Thing
shiro to kuro de egaku
白と黒で描く
I draw with black and white
shiro to kuro de egaku
白と黒で描く
Music
In
My
Heart
owaranai haamoni
The unending Harmony
終わらないハーモニー
owaranai haamoni
We're at West Fujimi City Public Junior High
School today in Saitama Prefecture.
Good luck.
Everyone in the Go club is working hard and
cheering each other on every day
to prepare for the tournament.
I lost.
We had discussion after the matches.
Teacher Yukari explained everything
clearly to everyone.
Thank you for the game.
Please keep on playing Go.
Okay.
Forfeits!?
I have no idea. It seems like he doesn't
want to play Go anymore.
He WILL return. He will come before
the opponent that he needs to face.
Shindou, let's play a game. That's
what I came here for.
Isumi-san...