Real Fansubbers presents
Hikaru no Go
胸の鼓動　熱くゆるがす
mune no kodou atsuku yurugasu
My heart walks, searching for something exciting
刺激求めて歩く My Heart
shigeki motomete aruku MY HEART
That will passionately sway the beating in my chest.
時間だけが過ぎる毎日じゃ
jikan dake ga sugiru mainichi jya
If I just wait for the time to pass everyday.
変化はない
henka ha nai
nothing's going to change.
Woo Wooo
止まらない　信じたい　進みたい
tomaranai shinjitai susumitai
I won't stop. I want to believe. I want to move forward.
自分の力試す My Life
jibun no chikara tamesu MY LIFE
I will test my strength during my life.
でも早歩きしたって見落とすだけ
demo hayaaruki shitatte miotosudake
But even if I walk faster.
I will definitely lose track of
そう確実に
sou kakujitsu ni
the important things.
Baby for you...
明日は明日の風が吹く
ashita ha ashita no kaze ga fuku
Tomorrow's wind will blow tomorrow.
それでも　今この瞬間を強く生きたい
soredemo
but I want to make the most out of this moment now.
ima kono shunkan wo tsuyoku ikitai
It's fantasy
さまよったとしても
samayotta to shitemo
Even if I'm wandering,
見たことない世界でも
mitakotonai sekai demo
even if I'm in a strange new world,
何よりも 自分を信じ立ち向かおう
nani yori mo jibun wo shinji tachimukaou
I'll stand up to it,
believing in myself more than anything else.
It's destiny
どんな場所にいても
donna basho ni itemo
No matter where I am,
つつむ空は一つだから
tsutsumu sora ha hitotsu dakara
I'm surrounded by the same sky.
ねぇ　もっと 翼広げて
nee motto tsubasa hirogete
so I'll be able to fly
羽ばたけるよね
habatakeruyone
with my wings spread out.
ONINBOU SHUUSAKU
He isn't here...
Why aren't you here, Sai?
Didn't you want to come and visit Torajirou's homeland?
The Sixty-Second Match
The Top Player in Hiroshima
GO IGO CLUB
What are you talking about!? That makes no sense.
Where did you get 50,000!?
Who said anything about 50,000!?
Why don't you say something!?
K-Kawai-san...
What's with that attitude!? I'm not done yet!
You spread your palm out like this.
Doesn't that mean 50,000?
You've got to be kidding! It means 5,000!
Then make that clear from the start. It's too late, you idiot.
You bastard! You called me an idiot again!
Kawai-san!
Hey, do you know that guy with the sunglasses?
Y-Yes.
The Giants and Curbs are rival baseball teams in Japan.
Tell him later to hide the fact
that he's a Giants fan here.
After all, this is the land of the Hiroshima Curbs.
Well Shuuhei was the one that got them on the topic of baseball.
Baseball!?
He insulted the Curbs. I don't blame
Shuuhei for messing with him.
Kawai-san, why?
Then leave whatever you want and go.
You got this Go lesson cheap.
Go lesson!? Fuck off!
Play me again. I'll win this time and even the score.
Give it up, you couldn't even tell how strong I was.
Kawai-san!
What do you think you're doing? I'm going to drag you home if you're just going to fight.
Wait a minute, I'm playing one more game.
Isn't he...?
Put your stones away already.
I'm done with you.
What did you say!?
You there. Wanna play me?
I'll forget about the money from the last game if you beat me.
Do you know who you're talking to?
He may look like just a kid, but he's...
I know. He's Shindou, a pro.
What? A pro?
That kid?
He doesn't look like a pro. He's
the same age as my grandson.
How can you be so confident when
you know that he's a pro!?
I saw him on Weekly Go. His new first dan
game against Touya Kouyou was horrible.
A pro shouldn't disappoint us amateurs like that.
Who are you, mister?
He's the man who is going to represent Japan at
the next International Amateur Tournament.
Shuuhei is the number one amateur player.
Number one amateur...
I play even games against Western Japan pros.
See? 5,000 yen is a cheap Go lesson.
Pinch hitter!
Pinch hitter!?
Come here. Teach him a lesson.
W-Wait!
Kawai-san!
Just sit down.
Don't back out on your word later!
I said...
I'm done with you.
Please, don't lose to him.
Really, Kawai-san.
Okay.
Let's play then.
Shuuhei-san's playing a pro?
We've got to watch this.
I'm playing first.
Good luck.
Oh well. I guess I'll play a game.
And why are you over here?
Just for a change of pace.
A change of pace?
We went around Hiroshima visiting
historic Shuusaku sites.
We visited his grave, too.
But there's a grave for Shuusaku in Tokyo.
In Tokyo?
Yeah, Shuusaku was in Innoshima
when he was a child.
But he lived in Edo after he started
playing in the palace.
His students made a grave in the palace, too...
in addition to the one here at his home.
Didn't you know that?
There's a grave for Shuusaku...
for Torajirou... in Tokyo...
Where in Tokyo!?
Who cares about that! You just need
to pay attention to the game!
Exactly, if you don't want to embarrass yourself.
Torajirou's grave in Tokyo...
That's it!
That has to be where Sai is!
Yeah!
He couldn't have come this far to Hiroshima.
He's in Tokyo.
He has to be in Tokyo.
Where in Tokyo?
I'll ask when you're done. Pay
attention to the game!
Sai...
I want to go home...
back to Tokyo... as quickly as possible.
What's with that speed?
No wonder he's a pro.
No time?
Why don't you think a bit?
You idiot! Why are you playing so quickly?
You're just asking for mistakes!
Looks like you guys are the ones that
are going to be embarrassed.
Please! Please play carefully!
Listen to what I'm saying!
Seems like he's sped up even more.
Does he think that little of Shuuhei?
It's got to be a bluff. What a stupid
thing to do against Shuuhei.
A bluff? He doesn't do stuff like that.
He's playing quickly, but he's playing solidly.
I see why he's a pro now, even though he's a child.
He took the corner, I'm behind now.
He can see further than I can, even
though I'm taking my time.
What's wrong now?
Just you wait. It's just starting.
The Curbs show their strength
in the last half of the game.
I have to be patient... but...
His quick play is urging me to play faster.
If he won't stop playing quickly...
I'll play a game-deciding move and
force him to make a mistake.
He instantly read through my deciding
move and responded correctly!
He's not playing fairly. He's urging
Shuuhei on by playing quickly!
That's ridiculous. Normally you'd make
a mistake before that would happen.
How can he play without thinking?
Is he playing on instinct?
No, he has time to think.
Look.
When Shuuhei's thinking...
he's thinking as much as he can during that time.
He's incomparable to what he was like last year.
When did he change so much?
Dammit!
If he responds here, I'll play a Tsuke for an Atari.
If he doesn't respond, hell play a Tsuke
here... but I won't respond and okay...
Okay. Once I play here, the game's decided.
I resign.
Okay.
Sai! How was it?
W-Wh-Wha?
Oh yeah... Sai is in Tokyo...
Where is Shuusaku's grave in Tokyo?
It's in Sugamo... Where was
it...? Oh yes, Honmyouji!
Sugamo...
Thanks for the game.
Kawai-san, let's go home.
Wait.
Crap, I beat him too badly.
But I don't want a fight...
I'll drive you to the station. Come with me.
You're a pretty nice guy. Or...
are you just giving up because
he's too good for you?
And who was it that I crushed?
Want me to drive? I'm a taxi driver.
You don't know the roads around
here. Stay back there.
What did you say!?
Don't fight! I want to get home as soon as possible.
You in a hurry?
Then I'll drive you to the Hikari station.
Hikari and Kodama are the names of the two types of bullet trains in Japan,
with Hikari being the faster of the two. In the previous line, Shuuhei says
he'll drive them to the nearest station that the bullet trains stop at.
His driving is worse than mine!
It's about the same!
Shindou-kun, I lost today.
I'll be in Tokyo for the International Amateur
Tournament in the summer.
Will you play me again then?
Like I'm going to let you play.
You should talk less.
Shindou Hikaru...
And he's still only in the 9th grade... how exciting.
The Go World will start to revolve around him soon.
But then what was that new first dan
game against Touya Kouyou?
He played so poorly...
Why was that?
Hey! Why are you in such a hurry!?
There's something wrong with you!
Sai!
Hey!
Sai, you're here right!?
Sai!
Hey!
Sai...
Sai.
Sai!
He's not here either!
Sai...
Hey, are you done?
Really... what were you doing running
around the past two days?
Were you looking for something?
Is it not at the Go Institute?
You've got to go to the Go Institute for Go stuff.
I've already looked at the Go Institute.
He wasn't in Grandpa's shed either.
Sai... where are you?
You okay?
Don't touch me!
What did you say?
Leave me alone!
Are you going home?
Hey! Stop by the Go salon sometime!
We're all cheering you on!
Really... what did he go to Hiroshima for?
I'm home.
Hikaru! It's so late! You couldn't
have gotten home earlier?
Make sure to tell me where you're
going when you go somewhere.
I know you have your own things...
but... you are still just a child.
Hikaru!
Sai!
The match against that Shuuhei person, it was rough.
I'm tired.
Go to the Go Institute for Go stuff.
I guess I'll take another look.
Hikaru! Where are you going?
The Institute.
This late?
It's already time for dinner, Hikaru!
He isn't here after all...
Sai...
Why did you disappear?
I don't understand...
He said before in the shed...
that he was disappearing soon...
I didn't listen to him...
I mean...
I never thought about Sai disappearing...
I never...
I never even thought about it!
Oh? Shindou-kun.
What are you doing this late?
Did you forget something?
Do you know where?
Huh? What?
Somewhere ghosts might show up!
Is there anywhere?
A ghost?
The Institute building is old and it is nighttime,
so I guess a ghost can appear anywhere.
Bye...
Wait... there really might be one there...
There?
Want to see?
つらい想い出とかいくつあったのかな？
tsurai omoide toka ikutsu atta no kana?
How many sad memories did we have?
どんな楽しい日を
donna tanoshii hi wo
What kind of happy days are we going to
これからは大切にしていくのかな？
kore kara wa taisetsu ni shite iku no kana?
hold onto preciously from now on?
近くの公園で集まったねいつも
chikaku no kouen de atsumatta ne itsumo
We always gathered at the nearby park
夜中まで大きな声出して笑ってたね
yonaka made ookina koe dashite waratteta ne
and laughed out loud into the middle of the night,
ずっとずっと
zutto... zutto...
always... always...
同じ時代を今生きてる奇跡が
onaji toki wo ima ikiteru kiseki ga
Because I'm really happy for the miracle
すごくうれしいからね
sugoku ureshii kara ne
of being here when you are
次あう日もきっとねぇ
tsugi au hi mo kitto nee
Let's laugh together again
一緒に笑っていようよ
issho ni waratte iyou yo
the next time we meet
今度はどんな夢を
kondo wa donna yume wo
what kind of dreams
一緒に語りあうのかな？
issho ni katariau no kana?
are we going to talk about then?
I should have let Sai play from the beginning.
Come back...
Sai.
Why did you become a pro?
Wasn't it to play me?
Shindou!
I won't play anymore.